[
  {
    "text": "Machine learning-based prediction of disease-free survival in breast cancer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a retrospective multicenter cohort study.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Breast Diseases, Jiaxing Women and Children's Hospital, Wenzhou",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Breast Diseases",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jiaxing Women and Children's Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wenzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical University Jiaxing 314000, Zhejiang, P. R. China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical University Jiaxing 314000",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhejiang",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "This study aimed to construct a robust machine learning (ML) model for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ML",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "predicting the disease-free survival (DFS) and risk stratification of breast",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer (BC) patients with non-pathological complete response (non-PCR) after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "neoadjuvant chemotherapy (NAC). The model will facilitate the initiation of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NAC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "early interventions for high-risk patients. This retrospective multicenter",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cohort study included BC patients from two hospitals in China who received NAC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NAC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "but did not achieve PCR. Four ML algorithms were utilized to construct models",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ML",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "based on patients' clinicopathological data, followed by a performance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluation of these models. To improve the interpretability of the model, the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "shapley additive explanation (SHAP) method was employed to analyze the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SHAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "contribution of each feature to the predictive outcomes. A total of 463 non-PCR",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "463",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital, affiliated with Shanghai Jiao Tong University, and were randomly split",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Shanghai Jiao Tong University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "into a training cohort and an internal validation cohort in a 3:1 ratio for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3:1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "model development and preliminary performance evaluation. In addition, 78",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "78",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients enrolled from Jiaxing Women and Children's Hospital were assigned to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jiaxing Women and Children's Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the external validation cohort to evaluate the model's generalizability.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "residual tumor size, Ki67 change, molecular subtype, and axillary lymph node",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metastasis were independent factors influencing DFS. Among the four ML models,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ML",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the random survival forest (RSF) model showed the best performance, with a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "concordance index of 0.820 in the training cohort, 0.642 in the internal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.820",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.642",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "validation cohort, and 0.689 in the external validation cohort. Further analysis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.689",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed that the RSF model had excellent discriminative ability with a high",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "area under curve value, while its low Brier score indicated excellent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Brier",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "calibration. Decision curve analysis indicated that the RSF model offered a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "higher clinical net benefit at various time points and effectively stratified",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "risk, successfully identifying high-risk patients. SHAP analysis underscored",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "residual tumor size as the most influential predictive feature. The RSF model",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "can effectively predict DFS and risk of BC patients with non-PCR following NAC,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "non-PCR",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "NAC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "offering a critical reference for developing individualized treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AJCR Copyright © 2025.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Erratum: Baicalein suppress EMT of breast cancer by mediating tumor-associated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Baicalein",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "macrophages polarization.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University 157 West Fifth Street, Xi'an 710004, Shaanxi, P. R. China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Xi'an 710004",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shaanxi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)The Second Department of Thoracic Surgery, The First Affiliated Hospital of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Second Department",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The First Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Xi'an Jiaotong University 277 West Yanta Road, Xi'an 710061, Shaanxi, P. R.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Xi'an Jiaotong University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shaanxi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "P. R.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Institute of Traditional Chinese medicine, Hunan University of Chinese",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Traditional",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hunan University of Chinese\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medicine 300 Xueshi Street, Changsha 410208, Hunan, P. R. China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "300",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Changsha",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "410208",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hunan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Blood, The Chengdu Military Command General Hospital of Kunming",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Blood",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Chengdu Military Command General Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kunming",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical University 212 West Daguan Road, Kunming 650032, Yunnan, P. R. China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "212",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yunnan",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "P. R. China",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Am J Cancer Res. 2018 Aug 01;8(8):1528-1540.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "[This corrects the article on p. 1528 in vol. 8, PMID: 30210921.].",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1528",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "30210921",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ESRP1 drives subtype-specific breast cancer progression through ER-regulated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transcriptional programs and EMT-related splicing switch.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Cancer Center, The Affiliated Dongguan Songshan Lake Central Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Affiliated Dongguan Songshan Lake Central Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Guangdong Medical University Dongguan, Guangdong, The People's Republic of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Medical University Dongguan",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "The People's Republic",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Pathology, School of Basic Medicine, Guangdong Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pathology, School of Basic Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University Zhanjiang, Guangdong, The People's Republic of China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University Zhanjiang",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "The People's Republic of China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)The First Clinical Medical College, Guangdong Medical University Zhanjiang,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "First Clinical Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Medical University Zhanjiang",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Guangdong, The People's Republic of China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Guangdong",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "The People's Republic of China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Pathology, The Affiliated Hospital of Guangdong Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pathology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Affiliated Hospital of Guangdong Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Thyroid and Breast Surgery, Dongguan Songshan Lake Central",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thyroid",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Breast Surgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dongguan Songshan Lake Central",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital, Guangdong Medical University Dongguan, Guangdong, The People's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Medical University Dongguan",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Republic of China.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Epithelial Splicing Regulatory Protein 1 (ESRP1), an epithelial splicing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Epithelial Splicing Regulatory",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "yet its prognostic significance and interaction with estrogen receptors are not",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "estrogen",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fully understood. Our findings indicate that ESRP1 is significantly up-regulated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in breast cancer tissues and correlates positively with adverse clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes, particularly in estrogen receptor (ER) positive breast cancer. In",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "vitro experiments with cells demonstrated a dual regulatory mechanism: in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ER-positive breast cancer cells, reduced expression of ESRP1 suppresses tumor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cell proliferation but does not significantly affect tumor cell invasion and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "migration; conversely, in ER-negative breast cancer cells, ESRP1 hinders tumor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "progression by regulating the alternative splicing of epithelial-mesenchymal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transition (EMT)-related genes. To investigate whether the presence of ER is a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "decisive factor in ESRP1's role, we treated ER-positive breast cancer cells with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an ER inhibitor to induce EMT, followed by the knockdown of ESRP1, which further",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "promoted the EMT process and enhanced the cells' invasive and migratory",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "abilities. This study demonstrates that ESRP1 is a potential breast cancer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prognostic marker with subtype specificity and its value as a molecular target",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "needs to be accurately assessed in the context of breast cancer subtypes, as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ESRP1 function may be highly dependent on the ER background.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESRP1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: None.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Super-resolution microscopy reveals distinct epigenetic states regulated by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "estrogen receptor activity.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "estrogen",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Akhshi T, Hu SS, Wheeler E, Hellriegel C, Richardson DS, Cayting N, Mvula W,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hu SS",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hellriegel C",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Richardson DS",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mvula W",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Ahmed B, Jeselsohn R, Zang C, Brown M.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ahmed B",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jeselsohn R",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Changes in gene expression regulated by ligand-dependent transcription factors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "such as estrogen receptor-α (ERα) involves the recruitment of coactivators",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "estrogen",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ERα",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "including p300 that acetylates histone H3 at lysine 27 (H3K27ac). While H3K27ac",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "H3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "27",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "marks active enhancers, the detailed chromatin architecture of enhancers remains",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unclear. Using super-resolution microscopy, we reveal distinct structural states",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of H3K27ac modified chromatin in response to ERα activation. In estradiol",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(E2)-treated cells, H3K27ac modified chromatin adopts open, elongated structures",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with active enhancers, while ERα inhibition induces compact,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "spherical H3K27ac modified chromatin conformations linked to repression. A",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "constitutively active ERα mutation linked to endocrine therapy resistance in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "breast cancer maintains open chromatin states independent of ligand, suggesting",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sustained transcriptional activity. Our findings provide the first direct",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "visualization of H3K27ac associated chromatin structural dynamics, challenging",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the assumption that H3K27ac modification alone is sufficient to lead to enhancer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activation. By demonstrating that H3K27ac architecture is dynamically regulated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "by ERα, we establish a new paradigm for understanding epigenetic regulation and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ERα",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "highlight potential therapeutic targets for endocrine therapy resistant cancers.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Integrated Omics Approach to Delineate the Mechanisms of Doxorubicin-Induced",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Integrated Omics Approach",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cardiotoxicity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Dabour MS, Abdelgawad IY, Sadaf B, Daniel MR, Grant MKO, Blaes AH, Jacobson PA,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dabour MS",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Abdelgawad IY",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sadaf B",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Daniel MR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Grant MKO",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Blaes AH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jacobson PA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Doxorubicin (DOX) is an effective chemotherapy whose clinical utility is limited",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Doxorubicin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by cardiotoxicity. To investigate underlying mechanisms, we employed a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "multi-omics approach integrating transcriptomic and proteomic profiling",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "leveraging established mouse models of chronic DOX- induced cardiotoxicity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Five-week-old male mice received weekly DOX (4 mg/kg) or saline injections for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Five-week-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "weekly",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "4 mg/kg",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "six weeks, with heart tissues harvested 4 days post-treatment. Differentially",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "4 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expressed genes (DEGs) and proteins (DEPs) were identified by bulk RNA-seq and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "proteomics, validated via qPCR and western blot, respectively Key DEPs were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "qPCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "validated in plasma samples from DOX-treated breast cancer patients.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Additionally, a temporal comparison was conducted between DEPs in the mice",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hearts 4 days and 6 weeks post-DOX. RNA-seq revealed upregulation of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "6 weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "post-DOX",
        "label": "EVENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stress-responsive genes ( Phlda3, Trp53inp1 ) and circadian regulators ( Nr1d1",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "), with downregulation of Apelin and Cd74 . Proteomics identified upregulation",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Apelin",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of serpina3n, thrombospondin-1, and epoxide hydrolase 1. Plasma SERPINA3",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Plasma SERPINA3",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "concentrations were significantly elevated in breast cancer patients 24 hours",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "24 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "post-DOX. Gene set enrichment analysis (GSEA) revealed upregulated pathways",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "post-DOX",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "including p53 signaling, apoptosis, and unfolded protein response. Integrated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "omics analysis revealed 2,089 gene-protein pairs. GSEA of concordant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2,089",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gene-protein pairs implicated p53 signaling, apoptosis, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "epithelial-mesenchymal transition in upregulated pathways, while oxidative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "phosphorylation and metabolic pathways were downregulated. Temporal comparison",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with a delayed timepoint (6 weeks post-DOX) uncovered dynamic remodeling of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6 weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "post-DOX",
        "label": "EVENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cardiac signaling, with early response dominated by inflammatory and apoptotic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "responses, and delayed response marked by cell cycle and DNA repair pathway",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activation. This integrated-omics study reveals key molecular pathways and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "temporal changes in DOX-induced cardiotoxicity, identifying potential biomarkers",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CDH1 loss remodels gene expression and lineage identity in human mammary",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "epithelial cells.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Musick M, Ufondu CA, Rowland CE, Sottnik JL, Shackleford MT, Nesiba CS,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Musick M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ufondu CA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rowland CE",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sottnik JL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shackleford MT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nesiba CS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Invasive lobular carcinoma (ILC) is a common subtype of breast cancer that is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "defined in part by genetic loss of CDH1 caused by mutation or deletion, leading",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to loss of cell adhesion protein E-cadherin in >90% of ILC. Genetic loss of CDH1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "ILC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "is an early event in ILC oncogenesis, yet the mechanisms by which CDH1/",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "E-cadherin acts as a tumor suppressor are not well understood. To study how",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "early CDH1 loss drives ILC oncogenesis, we used a series of non-transformed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "human mammary epithelial cell (HMEC) models to target CDH1 /E-cadherin,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HMEC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibiting extracellular E-cadherin signaling using antibodies versus modeling",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "genetic CDH1 loss using siRNA or knockout via CRISPR/Cas9. Through transcriptome",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR/Cas9",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analyses across four HMEC models, we found that the mode of E-cadherin loss or",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "HMEC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suppression is critical for the subsequent phenotype. Antibody-mediated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibition of cell-cell contacts induced gene signatures of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "suppression during the EMT process. Conversely, genetic CDH1 loss - as in ILC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ILC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "oncogenesis - repressed EMT signatures, and instead remodeled gene expression",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EMT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "toward a luminal epithelial phenotype. Using single cell transcriptomics and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "flow cytometry analyses of cell lineage markers, we found that genetic loss of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CDH1 reprogrammed cells to a luminal progenitor-like phenotype. By isolating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "luminal versus basal cells prior to CDH1 knockout, we found that CDH1 loss led",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to remodeling of lineage identity in both populations, converging on a new",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lineage homeostasis with a luminal progenitor-like phenotype. Consistent with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "increased progenitor features, CDH1 loss enhanced proliferative capacity over",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the finite lifespan of the HMECs, highlighting a feature of early CDH1 loss that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "may contribute to clonal advantage during tumor initiation. Our findings support",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that inhibition of E-cadherin results in different transcriptional response",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "compared to CDH1 loss, with the latter driving a transcriptional and phenotypic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "state characteristic of a luminal progenitor-like population, which offers new",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "insight into early events in ILC oncogenesis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A microfluidic gradient and parallel-track system uncovers spatial control of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "endocytosis and adhesion formation in breast cancer cell migration.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Chan ET, Jones TH, Thompson CM, Kannan H, D'Souza MW, Ali MM, Kural C, Song JW.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chan ET",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jones TH",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thompson CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kannan H",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "D'Souza MW",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ali MM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kural C",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cell migration through confined spaces is a critical step in cancer metastasis,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "yet the spatial regulation of endocytosis and adhesion dynamics during this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "process remains poorly understood. To address this, we developed a microfluidic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "platform that generates stable, spatially linear biochemical gradients across 5",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "μm-tall migration channels while limiting confounding flow-induced shear stress",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(<0.05 dyn/cm 2 ). COMSOL simulations and optical calibration using FITC-dextran",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "FITC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "confirmed that gradients form reliably within 5 minutes. The microdevice also",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5 minutes",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "supports long-term live imaging and is compatible with both spinning disk",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "confocal and total internal reflection fluorescence structured illumination",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "microscopy modalities, enabling high-resolution visualization of adhesion and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "endocytic structures. Localized application of the endocytic inhibitor Dyngo-4a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dyngo-4a",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to the front or rear of migrating cells revealed that front-targeted inhibition",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly increased the enrichment of paxillin and the clathrin adaptor AP-2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "paxillin",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "at the leading edge, whereas rear-targeted inhibition completely abolished their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "front-rear asymmetry. These changes were accompanied by enhanced migration speed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and persistence, particularly under front-targeted inhibition. Together, these",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "findings highlight the critical role of spatially coordinated endocytosis in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sustaining polarized adhesion and persistent cell movement. Our platform offers",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a powerful tool for dissecting subcellular mechanisms of migration under",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "confinement and provides a broadly applicable framework for probing spatially",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "localized signaling in engineered microenvironments.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Anthracyclines induce global changes in cardiomyocyte chromatin accessibility",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that overlap with cardiovascular disease loci.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Matthews ER, Abodunrin RO, Hurley JD, Gutiérrez JA, Ward MC.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Matthews ER",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Abodunrin RO",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hurley JD",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gutiérrez JA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Breast cancer drugs including anthracyclines (ACs) and Trastuzumab increase the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Trastuzumab",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "risk for cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) such as atrial fibrillation (AF) and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "heart failure (HF) that ultimately affect the heart muscle. These CVDs are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with hundreds of genetic variants in non- coding regions of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "hundreds",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genome. However, how these drugs affect the regulatory potential of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "non-coding genome of the heart and CVD risk loci is unknown. We therefore",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CVD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "measured global chromatin accessibility across iPSC-derived cardiomyocytes from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "four individuals treated with the ACs, Doxorubicin, Epirubicin, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Doxorubicin, Epirubicin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Daunorubicin, a related non-AC, Mitoxantrone, and the monoclonal antibody",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "non-AC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mitoxantrone",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Trastuzumab, or a vehicle control for three and 24 hours. We identified 155,557",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Trastuzumab",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "three and 24 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "155,557",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "high-confidence regions of open chromatin across 48 samples where the major",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "48",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sources of variation are associated with drug type and time. Jointly modeling",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the data revealed three accessibility response signatures denoted as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "early-acute, early-sustained, and late that correspond to 67,329 regions that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "67,329",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "open or close in response to drug treatment. Sequences associated with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "drug-induced chromatin opening contain motifs for DNA damage-associated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transcription factors including p53 and ZBTB14, and associate with increases in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "transcription",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ZBTB14",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "active histone acetylation and gene expression. 21 AF- and HF-associated SNPs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "21",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "HF-associated SNPs\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "directly overlap with regions associated with drug-induced opening. A shared",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "intronic HF and AF SNP, rs3176326, that is also an eQTL for CDKN1A in heart",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SNP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "rs3176326",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue, associates with increased chromatin accessibility, histone acetylation,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and CDKN1A expression in response to all ACs. Our results demonstrate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "large-scale changes in chromatin accessibility in cardiomyocytes treated with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ACs, which correspond to several regions harboring CVD risk loci.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AUTHOR SUMMARY: Anthracyclines are a widely used class of breast cancer drugs",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that are linked to cardiac toxicity and the development of heart disease in some",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "women. There are hundreds of genetic variants that associate with risk for heart",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "hundreds",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disease; however their role and mechanism of action in drug- induced toxicity is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unclear given that most reside in the non-coding genome. We therefore tested the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effects of five breast cancer drugs on genome-wide chromatin accessibility using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "induced pluripotent stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes. We found tens of thousands",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "tens of thousands",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of chromatin regions that change in accessibility after drug treatment. Regions",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with increased accessibility contain sequences that have been shown to bind DNA",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "damage-associated transcription factors, and associate with increases in nearby",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "transcription",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gene expression. We find 21 heart disease-associated genetic variants in regions",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "21",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that increase in chromatin accessibility following treatment. This suggests that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer drugs have large effects on the non-coding genome of heart cells",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "including at regions associated with heart disease. This research contributes to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "our understanding of how genetic variants associated with disease exert their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effects.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Soluble E-cadherin Drives Brain Metastasis in Inflammatory Breast Cancer.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drives Brain Metastasis",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hu X, Xiong Y, Villodre ES, Zhang H, Song J, Fowlkes N, Krishnamurthy S,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hu X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xiong Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Villodre ES",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhang H",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fowlkes N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Krishnamurthy S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Rylander M, Bartholomeusz C, Tripathy D; MDACC Inflammatory Breast Cancer Team;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rylander M",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The brain is a common site of relapse in inflammatory breast cancer (IBC), an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "E-cadherin positive, aggressive form of breast cancer. We found that elevated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "serum levels of soluble E-cadherin (sEcad), an 80-kDa fragment of E-cadherin, in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "80-kDa",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with metastatic IBC correlated with poorer outcomes and increased rates",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of brain metastases. In our effort to understand the underlying mechanism, we",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "discovered that sEcad binds to XIAP, an inhibitor of cell death, activating the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "sEcad",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "XIAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pro-survival NF-kβ signaling in tumor cells. We also discovered that sEcad",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "affects the tumor cell microenvironment by enhancing cancer cell adhesion to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "endothelial cells and inducing reactive astrocytosis in the brain. In addition,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "we found that sEcad-mediated reactive astrocytosis relies on the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CXCL1/CXCL8-CXCR2 axis and treatment with a brain-permeable CXCR2 antagonist",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCL1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CXCL8-CXCR2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "CXCR2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced brain metastatic burden and prolonged survival. These findings implicate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sEcad in brain metastasis and provide new insights into potential therapeutic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "HIGHLIGHTS: High serum sEcad levels correlate clinically with poor survival",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes and development of brain metastasissEcad drives IBC brain metastasis",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "growth in mouse modelssEcad binds XIAP to activate NFkB and promote anoikis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "XIAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NFkB",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance and invasion of IBC cells sEcad activates reactive astrocytes and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "induces CXCR2 expression on tumor cells in vitro and in vivo CXCR2-IN-1, a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCR2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "CXCR2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "brain-permeable CXCR2 antagonist, reduces metastasis and improves survival in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCR2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Exosomes are specialized vehicles to induce fibronectin assembly.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Fibronectin is a key stromal matrix molecule whose assembly into fibrils is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fibronectin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thought to require cells. In contrast, we find that small exosome-type",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "extracellular vesicles (EVs) are critical initiators of fibronectin assembly.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Fibroblasts engineered to be deficient in exosome secretion showed greatly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced assembly of fibronectin and other stromal matrix molecules in 2D, 3D,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fibronectin",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2D",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and in vivo environments, and led to reduced tumor growth and lung metastasis by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "breast cancer cells. Furthermore, transgenic mice with defects in exosome",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "secretion had greatly reduced lung fibrosis after treatment with bleomycin. In a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "direct test of exosome function, we find that the addition of purified small EVs",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to purified soluble fibronectin in a cell-free system is sufficient to induce",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fibronectin assembly. The EV-induced fibronectin assembly requires the presence",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of fibronectin-binding integrins and Syndecan-1 in the EVs. We propose a new",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "model in which secreted exosomes directly drive stromal matrix assembly and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Radiosensitizers in Cancer Therapy: A Global Bibliometric Analysis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVES: Radiosensitizers are compounds given concurrently with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "radiotherapy to enhance the killing of cancer cells while sparing healthy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue. Radiosensitization research has involved a diverse range of therapeutic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "agents. In the present study, we aimed to investigate international trends in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the development of radiosensitizers across the most common cancer types.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: A bibliometric analysis was performed of the field of radiosensitizer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "research from 1956 to 2024. Individual author impacts and trends, collaborations",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1956 to 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "between and productivity of countries, and themes/keywords were analyzed.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Our search yielded 12,690 results. The most highly represented",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12,690",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "countries were the United States of America, China, and Germany. Radiosensitizer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the United States of America",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studies for breast cancers demonstrated the highest rate of annual growth in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "annual",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "record count by comparison with other cancer types, while publications for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "gynecological cancers showed the slowest growth. The most common",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "radiosensitizers investigated included ATM kinase inhibitors, chemotherapies,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ATM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gold nanoparticles, mTOR inhibitors, natural compounds such as caffeine or",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mTOR",
        "label": "LAW"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "curcumin, and poly (ADP-ribose) polymerase inhibitors.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: The United States, Germany, and China were the most productive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "countries during the study period, with China demonstrating the greatest",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increase in annual publication rate. Additionally, pre-clinical studies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "annual",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "primarily investigated gold particles and targeted therapies. By comparison,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical studies focused on radiosensitizing chemotherapies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Modeling the role of urokinase plasminogen activator, uPA, and circulating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cancer-Associated Fibroblasts (cCAFS) in breast cancer cell extravasation.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cancer-Associated Fibroblasts",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Circulating Cancer-Associated Fibroblasts (cCAFs) have been discovered in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Circulating Cancer-Associated Fibroblasts",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "circulating tumor cell clusters from all stages of disease progression in breast",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer patients. We have shown that CAFs promote lung metastases in the mouse",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tail vein model when they are clustered with triple negative breast cancer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "tail vein",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(TNBC) MDA-MB231 cells. Following on this observation, we saw that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MDA-MB231-luciferase labeled cells persist at higher levels when present in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CAF23/MDA-MB231 co-clusters compared to MDA-MB231 mono-clusters within the first",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "3 days after tail vein injection. This prompted us to investigate whether CAFs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "aid cancer cell extravasation from capillary venules into the lung parenchyma,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "which would impart better survival and faster seeding of metastases. Ex vivo",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lung extravasation assays showed that within the first 8-24 hrs after tail vein",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "injection, more cells from CAF23/MDA-MB231 co-clusters extravasated than cells",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "from MDA-MB231 mono-clusters. Using in vitro endothelial binding assays, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "determined that CAF/TNBC co-clusters bind to HUVEC endothelial cells better than",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CAF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "HUVEC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "TNBC mono-clusters. Single Cell RNA-seq identified several genes in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fibrinolysis pathway whose expression increases in TNBC cells when they are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clustered with CAFs. One of these genes is PLAU , which encodes the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "One",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "urokinase-type plasminogen activator, uPA. siRNA knockdown of PLAU decreased in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "vitro TNBC-endothelial cell interactions and ex vivo extravasation of MDA-MB231",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MDA-MB231",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mono-clusters, revealing a role for uPA/PLAU in breast cancer cell",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "extravasation. Our data helps to define the role of CAFs in breast cancer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CAFs promote tumor cell dissemination and metastasis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Paclitaxel-induced mitotic arrest results in a convergence of apoptotic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dependencies that can be safely exploited by BCL-X (L) degradation to overcome",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-X (L",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Qin X, Presser A, Johnson L, Matoba Y, Shay BS, Xu W, Choiniere J, Fraser C,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Qin X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Presser A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johnson L",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Matoba Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xu W",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Paclitaxel and other microtubule-targeting agents are cornerstone therapies for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diverse cancers, including lung, breast, cervical, pancreatic, and ovarian",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malignancies. Paclitaxel induces tumor cell apoptosis during mitosis by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disrupting microtubule dynamics required for chromosome segregation. However,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "despite initial responsiveness, many tumors develop resistance, limiting",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "therapeutic durability. Here, we used high-grade serous ovarian carcinoma",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(HGSOC), the most common and lethal subtype of ovarian cancer, as a model to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HGSOC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dissect the mechanisms underlying this resistance. We find that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "paclitaxel-induced mitotic arrest triggers degradation of the pro-survival",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "protein MCL-1 and upregulation of BCL-XL, followed by inactivating",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCL-1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "phosphorylation of BCL-XL at Ser62 to promote apoptosis. In resistant cells,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ser62",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "this MCL-1 downregulation is insufficient to commit cells to apoptosis but",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCL-1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "instead results in a transient convergence of apoptotic dependencies by forcing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BCL-X L to sequester the pro-apoptotic proteins BIM, BAX, and BAK. During this",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BIM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "BAX",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "state, BCL-XL inhibition induces synergistic apoptosis, even in chemoresistant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cells. Surprisingly, we also discover that loss of substrate attachment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "recapitulates this apoptotic convergence both in vitro and in vivo, with HGSOC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HGSOC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cells growing in metastasis-promoting malignant ascites displaying heightened",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "apoptotic priming and dependence on BCL-XL relative to solid tumors. In HGSOC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "HGSOC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "xenografts, targeted degradation of BCL-XL using the platelet-sparing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "xenografts",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "proteolysis-targeting chimera (PROTAC) DT2216 matches the efficacy of paclitaxel",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "monotherapy while avoiding the chronic thrombocytopenia induced by BCL-XL",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibitors such as navitoclax (ABT-263). Strikingly, combination therapy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "leveraging the synergy between paclitaxel and DT2216 leads to complete",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DT2216",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eradication of HGSOC cell line and patient-derived xenografts. Moreover, DT2216",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HGSOC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "DT2216\n",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment blunts the rapid apoptotic adaptation caused by other BCL-X L",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibitors, indicating that targeted degradation of pro-survival proteins may",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "yield more durable responses than inhibition alone. These findings uncover a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanistic framework for safely exploiting the apoptotic dependency convergence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "caused by mitotic arrest and substrate detachment and support the clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development of BCL-XL-targeting PROTACs to overcome chemoresistance in ovarian",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BCL-XL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer and other solid tumors.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Transient chromatin decompaction by histone deacetylation inhibition",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preferentially radiosensitizes cancerous breast epithelial cells at lower",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Radiation therapy plays a prominent role in breast cancer treatment, but the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "high doses of radiation damage both healthy and cancerous cells. Therefore,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "additional research is needed into combination therapies that could",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preferentially radiosensitize cancer cells compared to surrounding healthy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue without causing deleterious side effects. Histone deacetylase inhibitor",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "drugs (HDACis) have been tested as radiosensitizers in both basic research and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical trials, but the long exposure usually used in these treatments and lack",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of examination of effects on matched healthy cells leave aspects of their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanism of action unclear. Here, we show that transient (2 hour) trichostatin",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2 hour",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "trichostatin\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A (TSA) treatment of cancerous and non-tumorigenic breast epithelial cell lines",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TSA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increases immediate DNA damage and decreases long-term cell survival in both",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cell types at high radiation doses. At an intermediate radiation dose (1 Gy),",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "however, TSA treatment selectively radiosensitizes the cancer as compared to the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TSA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "non-cancer cell line. The radiosensitizing action of short-term TSA treatment,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TSA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "which by itself has no impact on cell viability, suggests that chromatin",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decompaction is an important part of the mechanism of radiosensitization by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "HDACis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cerebellum metastasis model of HER2-positive breast cancer unveils key role of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HER2",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "IL34-induced Arg1+ macrophages.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cheng X, Patel KK, Zhou B, Fu Y, Cleary R, Highkin M, Hsia J, Jin X, Kohn B,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cheng X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Patel KK",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhou B",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fu Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Highkin M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hsia J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jin X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kohn B",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Jain V, Gregory S, Kim A, Bose R.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jain V",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gregory S",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kim A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bose R.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Brain metastases occur in up to 40% of Stage IV breast cancer patients. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Brain",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "up to 40%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cerebellum is a frequent location for metastases in HER2-positive breast cancer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HER2",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients, but the mechanisms for this are unknown. Here, we developed a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "syngeneic, immunocompetent mouse model for breast cancer brain metastases by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "syngeneic",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stereotactically injecting mouse HER2-overexpressing breast cancer organoids",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "into the cerebellum. Growth of these cerebellar metastases was monitored by MRI",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and trastuzumab optical imaging using a near-infrared fluorophore conjugated to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "trastuzumab. Spatial transcriptomics identified interleukin-34 production by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "interleukin-34",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "breast cancer cells inducing ARG1+ macrophages at the invading edge of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metastasis. Treatment with a blocking antibody to interleukin-34's receptor,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "interleukin-34",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CSF1R, produced tumor shrinkage. These findings have immediate translation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "potential as a CSF1R-blocking antibody is FDA-approved. Further, it demonstrates",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that cancer-associated inflammation bordering the brain metastasis promotes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metastatic growth and offers a molecularly targeted strategy to treat",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inflammation in brain metastasis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Sulindac modulates the response of triple negative breast cancer to anti-PD-L1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "anti-PD-L1",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immunotherapy.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Teriple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) is a heterogeneous tumor, and there is a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lack of effective therapies. Immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) therapy has",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "been widely used to treat a variety of human cancers including TNBC. Despite the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "FDA's approval of therapies like Atezolizumab (anti- PD-L1) and Pembrolizumab",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Atezolizumab",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pembrolizumab",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(anti-PD-1) for certain TNBC cases, more than half of all TNBC patients,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "more than half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "especially those with low PD-L1 levels and in advanced stages, remain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unresponsive. Therefore, there is urgent clinical need to find other innovative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "combination therapy strategy for these TNBC patients. In this study, we examined",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the efficacy of sulindac to enhance the response of TNBC to anti-PD-L1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immunotherapy. We utilized a 4T1 syngeneic mouse tumor model to compare the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4T1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibitory effects of PD-L1 antibody, sulindac, and their combination on 4T1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4T1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tumor growth. We found that mice treated with combination therapy showed a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "significant reduction in tumor volume, along with increased infiltration of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activated T lymphocytes (Granzyme B+/CD8+ T cells) in the tumor tissues. We also",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Granzyme",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "established a PBMC humanized mouse model to further confirmed that combination",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PBMC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "therapy could significantly reduce the tumor size of TNBC patient-derived",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "xenografts (56S) and the combination group were found to have the most",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "xenografts",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infiltrating activated human T lymphocytes (Granzyme B+/CD8+ T cells) in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Granzyme",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tumor tissues. Immunofluorescent staining of organoids also confirmed that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "organoids from combination group have more CD8+ T cell and the results of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "organoid cell viability assay in vitro indicated that combination of sulindac",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with PD-L1 antibody together with activated human PBMC significantly reduce 56S",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "56S",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "organoid cell viability, which is consistent with in vivo study. When",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "investigating the mechanism of action, first we found sulindac could",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "downregulate exosomal PD-L1 by decreasing expression of nsMase2 which is a major",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "nsMase2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "regulator in production of exosomal PD-L1. Second, we demonstrated that sulindac",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PD-L1",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "could downregulate PD-L1 by blocking Stat3 signaling and enhancing the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "expression of miR-570-3p which can potentially target PD-L1, which in turn led",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "miR-570-3p",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PD-L1",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to a further decrease in exosomal PD-L1. Previous study showed that PD-L1",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "antibody could be bound and consumed by exosomal PD-L1 in the blood circulation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Therefore, in combination therapy, sulindac downregulating exosomal PD-L1 leads",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to increased availability of PD-L1 Ab, which potentially improves the overall",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PD-L1 Ab",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "efficacy of anti-PD-L1 therapy. In conclusion, our findings provide unique",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "anti-PD-L1",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "insights into the mechanism of action and efficacy for sulindac as an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immunomodulatory agent in combination with anti-PD-L1 therapy for the treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of TNBC.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Brain FGF2 and NCAM1 contribute to FGFR1-dependent progression of ER+ breast",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NCAM1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "FGFR1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer brain metastases in young and aged hosts.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cittelly DM.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "proportion of BC brain metastasis (BCBM) but remains understudied. Here, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "report that FGFR1-amplification, a well-established driver of ER+ BC endocrine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FGFR1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER+ BC",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance, promotes ER+ BCBM colonization in young and aged mice, through",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "brain-dependent mechanisms. FGFR1-dependent brain colonization in young and aged",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interactions. Astrocytic FGF2-mediated paracrine activation of FGFR1 promoted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FGFR1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BCBMs in estrogen-treated young mice, but FGF2 signaling decreased in the brain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with aging and estrogen-depletion. Neuronal and glial NCAM1, which remain",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NCAM1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "unchanged in young and aged brains, promoted adhesion to neurons and migration",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of ER+ BC cells, suggesting that interactions with astrocytes and neurons",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ER+ BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "facilitate early ER+ BCBM colonization through FGFR1. Importantly, FDA-approved",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FGFR1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "FDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "FGFR inhibitors effectively blocked early but not late metastatic progression",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "only in young mice, suggesting limited efficacy of FGFR inhibitors to block",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FGFR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "18. Health Sci Rep. 2025 Jul 15;8(7):e71062. doi: 10.1002/hsr2.71062. eCollection",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "18",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1002",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Assessment of ESR1, PGR, ERBB2, and MKI67 mRNA in Hormone Receptor-Positive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PGR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ERBB2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hormone Receptor",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Early Breast Cancer: A Cross-Sectional Study.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Hematology-Oncology Shahid Beheshti University of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hematology-Oncology Shahid Beheshti University of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences Tehran Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tehran",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Hormone receptors are expressed in 70% of breast cancers",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "70%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and are the major biomarkers for tailoring treatment in early-stage breast",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer. In clinical routine, immunohistochemistry (IHC) is used to assess",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expression. However, IHC procedure is challenged with pre-analytical and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analytical variability. Pathologist interpretation of IHC results can vary, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "discordant results between local and reference laboratories have been reported.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Using mRNA-based tests may be a more robust, reliable, and standardized method",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to assess these important breast cancer biomarkers. This study aimed to assess",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the concordance between real-time PCR and IHC results.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: In this study, we analyzed 178 early-stage hormone receptor-positive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "178",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "breast tumors. IHC for ER, PR, HER2, and Ki67 had been previously performed for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PR",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "HER2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the study samples at local laboratories. For samples with HER2 IHC score 2+,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization was performed. ESR1 (encoding ER), PGR",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "ER",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PGR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(encoding PR), ERBB2 (encoding HER2), and MKI67 (encoding Ki67) mRNA expression",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ERBB2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "HER2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were determined using TaqMan gene expression assays.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The overall concordance between mRNA expression results and their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "corresponding IHC markers was 95.9% for ESR1/ER, 79.3% for PGR/PR, and 100% for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "95.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "79.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "PGR/PR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "100%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ERBB2/HER2. There was a moderate correlation between MKi67 mRNA values and Ki67",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ERBB2/HER2",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MKi67",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "IHC. ESR1 expression was significantly lower in tumors of younger patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosis and ER IHC was identified. Higher ESR1 and MKI67 mRNA expression was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with worse pathological characteristics.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: PCR-based classification of breast tumors in a central laboratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "may be used to confirm the available IHC results performed at local laboratories",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and add valuable information for patient management. mRNA-based biomarkers may",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "be promising for more standardized breast cancer management.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Health Science Reports published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wiley Periodicals",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LLC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "19. APL Bioeng. 2025 Jul 14;9(3):036104. doi: 10.1063/5.0230800. eCollection 2025",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "19",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bioeng",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1063/5.0230800",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "eCollection",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Microwave-assisted immunostaining for rapid labeling of matrix-embedded",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Cancer Early Detection Advanced Research Center, Knight Cancer Institute,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Early Detection Advanced Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knight Cancer Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Oregon Health and Science University, Portland, Oregon 97201, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oregon Health and Science University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Portland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oregon 97201",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Immunofluorescence staining of cell proteins is essential to understanding",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "biomolecular interactions within three-dimensional (3D) hydrogel cell cultures.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "However, the scaffold material limits passive diffusion of antibodies through",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thick 3D matrices, prolonging staining and washing steps and resulting in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "processing times that can last for several days. Microwave irradiation has",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "several days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "previously been shown to enhance penetration of fixatives in a variety of soft",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissues by increasing the rate of diffusion through the sample, yet it is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unknown if microwave irradiation can improve immunofluorescence staining of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cells in 3D hydrogel cultures. Here, we demonstrate a microwave-assisted",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immunostaining technique that rapidly labels cells within spheroid structures",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "embedded within thick intact hydrogels. These results show that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "collagen-embedded breast epithelial spheroids can be efficiently labeled with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "primary antibodies in less than 3.5 h. We show significantly enhanced staining",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "less than 3.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and greater depth penetration with microwave-assisted staining compared to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "conventional benchtop staining methods. We demonstrate staining of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "collagen-embedded breast cancer spheroids with complete staining achieved in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "less than 2.5 h via the microwave, which outperforms conventional staining",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "less than 2.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "techniques. Moreover, we demonstrate enhanced staining of spheroids embedded in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "basement membrane-derived Matrigel matrices with the microwave method compared",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Matrigel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to benchtop techniques. Finally, we directly compare 2-h microwave-assisted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "staining to conventional 15-h longform benchtop staining and show that microwave",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "staining increases depth penetration and intensity of stains compared to the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "longform staining. This work develops a microwave-assisted staining protocol",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that provides a rapid and reproducible method to label a variety of cell types",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "within various 3D hydrogel cell culture systems.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The authors have no conflicts to disclose.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Paraneoplastic Amyopathic Dermatomyositis Associated With a Bone and Medullary",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Location of Breast Adenocarcinoma.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Medical Oncology, Centre Hospitalo-Universitaire Mohammed VI,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Oncology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mohammed VI",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Medical Oncology, Cadi Ayyad University, Marrakesh, MAR.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Oncology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cadi Ayyad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Marrakesh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MAR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Paraneoplastic amyopathic dermatomyositis (ADM) is a rare connective tissue",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disease presenting with characteristic dermatomyositis-like skin findings in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "absence of muscle involvement. It is associated with malignancies in 15%-30% of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15%-30%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cases and may portend a fatal outcome, especially when linked to advanced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancers. We report the case of a 58-year-old woman who presented with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "58-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "progressive low back pain and erythroderma. Imaging revealed diffuse bone",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metastases, and bone biopsy confirmed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "erythema and other cutaneous findings consistent with ADM. The patient was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "started on endocrine therapy with palbociclib and letrozole, along with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "improvement. However, within six months of diagnosis, she developed severe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19 pneumonia, complicated by pancytopenia and sepsis, and ultimately",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "succumbed to multiorgan failure despite intensive care support. This case",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "underlines the importance of recognizing paraneoplastic ADM as an initial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "manifestation of malignancy. A multidisciplinary approach is key, but the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prognosis largely depends on the cancer's burden and complications such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment-induced immunosuppression.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025, Haboub et al.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "al.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Updates on Breast Cancer in Oman: Challenges and Promising Frontiers.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Pathology and Blood Bank, Sohar Hospital, Sohar, OMN.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pathology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Blood Bank",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sohar Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sohar",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "OMN",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Breast cancer is a significant public health concern in Oman, with increasing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "incidence rates over the past few decades. This literature review explores the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the past few decades",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "epidemiology, risk factors, cultural influences, screening practices, treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes, research, and role of non-profit organizations in breast cancer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "awareness in Oman. The review highlights the unique challenges faced by Omani",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oman",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Omani",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "women, including late-stage diagnosis, cultural stigma, and limited awareness of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "screening programs. While efforts have been made to improve early detection and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment, there is a need for more comprehensive public health strategies to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "address the growing burden of breast cancer in Oman. This review synthesizes",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "breast cancer in Oman and suggests directions for future research and policy",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "interventions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025, Al Khan et al.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Al Khan",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "al.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "influenced the submitted work.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Identification and validation of genes related to stem cells and telomere",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "maintenance mechanisms as biomarkers for breast cancer.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Breast Surgery, Department of General Surgery, The First",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Breast Surgery",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of General Surgery",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "First",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Affiliated Hospital with Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanjing Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanjing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Stem cell-related genes (SCRGs) and telomere maintenance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCRGs",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanism-related genes (TMMRGs) are pivotal in breast cancer (BC) pathogenesis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by facilitating tumor cell proliferation and self-renewal. This study employed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "integrated transcriptomic and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) analyses to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "investigate SCRGs and TMMRGs as potential biomarkers for BC and to elucidate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCRGs",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "TMMRGs",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "their underlying cellular mechanisms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Total RNA was extracted from eight BC tumor samples and eight matched",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "BC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "adjacent non-tumorous tissues. Differential expression profiling,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "protein-protein interaction (PPI) network construction, and Molecular Complex",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Molecular Complex",
