[
  {
    "text": "The efficacy of remote ischemic conditioning in improving neurological function",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and short-term prognosis in acute ischemic stroke: a prospective controlled",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Rehabilitation, The First Affiliated Hospital of Shantou",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rehabilitation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The First Affiliated Hospital of Shantou\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University Medical College, Shantou, Guangdong Province, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shantou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Endocrinology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Shantou",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The First Affiliated Hospital of Shantou\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical College, Shantou, Guangdong Province, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shantou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangdong Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: To evaluate the efficacy of remote ischemic conditioning (RIC) in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "improving neurological function and short-term prognosis in patients with acute",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This randomized, controlled, single-blind study aimed to evaluate the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "short-term (7-day) effects of RIC on neurological function in patients with AIS.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "264 AIS patients (median age 65 years, 63.3% male) with ischemic symptoms <72 h",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "264",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "age 65 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "63.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "post-onset were randomly assigned to either the RIC group (n = 65) or the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "65",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "control group (n = 199). RIC was administered manually using a cuff",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "control group",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "199",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sphygmomanometer, while the control group received a sham RIC treatment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Patients with cardioembolic sources or a history of prior stroke were excluded",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "from the study. Primary outcomes were the proportion of patients with an mRS",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "score of ≤2 at 7 days, as well as changes in the National Institutes of Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the National Institutes of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Stroke Scale (NIHSS), modified Rankin Scale (mRS), Activities of Daily Living",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Stroke Scale",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "NIHSS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rankin Scale",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Activities of Daily Living",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(ADL), and Rancho Los Amigos (RLA) scores. Data were collected at baseline and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rancho Los Amigos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RLA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "7 days post-enrollment, with in-person follow-up visits conducted by blinded",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: At 7 days, the RIC group showed a significantly higher proportion of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with an mRS score of ≤2 compared to the control group (41.5% vs. 28.1%,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "41.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "28.1%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "p = 0.043). Significant improvements were observed in the RIC group compared to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.043",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the control group in NIHSS (p = 0.004) and ADL scores (p = 0.005), but not in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NIHSS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.004",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ADL",
        "label": "LAW"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.005",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "adjusting for baseline factors, the treatment effect of RIC remained",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "statistically significant.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: RIC treatment enhances neurological function and improves short-term",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prognosis in AIS patients. These findings support the potential clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "application of RIC in AIS management.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Serum ferritin and risk of stroke: a meta-analysis of observation studies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)School of Preclinical Medicine, Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)School of Preclinical Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zunyi Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zunyi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Neurosurgery, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurosurgery, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Gastrointestinal Surgery, Chongqing Jiulongpo People's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chongqing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jiulongpo People's",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of General Surgery, Xipeng Town Health Center of Jiulongpo",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Surgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xipeng Town Health Center of Jiulongpo\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "District, Chongqing, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chongqing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Serum ferritin, a well-established biomarker of iron",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Serum ferritin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "status, has been inconsistently linked to stroke risk in previous studies. This",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "meta-analysis aims to systematically evaluate the association between serum",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ferritin levels and the risk of stroke.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We conducted a systematic literature search across the PubMed and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PubMed",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eligibility criteria were selected, and relevant data were extracted.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Ten studies, including eight longitudinal and three cross-sectional,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ten",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were included in our meta-analysis. Cross-sectional studies showed that stroke",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients had significantly higher serum ferritin levels than controls.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Longitudinal studies suggested a 22% increase in stroke risk in individuals with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "higher serum ferritin. Subgroup analysis indicated that further high-quality",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "population-based cohort studies are warranted to validate these findings.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Dose-response meta-analysis confirmed a positive association between serum",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: This meta-analysis provides evidence of a positive association",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between increased serum ferritin levels and stroke incidence. While these",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "results are promising, definitive conclusions cannot be drawn at this time.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Therefore, additional robust, prospective cohort studies are imperative to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "substantiate this relationship.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Zheng, Wang, Xia and Liu.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zheng",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wang",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xia",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Is helicopter transferal in the \"drip-and-ship\" approach for endovascular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment the better choice? A retrospective analysis of transfer times.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "V(5), Macke C(5), Worthmann H(1).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Macke C(5)",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Worthmann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Neurology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover Medical School",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Interdisciplinary Emergency and Disaster Medicine, Hannover Medical School,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Interdisciplinary",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover Medical School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hannover, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hannover",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Anesthesiology and Surgical Intensive Care Medicine, KRH",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Anesthesiology and Surgical Intensive Care Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "KRH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital Siloah, Hannover, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hannover",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Institute of Diagnostic and Interventional Neuroradiology, Hannover Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Diagnostic and Interventional Neuroradiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School, Hannover, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hannover",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Trauma Surgery, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Trauma Surgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover Medical School",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hannover",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: For patients with large vessel occlusion (LVO) admitted to primary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke centers (PSC) without neuro-interventional capabilities, timely transfer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to comprehensive stroke centers (CSC) is crucial. In this study, we compared the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transport time of ground- and air-based transfer for patients receiving",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: In a retrospective cohort study, consecutive ischemic stroke patients",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with LVO who were transferred ground- or air-based to our CSC between October",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "between October\n",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2018 and December 2022 were examined. 170 patients with LVO from five PSCs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "December 2022",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "170",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "LVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "within a radius of 55 to 85 km to the CSC were included. Patients were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "55 to 85 km",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transported either with an emergency rescue helicopter (ERH), a ground ambulance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(GA), GA accompanied by an emergency physician vehicle (EPV), or in a mobile",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EPV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "intensive care unit (MICU) and were accordingly divided into air-based (61",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MICU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "61",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients) and ground-based (109 patients) main transport groups.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "109",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ground-based transport groups (75 vs. 82 min, p = 0.01). After calculating the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "75",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "82",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.01",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transport time in relation to the covered ground distance, air-based transport",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "was shorter by a median of 0.15 min per kilometer. In a comparison of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "individual means, ERH was faster than GA and EPV (both p < 0.001). Only few",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EPV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transports were done by MICU and they mainly showed very long transfer times.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MICU",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The complication rates were generally low with only minor complications and no",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "deaths reported in both groups. However, they were more frequently observed in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the land-based transport group (20.2% vs. 8.2%, p = 0.04).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "20.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "8.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.04",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: In the present analysis, air-based transport was faster than",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ground-based transport for the secondary transfer of patients with stroke due to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "LVO in the observed regional conditions. Both air- and land-based transport",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "appear to be safe. No serious complications occurred during transport, while",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications were more frequent in the ground-based transport group.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Worthmann.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Worthmann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Metabolic syndrome is associated with prognosis in patients with acute ischemic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke after intravenous thrombolysis: a prospective cohort study.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Geriatric Medicine, Shanxi Bethune Hospital, Shanxi Academy of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Geriatric Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bethune Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanxi Academy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical Sciences, Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, Tongji Shanxi",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Third Hospital of Shanxi Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tongji Shanxi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Neurology, Linfen People's Hospital, Linfen, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Linfen People's Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Linfen",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Neurology, Beijing Yanhua Hospital, Beijing, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Beijing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: Metabolic syndrome (MetS) is a known risk factor for stroke, but its",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "impact on prognosis after intravenous thrombolysis (IVT) in acute ischemic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IVT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke (AIS) remains unclear. This study aimed to evaluate the association",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "between MetS and prognosis in AIS patients treated with IVT.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IVT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We conducted a prospective cohort study including AIS patients who",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "received IVT at Shanxi Bethune Hospital between January 2022 and December 2023.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IVT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanxi Bethune Hospital",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "between January 2022",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "December 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Propensity score matching (PSM) was applied to balance baseline characteristics",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between MetS and non-MetS groups. The primary outcome was 3-month all-cause",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "3-month",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mortality. Secondary outcomes included good functional outcome (modified Rankin",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Secondary",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Scale [mRS] 0-2) and symptomatic intracranial hemorrhage (SICH).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: After PSM, 292 patients (146 pairs) were enrolled in the analysis. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PSM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "292",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "146",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "all-cause mortality rate within 3 months was significantly higher in the MetS",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "group compared to the non-MetS group (24.0% vs. 11.6%; p < 0.01). Multivariate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "non-MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "24.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "11.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cox regression analysis indicated that MetS was independently associated with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increased 3-month mortality (adjusted hazard ratio [HR] = 2.50, 95% CI:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3-month",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2.50",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1.35-4.60; p < 0.01). A dose-response relationship was observed between the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.35",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "number of MetS components and mortality. Additionally, patients with MetS were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "less likely to achieve good functional outcomes (adjusted odds ratio",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "[OR] = 0.47, 95% CI: 0.28-0.77; p < 0.01) and had a higher risk of SICH",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.47",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(adjusted OR = 2.40, 95% CI: 1.17-4.92; p = 0.02).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.40",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.17-4.92",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.02",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: MetS is an independent predictor of increased mortality, poorer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MetS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "functional recovery, and higher risk of SICH in AIS patients treated with IVT.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IVT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Early identification and management of metabolic risk factors may improve",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes in this population.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Chen, Liu, Li and Zhang.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Li",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhang",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "How does academic self-efficacy influence learning anxiety and academic burnout",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in Chinese characters learning among international students in China?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Faculty of Humanities and Foreign Languages, Xi'an University of Technology,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Humanities and Foreign Languages",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xi'an University of Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: The interplay between learning self-efficacy, anxiety, and burnout",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "has been extensively documented in English as a Second Language (ESL) education.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "English",
        "label": "LANGUAGE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "However, Chinese character learning-a uniquely complex task involving",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "visual-spatial processing, stroke order mastery, and radical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decomposition-presents distinct cognitive and affective challenges. The dynamics",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of self-efficacy, anxiety, and burnout in Chinese character acquisition remain",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "under-explored, creating a critical gap in understanding how these constructs",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "operate in non-alphabetic language contexts.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(LA) affects academic burnout (AB) and explores the role of academic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "self-efficacy (ASE) in the relationship between the two.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: A study of 537 international students (50.4% males, mean",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "537",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "50.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "age = 20.96 years, SD = 1.36) was conducted using the Academic Self-Efficacy",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "20.96 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.36",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Academic Self-Efficacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Scale (ASES), Foreign Language Learning Anxiety Scale (FLLAS), Academic Burnout",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Foreign Language Learning Anxiety Scale",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly and negatively correlated with ASE. ② ASE mediated the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "②",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "relationship between LA and AB. ③ Grade level, sleep quality, and parental",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AB",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "③",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "education level have a significant effect on ASE, LA and AB; and ④ Extroversion",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "④ Extroversion",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "has a significant effect on ASE, but not on LA and AB.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AB",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: The chain mediation model validated by this study provides valuable",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "insights into the effects of international students' learning anxiety (LA) on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "academic burnout (AB) in China, alongside practical implications for preventing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and intervening in LA and AB among other current students.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Lin.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The author declares that the research was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "EF-G Mutations Reveal Correlation between Power Stroke and Translocation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Fidelity in Protein Synthesis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The ribosome translocates on the mRNA by primarily three nucleotides per step",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "during protein synthesis, a process catalyzed by elongation factor G (EF-G). The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "large conformational changes of EF-G in this process generate significant",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanical force, referred to as power stroke. Quantification of power stroke",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "remains under debate and its potential correlation with translocation fidelity",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "has not been observed. In this work, we present a unique application of quantum",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "quantum",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sensing in combined measurements of the power strokes of mutated EF-G and their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "influence on ribosome translocation steps. Two EF-G mutants, H584K and Q508K,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "H584K",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Q508K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were expressed, with the mutated residues directly interacting with tRNA. H584K,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mutated",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "H584K",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "which interacts on codon-anticodon minihelix, produced a much reduced power",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke of 60 ± 6 pN and induced -1 frameshifting, wherein the ribosome",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "60",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "translocated only two nucleotides on both sides of the mRNA. In contrast, Q508K,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "only two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Q508K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "which interacts with tRNA residue 37 immediately outside the codon-anticodon",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "37",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "minihelix, exhibited a power stroke of 89 ± 11 pN and maintained canonical 3-nt",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "89",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "11",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3-nt\n",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "translocation, similar to wild-type EF-G. These findings provide direct",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanistic evidence that the pivotal point and force projection exerted by EF-G",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "are critical for maintaining translocation fidelity, likely via lowering the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Multimodal Analysis of Sepsis-induced Cardiomyopathy in a Baboon Model.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Multimodal Analysis of Sepsis",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cardiomyopathy",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sepsis-induced cardiomyopathy (SIC) significantly contributes to sepsis-related",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "morbidity and mortality, necessitating a deeper understanding of its mechanisms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "This study used a post-hoc, multimodal approach-including single-nucleus RNA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sequencing (snRNA-seq), echocardiography, mitochondrial function, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "histopathology-to characterize SIC in a non-human primate model. Archived data",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and samples from six baboons challenged with 37.5 mg/kg of purified",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "37.5 mg/kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "peptidoglycan were analyzed. Vital signs and echocardiography were monitored for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "8 hours; the endpoint was survival at 168 hours or euthanasia for irreversible",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "168 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "organ failure. Septic shock-defined by hypotension, tachycardia, and elevated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lactate-was associated with poor outcomes. Echocardiography showed reduced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed distinct transcriptomic profiles: non-survivors exhibited inflammation,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mitochondrial dysfunction, and maladaptive remodeling; survivors showed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activation of pathways supporting contraction, metabolism, and repair. Cell-type",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis highlighted metabolic dysfunction in cardiomyocytes, TNF/NF-κB-driven",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNF/NF-κB-driven\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inflammation in endothelial cells, and stress responses in fibroblasts and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pericytes. Mitochondrial analysis showed impaired electron transport and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disrupted metabolism. Histopathology revealed inflammation and myofibrillar",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "damage, more severe in non-survivors. This model recapitulates key SIC features",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and supports mechanistic and therapeutic discovery.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Competition between tool and hand motion impairs movement planning in limb",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Thibault S, Yates JB, Buxbaum LJ, Wong AL.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Thibault S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yates JB",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Buxbaum LJ",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wong AL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tool use is a complex motor planning problem. Prior research suggests that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "planning to use tools involves resolving competition between different",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tool-related action representations. We therefore reasoned that competition may",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "also be exacerbated with tools for which the motions of the tool and the hand",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "are incongruent (e.g., pinching the fingers to open a clothespin). If this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hypothesis is correct, we should observe marked deficits in planning the use of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "incongruent as compared to congruent tools in individuals with limb apraxia",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "following left-hemisphere stroke (LCVA), a disorder associated with abnormal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "action competition. We asked 34 individuals with chronic LCVA (14 females) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "34",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "14",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "16 matched neurotypical controls (8 females) to use novel tools in which the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correspondence between the motions of the hand and tool-tip were either",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "congruent or incongruent. Individuals with LCVA also completed background",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LCVA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "assessments to quantify apraxia severity. We observed increased planning time",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for incongruent as compared to congruent tools as a function of apraxia",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "severity. Further analysis revealed that this impairment predominantly occurred",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "early in the task when the tools were first introduced. Lesion-symptom mapping",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analyses revealed that lesions to posterior temporal and inferior parietal areas",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were associated with impaired planning for incongruent tools. A second",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "experiment on the same individuals with LCVA revealed that the ability to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LCVA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gesture the use of conventional tools was impaired for tools rated as more",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "incongruent by a normative sample. These findings suggest that tool-hand",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "incongruence evokes action competition and influences the tool-use difficulties",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "experienced by people with apraxia.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SIGNIFICANCE STATEMENT: Prior research indicates that competition between",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SIGNIFICANCE STATEMENT",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "different representations associated with moving or using tools must be resolved",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to enable tool use. We demonstrated that competition may be exacerbated when",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tool and hand motions are incongruent (e.g., pinching the hand opens a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clothespin), resulting in tool-use impairments particularly for individuals with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "greater severity of limb apraxia, a disorder known to be associated with action",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "competition abnormalities. Lesions in posterior portions of the brain's tool use",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "network were associated with impairments in planning incongruent tool actions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "This study thus demonstrates that tool-hand incongruence may invoke competition",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between motions of the hand and tool-tip, which individuals with limb apraxia",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "have difficulty resolving to properly use tools.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Luminal Vascular Dysfunction Drives Rapid Blood Brain Barrier Injury in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Luminal Vascular Dysfunction Drives Rapid Blood Brain Barrier Injury",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hyperglycemic Stroke: Key Roles for Luminal Glycocalyx and Complement.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Chen H, Frank JA, Tan C, Lee AG, Kopchock R, Chiang T, Kim A, Galvan M, Fraser",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chen H",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Frank JA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tan C",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lee AG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kim A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Galvan M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fraser",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "JF, Dornbos D, Aboul-Nour H, Millson N, Tomlinson S, McCullough LD, Pennypacker",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "JF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dornbos D",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aboul-Nour H",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Millson N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tomlinson S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "McCullough LD",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pennypacker",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Acute hyperglycemia affects approximately 40% of stroke patients and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "approximately 40%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "is associated with worse outcomes. The underlying mechanisms linking this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic stress to stroke-induced brain injury remains unclear, and effective",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "therapies are lacking.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: In a mouse model of acute hyperglycemic stroke, luminal disruption,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "blood-brain barrier (BBB) leakage, neurological deficit, motor function, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mortality were evaluated. Vascular luminal glycocalyx and complement activation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were assessed by immunostaining, with glycocalyx loss confirmed by electron",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "glycocalyx",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "electron\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "microscopy. Complement C3's causal role was tested using C3 knockout mice and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Complement C3's",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "C3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "site-targeted inhibition with CR2-Crry. To enhance translational relevance,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CR2-Crry",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "post-mortem human stroke and control brains were immunostained to assess the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "association between endothelial glycocalyx loss and vascular complement",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "glycocalyx",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "activation. In a separate stroke patient cohort, soluble complement activation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "products were measured in pre-thrombectomy plasma, and their predictive value",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for modified Rankin Scale (mRS) outcomes evaluated using elastic net regression.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rankin Scale",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Hyperglycemic stroke mice exhibited accelerated and more severe BBB",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "breakdown, greater functional deficits, and higher mortality than normoglycemic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "controls, mirroring clinical observations. Acute hyperglycemia triggered rapid",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "vascular luminal injury characterized by loss of endothelial luminal glycocalyx,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "luminal IgM/IgG deposition, and vascular complement C3 activation, leading to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BBB disruption. This vascular luminal injury was corroborated in human stroke",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "brain tissue. These luminal changes persisted despite glucose normalization and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were exacerbated by reperfusion, driving injury into the brain parenchyma.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Genetic and pharmacological approaches confirmed vascular complement activation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "as a causal driver of severe BBB disruption and poor outcomes. Importantly,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "site-targeted pharmacological inhibition of complement after reperfusion",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preserved BBB integrity and improved outcomes, defining a time-specific,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "luminal-directed strategy as a promising adjunct to thrombectomy. Notably,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "soluble complement activation markers in pre-thrombectomy stroke plasma",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "predicted clinical outcomes, highlighting their potential as pre-intervention",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "markers for patient stratification and tailored therapy.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: This study reframes acute hyperglycemic stroke as a vascular luminal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disorder, establishing a novel Metabolic-Complement-Vascular (MCV) axis linking",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Metabolic-Complement-Vascular",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic stress to endothelial luminal glycocalyx loss, vascular complement",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activation, and BBB breakdown in both mice and humans. This new mechanistic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding transforms the therapeutic landscape of hyperglycemic stroke,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "offering a potential time-defined, luminal-focused adjunct therapy alongside",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thrombectomy.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CLINICAL PERSPECTIVE: What Is New?: - This study reframes hyperglycemic stroke",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "as an acute vascular luminal problem, marked by rapid loss of endothelial",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "luminal glycocalyx and complement C3 activation at the vascular luminal surface.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "- The rapid luminal changes, identified in both rodent and human stroke brain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissues, establish a novel Metabolic-Complement-Vascular (MCV) axis linking",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Metabolic-Complement-Vascular",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic stress to luminal damage, blood-brain barrier (BBB) breakdown, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "injury progression into the brain parenchyma. - The first clinical evidence that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pre-thrombectomy plasma complement activation markers independently predict",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke outcomes - laying the foundation for risk stratification before",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reperfusion and precision adjunct therapies.What Are the Clinical Implications?:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "- The rapidity and persistence of the MCV axis activation-even after glucose",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "normalization-help explain the limited efficacy of insulin therapy, shifting the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "therapeutic focus from glycemic control to luminal-targeted interventions.-",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Identification of a narrow but actionable window following reperfusion where",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complement C3 inhibition preserves the BBB and limits injury progression to the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "parenchyma, offers a promising adjunct to thrombectomy in metabolically",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "vulnerable stroke patients.- Targeting the vascular luminal surface reshapes the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "therapeutic landscape for hyperglycemic stroke by enabling systemic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interventions-bypassing the challenge of BBB penetration, supporting rapid",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical translation using existing FDA-approved C3 inhibitors, and framing the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "C3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "endothelial glycocalyx as a promising area for therapeutic and diagnostic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "exploration in hyperglycemic stroke and broader cerebrovascular disease.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cross-sectional Cranial CT Imaging Findings and Patterns in Clinically Diagnosed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cranial CT Imaging Findings",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19 Cases in a Tertiary Referral Center.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19 Cases",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Vascular and Interventional Radiology Section, Department of Radiology,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Interventional Radiology Section,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Radiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Philippine General Hospital, University of the Philippines Manila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Philippine General Hospital, University of the Philippines",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Manila",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by the SARS-CoV-2 virus,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "presents not only as a respiratory ailment but also poses risks of neurological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications whose underlying mechanisms remain unclear. These complications",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "range from mild to severe and may involve direct invasion of the central nervous",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "system (CNS), disruption of the blood-brain barrier, or systemic cytokine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effects. Diagnostic challenges persist due to the suboptimal sensitivity of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RT-PCR assays.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RT-PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: The present study aimed to review the contrast and non-contrast",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "enhanced cranial CT images of all diagnosed COVID-19 patients in a tertiary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "referral center with the clinical impression of non-traumatic and nonoperative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CNS pathologies.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with neurological symptoms. Among 51 included patients, plain CT scans",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were predominantly used, revealing no acute infarcts or hemorrhages in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "majority, while frontal lobe involvement was notable in cases with pathology.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Chronic infarcts or ischemic changes were observed in over half of the cases,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "over half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "primarily affecting the anterior circulation. Only one case of meningitis was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Only one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "meningitis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: In the final analysis, 51 patients met the inclusion criteria out of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the initial 64 enrolled. The study population, predominantly male with a mean",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "64",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "age of 58.02 ± 20.87 years, mainly comprised patients solely diagnosed with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "58.02",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "20.87 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19. Plain CT scans were favored over contrast-enhanced scans (76.50%, n =",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "76.50%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "39). While most patients had no acute infarcts or hemorrhages, the frontal lobe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "39",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was commonly affected among stroke patients (9.8%, n = 5). Additionally, a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9.8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant portion of patients without acute stroke findings exhibited chronic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infarcts or ischemic changes (57.69%, n = 15).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "57.69%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: This study sheds light on the radiological patterns of CNS",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "involvement in COVID-19 patients, highlighting frequent frontal lobe involvement",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "possibly attributed to hypercoagulability and endotheliitis. Further research",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with larger sample sizes and MRI utilization is recommended to enhance our",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding of CNS manifestations in COVID-19. This study contributes to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding COVID-19 neurological sequelae, particularly in terms of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings highlight the need for comprehensive evaluation and management of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Dependence of mitochondrial dysfunction in peripheral blood mononuclear cells on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cervicocephalic atherosclerotic burden in acute ischemic stroke.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "cervicocephalic atherosclerotic",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Neurology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xuanwu Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Capital Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)National Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders, Beijing, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Research Center for Geriatric Disorders",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Beijing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Radiology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Xuanwu Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Capital Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Center for Evidence-Based Medicine, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Xuanwu Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Capital Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Beijing, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Beijing",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Neurobiology, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xuanwu Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Capital Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Clinical Biobank, Xuanwu Hospital, Capital Medical University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Biobank",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xuanwu Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Capital Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "As an inflammatory disease, atherosclerosis is associated with acute ischemic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke (AIS), but its early identification and intervention efficacy remain",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suboptimal. A new research direction may be to explore peripheral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "atherosclerotic biomarkers from the perspective of mitochondrial dysfunction,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "which can induce inflammatory cell activation. Moreover, the degree of overall",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cervicocephalic atherosclerosis (namely, atherosclerotic burden) is more closely",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "related to AIS prognosis than local atherosclerotic lesions. Therefore, this",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "study investigated the relationship between mitochondrial dysfunction in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs), including monocytes and lymphocytes,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and overall cervicocephalic atherosclerotic burden and AIS outcome. Patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with AIS and cervicocephalic atherosclerosis were enrolled and followed up for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "90 days. The reactive oxygen species (ROS) and the mitochondrial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ROS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "deoxyribonucleic acid copy number (mtDNA-CN) in PBMCs were measured respectively",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "deoxyribonucleic",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "through a fluorescence probe and a droplet digital polymerase chain reaction to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluate mitochondrial function. The overall intracranial and cervical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "atherosclerotic burden (ICAB) was quantified by summing up the atherosclerosis",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "degree points in each arterial segment as assessed by computed tomography",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "angiography. A modified Rankin Scale (mRS) score >2 was considered a 90-day",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rankin Scale",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "90-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "unfavorable functional outcome. Five (4.9%) of the 103 patients with AIS were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "4.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "103",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lost to follow-up. mtDNA-CN [adjusted β = -0.099, 95% confidence intervals (CIs)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "= -0.153 ∼ -0.044, p < 0.001] and ROS content (adjusted β = 1.275, 95%CI = 0.885",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ROS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.275",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.885",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "∼ 1.665, p < 0.001) were correlated with ICAB. The risk of a 90-day unfavorable",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.665",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "p < 0.001",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ICAB",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "90-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "functional outcome increased with higher ROS content [adjusted odds ratio (OR) =",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ROS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1.523, 95%CI = 1.172 ∼ 1.981, p = 0.002] and decreased with higher mtDNA-CN",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.523",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.172",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.981",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.002",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(adjusted OR = 0.911, 95%CI = 0.850 ∼ 0.976, p = 0.008). PBMC mitochondrial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.911",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.850",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.976",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.008",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dysfunction was found to be independently associated with extensive and severe",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cervicocephalic atherosclerosis and a 90-day unfavorable functional outcome in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with AIS, which may provide a novel approach to improving the early",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "identification and risk stratification of cervicocephalic atherosclerosis, along",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with the prediction of the outcome of atherosclerotic AIS.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Zhao, Yang, Du, Li, Hou, Cai and Ma.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhao",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yang, Du",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cai",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ma",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "13. Brain Netw Disord. 2025 Jun;1(2):98-108. doi: 10.1016/j.bnd.2024.08.001. Epub",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1016/j.bnd.2024.08.001",
        "label": "MONEY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Acute temporal lesions are associated with phonological word verification",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Otolaryngology, Loma Linda University School of Medicine, Loma",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Otolaryngology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Loma Linda University School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Loma",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Radiology and Radiological Science, Johns Hopkins University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Radiology and Radiological Science",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johns Hopkins University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, 21287, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Baltimore",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MD",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "21287",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Speech-Language Pathology & Audiology, Towson University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Speech-Language Pathology & Audiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Towson University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Towson, MD, 21252, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Towson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MD",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "21252",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Communication Sciences and Disorders, University of South",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Communication Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Disorders, University of South\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Carolina Arnold School of Public Health, Columbia, SC, 29208, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Carolina Arnold School of Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Columbia",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "29208",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Department of Cognitive Sciences, Department of Language Science, University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cognitive Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Language Science",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of California, Irvine, CA, 92697, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "California",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Irvine",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "CA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "92697",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Within the dual stream model for language, the bilateral dorsal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "superior temporal gyrus (STG) is associated with spectro-temporal analysis while",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the mid-post superior temporal sulcus is associated with processing of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "higher-level phonological codes. However, the true lateralization of functions",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "needed for phonological discrimination at the word level remains unsettled. The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "aim of the present work was to determine if individuals with acute stroke",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "primarily involving the left STG and middle temporal gyrus (MTG) demonstrated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "STG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "poorer discrimination (d') between phonologically related words in a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "word-picture verification task than those with left hemisphere lesions outside",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the temporal lobe and compared to those with right hemisphere stroke. The latter",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "would support a left bias and provide an estimate of the magnitude.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: One hundred fourteen individuals with acute stroke completed both acute",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "One hundred fourteen",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "magnetic resonance imaging and a word-picture verification task with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "phonological and semantic foils. Eighty-nine participants had left hemisphere",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Eighty-nine",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke (51 included the temporal lobe). Twenty participants had right hemisphere",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Twenty",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stroke (14 included the temporal lobe). Five participants with bilateral stroke",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "14",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were included (3 included the bilateral temporal lobes). Quantile regression was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "performed controlling for overall lesion volume, age, and sex.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: While more than half of patients performed the task well, patients with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "more than half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "left temporal lobe lesions were more likely to perform poorly.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: These results confirm a role for the left superior temporal lobe,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "including the STG, in phonological processing during word recognition, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "STG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "indicate that a subset of individuals (<50%) have varying degrees of left bias",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "50%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in discrimination of phonologically similar words in the STG.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "STG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declaration of competing interest The authors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Editorial: Women in radiology: neuroimaging and neurotechnology.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)College of Health and Life Sciences, London South Bank University, London,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Health and Life Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "London South Bank University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "London",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "United Kingdom.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "United Kingdom",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Translational Neuroscience and Stroke, Queen Square Institute",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Translational Neuroscience",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Stroke, Queen Square Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)TU London, Teesside University London, London, United Kingdom.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)TU",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "London",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Teesside University London",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "London",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United Kingdom",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Lysholm Department of Neuroradiology, National Hospital for Neurology and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Department of Neuroradiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "National Hospital for Neurology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Late-onset ornithine transcarbamylase deficiency mimicking cognitive, behavioral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and gait disorders: a case report and literature review.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Neurology and Stroke Department, St. Adalbert Hospital, Gdansk, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Stroke Department",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "St. Adalbert Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gdansk",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Intensive Care Unit, St. Adalbert Hospital, Gdansk, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Care Unit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "St. Adalbert Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gdansk",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Neurological-Psychiatric Nursing, Faculty of Health Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical University of Gdansk, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical University of Gdansk",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PURPOSE: Progressive cognitive disorders are not always caused primarily by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "neurodegenerative diseases. This case report emphasizes the importance of taking",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "rare metabolic disorders into consideration in the differential diagnosis in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "rare metabolic",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients of all ages. It also shows the possible risk of corticosteroids in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment of unexplained neurological symptoms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CASE DESCRIPTION: We report on the case of a 60-year-old female who presented",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DESCRIPTION",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "60-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mild dementia with progression and fluctuations for the last 5 years, scanning",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the last 5 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "speech and wide-base gait. Due to a significantly elevated level of anti-thyroid",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thyroiditis (STREAT) was suspected and steroids were administered. This was a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "thyroiditis",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "STREAT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "trigger factor for the patient developing coma with severe hyperammonemia.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Consequent genetic testing identified a pathogenic variant of the OTC (ornithine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "COMMENT: Late-onset ornithine transcarbamylase deficiency can be a rare cause of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cognitive impairment. It is reasonable to determine the level of ammonia in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with non-specific symptoms, as hyperammonemia can cause permanent brain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Institute of Psychiatry and Neurology.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institute of Psychiatry and Neurology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Absent.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Anti-LGI1-antibody autoimmune encephalitis as a neurological paraneoplastic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Anti-LGI1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "syndrome associated with gastrointestinal stromal tumour: a case report.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Neurology and Stroke, University Clinical Hospital 2 of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Stroke, University Clinical Hospital 2",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Lodz, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Lodz",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Neurology and Faculty of Health Science, Mazovian \"Bródnowski\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology and Faculty of Health Science",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital, Warsaw, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Warsaw",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Medical University of Warsaw, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Warsaw",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Extrapyramidal Diseases, Central Teaching Hospital of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Extrapyramidal Diseases",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Central Teaching Hospital of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Medical University of Lodz, Poland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Lodz",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Poland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PURPOSE: The aim of the case is to present the significance of a thorough",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis of the cases of patients with newly developed memory disorders",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "accompanied by epileptic seizures.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CASE DESCRIPTION: We present a case of a 61-year-old male patient who was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DESCRIPTION",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "61-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "admitted to the hospital due to unexplained memory disorders and seizures.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Further examination showed the presence of anti-LGI1 (leucine-rich",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "anti-LGI1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "glioma-inactivated 1) antibodies. Computed tomography of the abdominal cavity",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed a mass located between the stomach and the spleen. Histopathological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "examination identified the mass as a gastrointestinal tumour (GIST). After the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "surgical removal of the tumour the symptoms were significantly reduced. The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "early diagnosis and treatment of the tumour contributed to favourable",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neurological and oncological outcomes for the patient.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "COMMENT: Paraneoplastic neurological syndrome is a clinical condition in which",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the functioning of the nervous system is impaired, not resulting from local",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tumour growth or metastases. The currently recognized underlaying mechanism of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "this condition is an autoimmune reaction occurring in the patient's body. In",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "response to the presence of tumour, the antibodies called onconeural antibodies",
