[
  {
    "text": "Successful Hemostasis With Platelet Transfusion and Tranexamic Acid, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Inhibitor Elimination With Cyclosporine, in Steroid-Resistant Acquired",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Steroid-Resistant",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Coagulation Factor V Deficiency Caused by Antibiotic Readministration.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Coagulation Factor V Deficiency",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Hematology, Chikamori Hospital, Kochi, Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hematology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chikamori Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kochi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Gastroenterology, Chikamori Hospital, Kochi, Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastroenterology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kochi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Cardiology, Chikamori Hospital, Kochi, Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cardiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kochi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Acquired factor V deficiency (AFVD) is a rare coagulation abnormality associated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AFVD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with infectious diseases, antibiotics, surgery, autoimmune diseases, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malignancy, which causality is difficult to prove. Here, we report a case of a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "90-year-old woman who developed melena following antibiotic treatment for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pneumonia. She had been on cefepime for bacterial pneumonia for 2 months to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2 weeks prior to her arrival in the emergency room. Upon presentation, she had",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2 weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "severe anemia (Hb: 6.7 g/dL) and prolonged PT (74.3 s) and activated partial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hb",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "6.7",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "74.3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thromboplastin time (APTT) (161.9 s). Coagulation studies revealed incomplete",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "thromboplastin time",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "161.9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correction of the APTT in a 1:1 mixing study with normal pooled plasma, factor V",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APTT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1:1",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "activity of 0%, and a factor V inhibitor titer of 13 Bethesda units, confirming",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bethesda",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the diagnosis of AFVD. Since the antibiotics were not recognized as the cause,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AFVD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the coagulation abnormality worsened after their readministration. The melena",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "subsequently improved with platelet transfusion and administration of tranexamic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "acid, while prednisolone-resistant coagulation abnormalities improved with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cyclosporine A (CsA) treatment. This case shows the importance of avoiding",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CsA",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suspected drugs and the effectiveness of CsA as a second-line treatment of AFVD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CsA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "AFVD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Kazuto Togitani et al. Case Reports in Hematology published by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kazuto Togitani",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hematology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "John Wiley & Sons Ltd.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "John Wiley & Sons Ltd.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Extracellular Vesicle-Mediated Delivery of Genetic Material for Transformation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and CRISPR/Cas9-based Gene Editing in Pneumocystis murina.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR/Cas9",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gene Editing",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sayson SG, Ashbaugh A, Bauer LC, Smulian G.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sayson SG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ashbaugh A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Smulian G.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pneumocystis species are obligate fungal pathogens that cause severe pneumonia,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "particularly in immunocompromised individuals. The absence of robust genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "manipulation tools has impeded our mechanistic understanding of Pneumocystis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "biology and the development of novel therapeutic strategies. Herein, we describe",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a novel method for the stable transformation and CRISPR/Cas9-mediated genetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "editing of Pneumocystis murina utilizing extracellular vesicles (EVs) as a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "delivery vehicle. Building upon our prior investigations demonstrating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "EV-mediated delivery of exogenous material to Pneumocystis , we engineered mouse",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lung EVs to deliver plasmid DNA encoding reporter genes and CRISPR/Cas9",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "lung EVs",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CRISPR/Cas9",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "components. Our initial findings demonstrated successful in vitro transformation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and subsequent expression of mNeonGreen and Dhps ARS in P. murina organisms.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Subsequently, we established stable in vivo expression of mNeonGreen in mice",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infected with transformed P. murina for a duration of up to 5 weeks.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "up to 5 weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Furthermore, we designed and validated a CRISPR/Cas9 system targeting the P.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "murina Dhps gene, confirming its in vitro cleavage efficiency. Ultimately, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dhps",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "achieved successful in vivo CRISPR/Cas9-mediated homologous recombination,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "precisely introducing a Dhps ARS mutation into the P. murina genome, which was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dhps",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "confirmed by Sanger sequencing across all tested animals. Here, we establish a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sanger",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "foundational methodology for genetic manipulation in Pneumocystis , thereby",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "opening avenues for functional genomics, drug target validation, and the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "generation of genetically modified strains for advanced research and potential",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "therapeutic applications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "IMPORTANCE: Pneumocystis species are obligate fungal pathogens and major causes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of pneumonia in immunocompromised individuals. However, their strict dependence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "on the mammalian lung environment has precluded the development of genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "manipulation systems, limiting our ability to interrogate gene function, study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "antifungal resistance mechanisms, or validate therapeutic targets. Here, we",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "report the first successful approach for stable transformation and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CRISPR/Cas9-based genome editing of Pneumocystis murina , achieved through in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR/Cas9",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "vivo delivery of engineered extracellular vesicles (EVs) containing plasmid DNA",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and encoding CRISPR/Cas9 components. We demonstrate sustained transgene",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expression and precise modification of the dhps locus via homology-directed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "repair. This modular, scalable platform overcomes a long-standing barrier in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "field and establishes a foundation for functional genomics in Pneumocystis and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "other obligate, host-adapted microbes.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The Maximum-Tolerated Dose and Pharmacokinetics of ISFP10 a Novel Inhibitor of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Maximum-Tolerated Dose",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pharmacokinetics of ISFP10 a Novel Inhibitor of\n",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: The newly identified small molecule ISFP10 has demonstrated the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ability to inhibit fungal phosphoglucomutases (PGM), leading to decreased fungal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PGM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "growth and survival. Exhibiting 50 times greater selectivity for fungal PGM",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "50",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PGM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "compared to the human homolog, ISFP10 shows promise as a broad-spectrum",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "antifungal and a candidate for preliminary testing in rodent models of fungal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infections, including Pneumocystis pneumonia (PCP). In preparation for targeted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "PCP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and relevant administration of the drug in fungal mouse models of infection, the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fungal mouse",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "current study describes the maximum-tolerated-dose (MTD) and pharmacokinetics",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(PK) of ISFP10 in mice.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: For the MTD study, 24 C57BL/6 mice were randomly distributed into 6",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MTD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "24",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "groups (2M/2F per group): Placebo (vehicle; 10% DMSO with 90% of 0.5%",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2M/2F",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Placebo",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "10%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "methylcellulose in 0.9% NaCl) at various doses (12.5, 25, 50, 100, 200 mg/kg),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "50",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "100",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "200 mg/kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were administered twice daily by intraperitoneally (IP) for 7 consecutive days.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "7 consecutive days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "For the PK study, 108 mice were administered either vehicle or ISFP10 in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "108",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "single-dose intraperitoneal (IP) injections twice daily for 7 consecutive days",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "7 consecutive days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "at concentrations of 0, 12.5, 25, 50, and 100 mg/kg. Pharmacokinetics were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.5",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "50",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "100 mg/kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pharmacokinetics",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "assessed in plasma, and epithelial lining fluid (ELF). Analysis of this test",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ELF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "compound was performed using LC-MS/MS for PK evaluation on blood samples drawn",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LC-MS/MS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "from mice at multiple time points.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: IP administered, ISFP10 did not produce significant changes in body",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "weight, food consumption or adverse events in the MTD up to 100 mg/kg dosing.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "100 mg/kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The plasma PK study demonstrated T max values ranging from 2 to 8 h.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Non-compartmental analysis (NCA) yielded elimination half-life values, t 1/2 ,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NCA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1/2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of 4.39 and 5.31 h for the 12.5 and 50 mg/kg dose groups. Concentration",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4.39",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5.31",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.5 and",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dependent peak-blood concentration (C max ) at the dosing and length tested",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: In conclusion, ISFP10, administered intraperitoneally to mice twice",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "daily at doses up to 100 mg/kg, exhibited no inherent safety concerns based on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "100 mg/kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the analyzed parameters. Pharmacokinetic analysis revealed slow absorption and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distribution kinetics, with plasma T max values ranging from 2 to 8 hours and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "distribution kinetics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2 to 8 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "elimination half-lives of approximately 4-5 hours at lower doses. These data",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4-5 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "support broader in vivo testing of the inhibitor as potential novel antifungal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in fungal diseases including PCP.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Identification of Chlamydia pneumoniae and NLRP3 inflammasome activation in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Identification of Chlamydia",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease retina.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Gaire BP, Koronyo Y, Vit JP, Hutton A, Swerdlow N, Fuchs DT, Rentsendorj A,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Koronyo Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vit JP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hutton A",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Swerdlow N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fuchs DT",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rentsendorj A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gupta VK, Mirzaei M, Black KL, Meyer JG, Arditi M, Crother TR, Koronyo-Hamaoui",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gupta VK",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mirzaei M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Black KL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Meyer JG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Arditi M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Crother TR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Koronyo-Hamaoui",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chlamydia pneumoniae (Cp), an obligate intracellular bacterium, has been",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chlamydia",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "implicated in Alzheimer's disease (AD), yet its role in retinal pathology",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "remains unexplored. We analyzed postmortem tissues from 95 human donors and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "95",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "found 2.9-4.1-fold increases in Cp inclusions in AD retinas and brains, with no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.9-4.1-fold",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cp",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant elevation in mild cognitive impairment (MCI). Proteomics revealed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dysregulation of retinal and brain bacterial infection-related proteins and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "NLRP3 inflammasome pathways. NLRP3 expression was markedly elevated in MCI and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AD retinas, and its activation was evident by increased N-terminal gasdermin D",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NGSDMD) and mature interleukin-1β. Retinal Cp strongly correlated with Aβ 42",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Retinal Cp",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ 42\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and NLRP3 inflammasome components, which tightly linked to cleaved",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "caspase-3-apoptotic and NGSDMD-pyroptotic cell death. Although retinal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "microgliosis was elevated in AD, Cp-associated microglia were reduced by 62%,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "62%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suggesting impaired Cp phagocytosis. Higher retinal Cp burden correlated with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "APOEε4, Braak stage, and cognitive deficit. Machine learning identified retinal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Braak",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cp or NLRP3 combined with Aβ 42 as strong predictors of AD diagnosis, staging,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "42",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and cognitive impairment. Our findings suggest that Cp infection contributes to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AD dementia but not initiating pathology, whereas early NLRP3 activation may",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "promote disease development, warranting studies on Cp's role in AD pathogenesis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cp",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and early antibiotic or inflammasome-targeted therapies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "5. Arch Clin Cases. 2025 Jul 15;12(2):98-101. doi: 10.22551/2025.47.1202.10320.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Arch Clin Cases",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "15;12(2):98",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.22551/2025.47.1202.10320",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Teclistamab-associated cytokine release syndrome in multiple myeloma: a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "case-based literature review of mechanisms, management, and clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "implications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cheema M(1), Syed S(1), Ghuman Z(1), Iftikhar A(2)(3).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Syed S(1",
        "label": "LAW"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ghuman Z(1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Internal Medicine, Mather Hospital, Northwell Health, Port",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mather Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Northwell Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Jefferson, NY, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jefferson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NY",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Division of Intensive Care Medicine and Pulmonary Medicine, Northwell Health,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Intensive Care Medicine and Pulmonary Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Northwell Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Port Jefferson, NY, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Port Jefferson",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "NY",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Donald and Barbara School of Medicine, Hofstra/Northwell, Hempstead, NY, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Barbara School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hempstead",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "NY",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cytokine release syndrome (CRS) is a potentially life-threatening inflammatory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "condition that can occur after immune-based therapies, such as bispecific",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "multiple myeloma who developed fatal CRS following treatment with Teclistamab, a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Teclistamab",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "bispecific antibody that targets CD3 on T cells and B-cell maturation antigen on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "myeloma cells. The patient had previously achieved remission with rituximab,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "bortezomib, and autologous stem cell transplantation but experienced a relapse",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "after eight years. Teclistamab was initiated with a step-up dosing regimen.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eight years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Teclistamab",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Before treatment, she received premedication with intravenous fluids, steroids,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and tocilizumab. Despite this premedication, the patient was readmitted with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fever, chills, and shortness of breath, leukopenia, and hypoxia. Imaging studies",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "indicated pneumonia. During her hospitalization, her condition deteriorated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "rapidly, resulting in respiratory failure and refractory shock. She was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transferred to the intensive care unit (ICU), where she required mechanical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ICU",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "efforts, she progressed to multi-organ failure, and the family ultimately chose",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to withdraw care. CRS is characterized by a systemic inflammatory response with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "rapid and excessive release of cytokines, particularly IL-6, IL-2, IL-10, IFN-γ,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IL-10",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "IFN",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and GM-CSF. Severe CRS can clinically resemble sepsis. Management strategies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GM-CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "include early recognition, supportive care, and immunomodulatory therapy,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "particularly with tocilizumab and corticosteroids. This case underscores the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnostic and therapeutic challenges of differentiating severe CRS from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infection. This case uniquely contributes to current understanding by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "highlighting the limitations of current premedication protocols and emphasizing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the critical need for enhanced monitoring and rapid intervention protocols in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "managing Teclistamab-induced CRS. It highlights the critical need for prompt,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "targeted intervention to prevent fatal outcomes in patients receiving novel",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immunotherapies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that they have no competing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Evaluation of the efficacy of cephalosporin antibiotics sold in Kano, Nigeria,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kano, Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "against clinical bacterial isolates.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Life Sciences, College of Natural and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microbiology, Faculty of Life Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "College of Natural",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pharmaceutical Sciences, Bayero University, P.M.B. 3011, Kano, Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bayero University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kano, Nigeria",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Biotechnology, Delft University of Technology, Van der Maasweg",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Biotechnology, Delft University of Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Van",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maasweg",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Microbiology, School of Science and Information Technology,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microbiology, School of Science and Information Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Introduction. The evaluation of the efficacy of cephalosporin antibiotics sold",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in Kano, Nigeria, against clinical bacterial isolates is a timely and crucial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kano, Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "public health concern. Cephalosporins are among the most widely used antibiotic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "classes globally due to their broad-spectrum activity and low toxicity. They",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "play a vital role in the empirical treatment of infections involving both",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacteria. However, the increasing misuse and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gram-negative",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "circulation of substandard or falsified antibiotics, especially in informal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "markets, threatens their therapeutic effectiveness. Gap statement. In Nigeria,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "several formal and informal reports of substandard antibiotics and their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unregulated sale in open markets, such as Sabon Gari in Kano, raise serious",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sabon Gari",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kano",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "concerns about the quality of drug and their potential contribution to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "antimicrobial resistance (AMR). Cephalosporins sold in these markets are often",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AMR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sourced and stored under questionable conditions, which increases the risk of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced potency or inefficacy. At the same time, AMR continues to rise globally,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AMR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and in low and middle-income countries like Nigeria, poor-quality antibiotics",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "can worsen treatment failure and drive resistance. Sabon Gari market is a major",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distribution centre for pharmaceuticals, yet research on its impact and extent",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of substandard drugs is lacking. Aim. This study aims to assess the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aim",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pharmaceutical quality of commonly sold cephalosporins purchased from drug",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distributors in Sabon Gari Market, Kano, by comparing their antimicrobial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sabon Gari Market",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kano",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "activity against a panel of clinical bacterial isolates (Escherichia coli,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Escherichia",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Salmonella sp.) with that of standard reference",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Salmonella",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "antibiotics. Methodology. Antimicrobial susceptibility pattern of the test",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "isolates was determined by the disc diffusion method. Fourier transform infrared",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "spectroscopy analysis was used to confirm the functional group of the active",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ingredients of all the antibiotics tested. Molecular identification of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resistant gene (CTX-M1) was carried out using PCR. Results. Market survey",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CTX-M1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(n=100) reveals that among drug distributors in Sabon Gari Market, Kano,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sabon Gari Market",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kano",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cephalexin 61% (first generation); cefuroxime 72% (second generation); cefixime",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "61%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "72%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "generation); cefepime 84% (fourth generation) were the most commonly sold",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "84%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "fourth",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cephalosporins, with different brands and company names. These percentages",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "represent the proportion of respondents who reported each antibiotic as one of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "their most frequently sold products. There is no significant difference between",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the branded antibiotics (drugs purchased in the market) and standard drugs.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Exactly 20% of E. coli and K. pneumoniae were resistant, while 80% of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "20%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "K.",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "80%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were susceptible. The CTX-M1 resistant gene was identified in E. coli and K.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CTX",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "K.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pneumoniae, which further confirms their resistance to cefotaxime and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ceftriaxone antibiotics. Conclusion. Branded cephalosporins sold in Kano were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ceftriaxone antibiotics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kano",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "chemically intact and structurally aligned with their respective formulations.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "No missing or anomalous functional groups were observed that would suggest",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "substandard or counterfeit products, thus fit for human intake.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that there are no conflicts",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of interest.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "7. J Arrhythm. 2025 Jul 15;41(4):e70079. doi: 10.1002/joa3.70079. eCollection",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1002",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cardiac arrhythmias in cancer patients using the nationwide claim-based database",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cardiac",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Preventive Cardiology National Cerebral and Cardiovascular",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Preventive Cardiology National Cerebral and Cardiovascular",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Division of Cardiovascular Medicine Department of Internal Medicine, Sensoji",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cardiovascular Medicine Department of Internal Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sensoji",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Present address: Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Department of Internal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Division of Cardiovascular Medicine,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Internal",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Cardio-oncology has recently developed as a new discipline. No study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "using a Nationwide Claim-Based Database has examined the association between",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancer and arrhythmia in Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: JROAD-DPC (Japanese Registry Of All cardiac and vascular Diseases -",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Japanese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Diagnosis Procedure Combination) is a nationwide claims database using data from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the Japanese Diagnosis Procedure Combination/Per Diem Payment System. Among",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Japanese Diagnosis Procedure Combination/Per Diem Payment System",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "11 297 525 records found between April 2012 and March 2021 from 1119 hospitals,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "11",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "297",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "525",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "April 2012 and March 2021",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1119",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2 976 362 patients with arrhythmias were studied and divided into categories",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "using cancer.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The prevalence rate of cancers was 7.51% of the patients hospitalized",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7.51%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for arrhythmias, and the prevalence of cancer increased with time. The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prevalence rate of Atrial fibrillation (AF) and/or atrial flutter (AFL) was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Atrial",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "70.6% and 60.7% of arrhythmic patients with and without cancer, respectively.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "70.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "60.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pneumonia (7.41%) was the first major infectious complication in arrhythmic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumonia",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "7.41%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with cancers. Arrhythmic patients with cancers had significantly higher",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Barthel index (65.2 at admission and 72.5 at discharge) and prevalences of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Barthel",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "65.2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "72.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "hyperuricemia (HU) and chronic kidney disease (CKD) (6.13% and 9.67%) than those",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HU",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "6.13%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "9.67%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "without cancer. The rate of emergency hospitalization was higher in arrhythmic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with cancers than those without cancer (58.9% vs. 57.6%).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "58.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "57.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Cancers were frequently observed in arrhythmic patients, and the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prevalences increased with time. AF and/or AFL were the most common arrhythmias",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AF and/or AFL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of cancer patients. Arrhythmic patients with cancers had significantly higher",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Barthel index and prevalences of HU and CKD than those without cancer.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Barthel",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "HU",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "CKD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Journal of Arrhythmia published by John Wiley & Sons",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "John Wiley & Sons",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Australia, Ltd on behalf of Japanese Heart Rhythm Society.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japanese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "this article.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Paraneoplastic Amyopathic Dermatomyositis Associated With a Bone and Medullary",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Location of Breast Adenocarcinoma.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Medical Oncology, Centre Hospitalo-Universitaire Mohammed VI,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Oncology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mohammed VI",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Medical Oncology, Cadi Ayyad University, Marrakesh, MAR.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Oncology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cadi Ayyad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Marrakesh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MAR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Paraneoplastic amyopathic dermatomyositis (ADM) is a rare connective tissue",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disease presenting with characteristic dermatomyositis-like skin findings in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "absence of muscle involvement. It is associated with malignancies in 15%-30% of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15%-30%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cases and may portend a fatal outcome, especially when linked to advanced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cancers. We report the case of a 58-year-old woman who presented with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "58-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "progressive low back pain and erythroderma. Imaging revealed diffuse bone",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metastases, and bone biopsy confirmed a poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "erythema and other cutaneous findings consistent with ADM. The patient was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "started on endocrine therapy with palbociclib and letrozole, along with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "corticosteroids and hydroxychloroquine, resulting in partial clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "improvement. However, within six months of diagnosis, she developed severe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19 pneumonia, complicated by pancytopenia and sepsis, and ultimately",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "succumbed to multiorgan failure despite intensive care support. This case",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "underlines the importance of recognizing paraneoplastic ADM as an initial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ADM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "manifestation of malignancy. A multidisciplinary approach is key, but the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prognosis largely depends on the cancer's burden and complications such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment-induced immunosuppression.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025, Haboub et al.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "al.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Lessons From Recurrent Dropped Head Syndrome After Inadequate Short Fixation: A",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lessons From Recurrent",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Case Series.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Neurosurgery, Shiroishi Kyoritsu Hospital, Shiroishi, JPN.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurosurgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiroishi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "JPN",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Neurosurgery, International University of Health and Welfare",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurosurgery, International University of Health and Welfare",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Dropped head syndrome (DHS) is a condition in which the head falls forward due",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DHS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to dysfunction or atrophy of the cervical extensor muscles. It is more commonly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "observed in elderly women and significantly affects horizontal gaze and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activities of daily living (ADL). For cases in which conservative treatment is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ADL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ineffective, surgical corrective fixation is considered; however, indications",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and standardized procedures have not yet been fully established. We",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "retrospectively analyzed five cases of DHS treated surgically at our institution",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "DHS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and examined the efficacy of corrective fixation and potential treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "strategies. Five patients (mean age: 82.6 years; all female) who underwent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "82.6 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "surgery for DHS between 2018 and 2024 were included. Three patients initially",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DHS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "between 2018 and 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "underwent short-segment fixation or laminoplasty, but DHS recurred. Eventually,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DHS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "all cases required long-segment fixation extending from C2 or the occiput to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Th1/Th2. Radiological evaluations included measurements of the C2-C7 Cobb",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "angles, sagittal vertical axis (SVA), and T1 slope before and after surgery. All",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "T1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients exhibited cervical kyphosis and sagittal imbalance. Postoperatively,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cervical lordosis was restored, and improvements were noted in SVA and T1 slope.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SVA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "T1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "In four cases, patients were able to maintain horizontal gaze for over 30",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "30",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "minutes, and improvements in ADL living were observed. One patient died from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "minutes",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "ADL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "One",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "aspiration pneumonia, although horizontal gaze was maintained postoperatively.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Long-segment corrective fixation within an appropriate range is considered a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "safe and effective treatment option.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025, Honda et al.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Honda",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "al.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A Rare Case of Polymicrobial Empyema Associated With COVID-19 Infection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Complicated by a Bronchopleural Fistula.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Internal Medicine, Nepalese Army Institute of Health Sciences, Kathmandu,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine, Nepalese Army Institute of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kathmandu",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Internal Medicine, Tribhuvan University Institute of Medicine, Kathmandu,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tribhuvan University Institute of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kathmandu",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Empyema is a rare but serious complication in patients with COVID-19, and its",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Empyema",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "association with bronchopleural fistula (BPF) is even more uncommon. We present",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BPF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the case of a 40-year-old woman with a history of intravenous drug use who",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "developed polymicrobial empyema in the setting of COVID-19, further complicated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by BPF. She presented with hypoxic respiratory failure, leukocytosis, and lactic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BPF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "acidosis. Imaging revealed a large right-sided hydropneumothorax and bilateral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lung opacities. Broad-spectrum antibiotics, antivirals, and corticosteroids were",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "initiated, and 3 liters of purulent fluid were drained via chest tube,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "confirming empyema. Cultures identified multiple pathogens, including",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Bacteroides fragilis, Arcanobacterium hemolyticum, methicillin-sensitive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Arcanobacterium",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "methicillin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Staphylococcus aureus, and Group C/G streptococci. Persistent air leak and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Group C/G",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "incomplete lung re-expansion led to a diagnosis of BPF. The patient was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BPF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "successfully managed with prolonged antibiotic therapy and chest tube drainage",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "without requiring surgical or bronchoscopic intervention. This case highlights",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the importance of recognizing and conservatively managing small BPFs in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19-associated empyema, emphasizing the potential for non-surgical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resolution in select cases.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025, Regmi et al.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Correlation of Radiographic and High-Resolution Computed Tomography (HRCT)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Correlation of Radiographic",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Features in Lower Lobe Tuberculosis With Microbiological Findings: A Study in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the Konaseema Region.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Konaseema Region",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Radiology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences and Research",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Radiology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences and Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Microbiology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microbiology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research Foundation, Amalapuram, IND.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amalapuram",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Pulmonology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pulmonology, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: This study aimed to evaluate the radiographic, high-resolution",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tuberculosis (PTB) in general, with a focused correlation analysis in a subset",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of patients with lower lobe tuberculosis (LLTB), to aid in the accurate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LLTB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosis and clinical differentiation of this atypical presentation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "radiology, and microbiology departments of Konaseema Institute of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Konaseema Institute of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences and Research Foundation, Andhra Pradesh. The study period was from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sciences and Research Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Andhra Pradesh",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "December 2022 to June 2024. The study included 40 confirmed cases of LLTB, which",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "December 2022 to June 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "40",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "LLTB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were identified based on microbiological and radiological findings. HRCT and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "chest radiographs were analyzed for characteristic patterns. At the same time,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "microbial confirmation was obtained through Ziehl-Neelsen (ZN) staining,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ziehl-Neelsen",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ZN",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "GeneXpert MTB/RIF assay (Cepheid, Sunnyvale, CA, USA), and culture",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GeneXpert MTB/RIF",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cepheid",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sunnyvale",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "CA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "India). Spearman's correlation was used to assess the correlation between",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Spearman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Patchy opacities were the most frequently observed radiological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "abnormality, identified in 37 (50.0%) out of 74 patients, followed by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "37",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "50.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "74",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "homogeneous consolidation in 31 (41.9%) and cavitation in 14 (18.9%) cases.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "31",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "41.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "14",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Nodular opacities and para-pneumonic effusion were noted in nine (12.2%) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nodular",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "nine",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eight (10.8%) patients, respectively, reflecting the heterogeneous imaging",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patterns associated with LLTB. Sputum smear microscopy for acid-fast bacilli",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LLTB",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sputum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(AFB) yielded positive results in 33 (18.2%) cases, while bronchoalveolar lavage",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AFB",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "33",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(BAL) confirmed tuberculosis in 12 (6.6%) patients. HRCT findings contributed to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BAL",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "6.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the diagnosis in 16 (8.8%) cases. Additionally, nine (5.0%) cases of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "8.8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "nine",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "non-resolving pneumonia and 11 (6.1%) cases presenting with hemoptysis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "11",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "6.1%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "underscored the diagnostic complexity of lower lobe involvement.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: In conclusion, LLTB shows atypical radiological features, often",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LLTB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mimicking pneumonia, with patchy opacities and consolidation. Cavitation is a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "combined clinical, radiological, and microbial approach is essential for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "study. Institutional Ethical Committee, Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institutional Ethical Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Konaseema Institute of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Research Foundation issued approval 83/02.12.2022. Animal subjects: All",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "83/02.12.2022",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "12. Mediastinum. 2025 May 21;9:12. doi: 10.21037/med-24-33. eCollection 2025.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mediastinum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "May 21;9:12",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.21037",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "eCollection",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Complications of linear endobronchial ultrasound guided biopsies: narrative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "review.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, United Health Services",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "United Health Services",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Southern California Medical Education Consortium, Temecula, CA, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Southern California Medical Education Consortium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Temecula",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "CA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Interventional Pulmonology, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, Sleep",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Interventional",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pulmonology, Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sleep\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE: Linear endobronchial ultrasound (EBUS) has become a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "key tool for diagnosing pulmonary diseases, offering high diagnostic yield for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "both malignant and non-malignant conditions. With its increased use, more",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications are being reported. The objective of this narrative review is to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "discuss the complications associated with linear EBUS.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: A literature search using PubMed and Google Scholar from 2009 to 2024",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PubMed",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Google Scholar",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2009",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2024",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was done. We included case reports, prospective, and retrospective studies",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reporting linear EBUS complications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "KEY CONTENT AND FINDINGS: Overall complications from EBUS range from 0.04% to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.04%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "17%. Most common are infectious complications which are 0.04-4%. These include",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "17%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.04-4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mediastinitis, pneumonia, pericarditis, bacteremia, tumor bed infection, lung",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mediastinitis",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "pericarditis",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "abscess, empyema, and septic shock. Other complications include pneumothorax,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "emphysema. Complications due to anesthesia or equipment malfunction can occur as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "emphysema",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "anesthesia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "well. Hemorrhagic complications have been reported as well. Mortality is low",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hemorrhagic",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "0.01-0.04%, and four cases have been reported that led to death from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.01-0.04%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "complications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: With increased use of EBUS as a diagnostic tool, number of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications will increase. Clinicians performing the procedures should be",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinicians",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "aware of types of possible complications that can occur and follow the patients",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "closely after the procedure. Rapid diagnosis and treatment should be done to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 AME Publishing Company. All rights reserved.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AME Publishing Company",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Conflicts of Interest: All authors have",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "completed the ICMJE uniform disclosure form (available at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ICMJE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "https://med.amegroups.com/article/view/10.21037/med-24-33/coif). G.C. received",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "G.C.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Harvard patent on SLIPS from BIDMC, and other patent pending, and received",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Harvard",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BIDMC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "consulting fees from Intuitive, Ajax, Olympus, Cook, Pinnicle Biologics,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Intuitive",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ajax, Olympus",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cook",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pinnicle Biologics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Siemens, Leadoptiks. G.C. also has a leadership role in AABIP board of directors",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Siemens",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Leadoptiks",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "G.C.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and in ACCP. N.M.P. received consulting proctoring fees from Intuitive Surgical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ACCP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "N.M.P.",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Intuitive Surgical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and support for meeting attendance from European Respiratory Society. The other",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "European Respiratory Society",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "STING regulates NETs formation by activating GSDMD in influenza viral pneumonia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GSDMD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)School of Basic Medical Sciences & Forensic Medicine, Hangzhou Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)School of",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Basic Medical Sciences & Forensic Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "College, Hangzhou, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)School of Public Health, Hangzhou Medical College, Hangzhou, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Key Discipline of Zhejiang Province in Public Health and Preventive Medicine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Key",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhejiang Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(First Class, Category A), Hangzhou Medical College, Hangzhou, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "First",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Center for Safety Evaluation and Research, Hangzhou Medical College,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Safety Evaluation and Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hangzhou Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Viral pneumonia is the most common and lethal pandemic disease, but",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "there are no broad-spectrum antiviral drugs with high genetic barriers to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance. To elucidate the mechanisms of viral pneumonia progression and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "potential targets for its treatment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Viral pneumonia models were induced by the PR8 virus strain in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "wild-type (WT) and STING knockout (STING-KO) mice. Series of molecular biology",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "techniques were used to evaluate the severity of pneumonia and cytokine levels.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: In this study, STING (stimulator of interferon genes) was activated in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the lungs of virus-infected mice, leading to cytokine production and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "amplification of the immune response, thereby causing rapid deterioration of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "symptoms. Furthermore, excessive activation of innate immune response via STING",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "was prevented by a STING inhibitor (C-176), which significantly reduced viral",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C-176",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "similarly suppressed during viral pneumonia treatment with STING inhibitors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(C-176), and NETs formation and STING expression were positively correlated,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C-176",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "indicating that STING plays an important role in NETs formation. Symptoms of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pneumonia in STING-KO mice infected with PR8 were significantly milder than",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "those in WT mice, and NETs were less likely to form in the lung tissue of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WT",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "STING-KO mice. Additionally, transcriptomic analysis revealed that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "STING-mediated regulation of NETs may be associated with gasdermin D (GSDMD),",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and immunoprecipitation experiments revealed that STING, GSDMD, and NETs-related",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GSDMD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "proteins interact with each other. Immunofluorescence assays revealed that in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neutrophils from WT mice, STING and GSDMD were colocalized on the membrane after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WT",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "viral infection, whereas in neutrophils from STING-KO mice, GSDMD expression was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decreased after exposure to the virus.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Our study demonstrated that targeted intervention with STING",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "alleviated pneumonia by inhibiting inflammation and NETs formation. The study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "also revealed that blocking STING could inhibit the activation of GSDMD to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GSDMD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibit NETs formation, slowing the progression of viral pneumonia.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Huang, Chen, Xing, Wu, Zhu, Jing, Zhou, Wu, Zhang and You.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Huang",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Xing",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhou",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Clinical Outcomes of Endoscopic Submucosal Dissection for Early Gastric Cancer",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Outcomes of Endoscopic Submucosal Dissection for Early Gastric Cancer",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Patients With Concurrent Advanced Malignancies With Expected Poor Prognosis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Gastroenterology Hiroshima University Hospital Hiroshima Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastroenterology Hiroshima University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hiroshima",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Gastrointestinal Endoscopy and Medicine Hiroshima University Hospital",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Gastrointestinal",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Endoscopy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Medicine Hiroshima University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AIMS: Despite improved outcomes for malignant tumors, evidence regarding the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "management of patients with multiple malignancies remains limited. We aimed to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluate the clinical outcomes and prognosis of patients undergoing endoscopic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "submucosal dissection (ESD) for early gastric cancer (EGC) complicated by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EGC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "advanced malignancies in other organs with a poor prognosis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS AND RESULTS: We retrospectively reviewed 3703 gastric cancer patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3703",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "who underwent ESD at our hospital (2005-2022), focusing on those with advanced",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2005-2022",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "extra-gastric malignancies with a 5-year survival rate of < 50%. ESD was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5-year",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "50%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "ESD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "performed for local tumor control based on patient preference when feasible,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "including lesions meeting standard, expanded, or relative indications where",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "curative resection was unachievable. Clinicopathological characteristics and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes were analyzed. Twenty-six patients met the inclusion criteria. En bloc",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Twenty-six",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resection was achieved in all cases (100%), with curative and non-curative",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "100%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resection in 16 (62%) and 10 (38%) cases, respectively. None of the 10 patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "62%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "38%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with non-curative resection exhibited lymphovascular invasion or GC recurrence.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Complications included delayed bleeding, perforation, and pneumonia, each in one",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "death within 30 days post-ESD. Notably, no complications were reported after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "post-ESD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2010. Eleven patients died from advanced malignant tumors, with no GC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2010",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "GC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "recurrences observed during follow-up in surviving patients.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Recently, no severe complications have been observed with ESD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Although ESD for local control in EGC with concurrent advanced extra-gastric",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EGC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "malignancies may be acceptable, the risk of severe complications, including DIC,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DIC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "remains. Therefore, careful patient selection and thorough informed consent are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). JGH Open published by Journal of Gastroenterology and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Journal of Gastroenterology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hepatology Foundation and John Wiley & Sons Australia, Ltd.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hepatology Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "John Wiley & Sons Australia, Ltd.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eCollection 2025 Jul.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eCollection",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025 Jul.",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gastrografin Enema to the Rescue of the Glorious Cecal Bascule.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastrografin Enema",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Glorious Cecal Bascule",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Internal Medicine, HCA Healthcare Houston Kingwood, Kingwood,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Houston Kingwood",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kingwood",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Gastroenterology, HCA Healthcare Houston Kingwood, Kingwood,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastroenterology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Houston Kingwood",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kingwood",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A 74-year-old woman with a history of gastroesophageal reflux disease, hiatal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "74-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "hernia, Barrett's esophagus, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, and chronic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "hernia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Barrett",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "constipation was hospitalized for community-acquired pneumonia. During her",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hospitalization, she developed progressive lower abdominal discomfort and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reported no bowel movement for 8 days. Conservative measures, including oral",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "laxatives, enemas, and manual disimpaction, were unsuccessful, prompting",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "enemas",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gastroenterology consultation. Imaging revealed colonic pseudo-obstruction with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a markedly dilated cecum, suggestive of a type III cecal bascule-a rare upward",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "folding of the cecum without torsion. Owing to her clinical stability, absence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of peritoneal signs, and lack of ischemia on imaging, a nonsurgical approach was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pursued. The patient was treated with a Gastrografin enema, resulting in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastrografin",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immediate decompression and clinical improvement. This case contributes to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "emerging literature supporting conservative management of cecal bascule in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "select patients and emphasizes the importance of careful patient selection.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "American College of Gastroenterology.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "American College of Gastroenterology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Association of follow-up neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio with postoperative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pneumonia in aneurysmal subarachnoid hemorrhage patients after endovascular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment: a retrospective analysis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Neurosurgery, The Second Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurosurgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fujian Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Quanzhou, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Quanzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Neurology, The Second Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurology",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fujian Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Division of Public Management, The Second Affiliated Hospital, Fujian Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Management",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fujian Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Division of Neurosurgery, Jinjiang Municipal Hospital (Shanghai Sixth",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Neurosurgery, Jinjiang Municipal Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanghai",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sixth",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "People's Hospital Fujian Campus), Quanzhou, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "People's Hospital Fujian Campus",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Quanzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: Research on the relationship between dynamic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR)-measured at different time points around",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR)-measured",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "endovascular treatment-and the occurrence of postoperative pneumonia (POP) in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "scarce. This study aims to explore the association between dynamic NLR and the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "incidence of POP in patients with aSAH undergoing endovascular therapy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This study included patients with aSAH who underwent endovascular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment between January 2019 and April 2023. The follow-up endpoint was the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "January 2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "April 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "presence of POP at 30 days postoperatively. Logistic regression analysis was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "30 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "conducted using POP as the dependent variable. The NLR was calculated at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "admission (NLR1), 24 h after endovascular treatment (NLR2), and 3-7 days after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "24",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3-7 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "endovascular treatment (NLR3). Four prediction models were constructed: Model 1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR3",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Model 1\n",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(variables with p < 0.05, except for the NLR), Model 2 (Model 1 plus NLR1),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Model 2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Among the 154 patients with aSAH, POP occurred in 101 (65.6%) patients.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "154",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "POP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "101",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "65.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
