[
  {
    "text": "School-informed risk calculator tool for reducing the spread of respiratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viral infection among school-aged children.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Wilson AM(1), Lowe AA(2)(3), Amoh-Asante NAA(1), Zhan Y(1), Ashraf A(1), Gerald",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Wilson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lowe AA(2)(3",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amoh-Asante NAA(1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhan",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gerald\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Community, Environment & Policy, Mel and Enid Zuckerman College",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community, Environment & Policy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Enid Zuckerman College",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Public Health, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Arizona",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tucson",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AZ",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Nursing & Health Sciences Division, College of Nursing, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Nursing & Health Sciences Division",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Asthma & Airway Disease Research Center, Tucson, AZ, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Asthma & Airway Disease Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tucson",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AZ",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Office of Population Health Sciences, Office of the Vice Chancellor for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Population Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School health staff need decision support for responding to respiratory viral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outbreaks. Quantitative microbial risk assessment (QMRA) tools are an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inexpensive and fast resource. Our objectives were to engage school districts to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inform the development of a risk-based calculator tool, test the tool across",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hypothetical cases, and elicit feedback among school health staff. We",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "administered an online survey for Kindergarten (K) - Grade 5 teachers, school",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kindergarten",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "health professionals, and other school staff to gather data about respiratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viral disease interventions and model parameters. A risk calculator tool was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "developed in which users choose hypothetical scenarios to estimate infection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "risk per individual and compare interventions. Three case studies (CS) were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "explored: CS1 - Rhinovirus transmission in a general education classroom with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "\"poor\" vs. \"great\" air quality, CS2 - Influenza A virus transmission in a music",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "classroom with vs. without a portable air purifier, CS3 - SARS-CoV-2",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transmission in a special education classroom with vs. without open",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "doors/windows. The prototype tool was presented at a national school nursing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "meeting, and attendees were surveyed on (dis)likes and anticipated tool uses.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "dis)likes",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "For the initial survey of Arizona school personnel (n = 132), the top",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Arizona",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "132",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory viral outbreak strategies reported by teachers were hand (94 %) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "94 %",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "surface hygiene (85.1 %). For all case studies, infection risks were above",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "85.1 %",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thresholds used in other contexts but were comparable to published student",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory illness incidence data. At the national meeting, school nurses (n =",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "12) identified potential uses including advocating for interventions to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "administrators. This work reflects a unique application of community partnership",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and QMRA to address school health decision support.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "gestational age prediction and acceleration.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Eapen AA, Loveless IM, Pan M, Liang X, Urquhart A, Straughen J, Cassidy-Bushrow",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Loveless IM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pan M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liang X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Straughen J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cassidy-Bushrow",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AE, Sitarik AR, Simmerman N, Thompson EE, Kottyan L, Ober C, Johnson CC, Zoratti",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sitarik AR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Simmerman N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thompson EE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kottyan L",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johnson CC",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zoratti",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "E, Levin AM.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Levin AM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DNA methylation (DNAm), capturing biological gestational age (GA) and epigenetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "gestational age acceleration (EGAA), can be modified by environmental exposures.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The Asthma&Allergy array is a new DNAm array developed with content focused on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "asthma and allergy loci. The association between content on the Asthma&Allergy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "array and chronological GA and EGAA has not been evaluated alone or in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EGAA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "context of perinatal exposures. We performed an epigenome wide association",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "study(EWAS) based on chronological GA at single CpG sites and regions. We",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CpG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "further constructed a multi-CpG site methylation model to predict chronological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "GA in cord blood from 391 newborn children from a Detroit-based birth cohort.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "391",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Detroit",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Associations between perinatal environmental factors with GA, epigenetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gestational age (EGA), and EGAA were assessed. We identified 2,435 CpG sites",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EGA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2,435",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CpG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with chronological GA. HLA class II ( HLA-DRB1,HLA-DQB1,HLA-DRB6 )",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were the most significantly associated with chronological GA. Our multi-CpG site",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "model attained predictive accuracy (cross-validated Pearson's correlation=0.75)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pearson",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "comparable to other EGA methods. Using genes implicated in region-based analyses",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EGA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(n=395 regions), the pathways most significantly enriched with chronological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "GA-associated CpGs included T helper 1(Th1) and 2(Th2) activation, macrophage",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CpGs",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2(Th2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "classical activation, and IL10 signaling, which were also enriched in at least",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "one of the other published epigenetic clocks. In multi-exposure models, prenatal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "indoor pet exposure and unplanned C-section were associated with EGA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EGA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "deceleration, while infant's first-born status was associated with EGAA. Our",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings highlight enrichment for T cell modulated pathways and antigen",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "presentation as biological processes enriched in chronological GA, as well as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "novel perinatal factors that may impact EGAA.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "3. J Transl Med. 2025 Jul 15;23(1):796. doi: 10.1186/s12967-025-06646-5.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15;23(1):796",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Meta-analysis of microarray data to identify potential signature genes and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "MiRNAs associated with the pathogenesis of asthma.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Student Research Committee, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Medical Biotechnology, School of Advanced Medical Sciences and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Biotechnology, School of Advanced Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Technologies, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Epilepsy Research Center, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Research and Technology, Kermanshah University of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kermanshah University of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Kermanshah, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kermanshah",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Medical Biotechnology, School of Advanced Medical Sciences and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Biotechnology, School of Advanced Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Infertility Research Center, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Center",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Pharmaceutical Sciences Research Center, Shiraz University of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sciences Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. manica.negahdaripour@gmail.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Department of Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, School of Pharmacy, Shiraz",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Biotechnology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "School of Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. manica.negahdaripour@gmail.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(9)Department of Artificial Intelligence, School of Medicine, Shiraz University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Artificial Intelligence, School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. manica.negahdaripour@gmail.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiraz",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interests: None declared.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Burden level and quality of life of caregivers of hemodialysis patient's in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "central India: a mixed-method cross-sectional study.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)School of Public Health (at time of study), All India Institute of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)School of Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "All India Institute of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chhattisgarh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Vedanta Medical Research Foundation (BALCO Medical Centre), Raipur,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Vedanta Medical Research Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BALCO Medical Centre",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Nephrology, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Raipur,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nephrology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "All India Institute of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Nephrology, Dau Kalyan Singh Post Graduate Institute and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nephrology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dau Kalyan Singh Post Graduate Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research center, Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chhattisgarh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Community & Family Medicine, All India Institute of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community & Family Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "All India Institute of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India. abhiruchigalhotra@aiimsraipur.edu.in.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chhattisgarh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PURPOSE: Caregivers of hemodialysis patients are at high risk of developing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced quality of life (QoL) and increased caregiver burden.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "QoL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AIM: This study aims to explore the level of caregiver burden and quality of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "life in caregivers of hemodialysis patients in central India.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This cross-sectional mixed-method study was undertaken among caregivers",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of stable hemodialysis patients attending a tertiary care hospital in central",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "tertiary",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "India. The Zarit Burden Interview (ZBI) and WHOQoL BREF questionnaire measured",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Zarit Burden Interview",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BREF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "caregiver burden and QoL. The qualitative data was gathered through in-depth",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interviews using a semi-structured open-ended questionnaire that delved into",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "their personal experiences with caregiving. The transcripts of these interviews",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were analysed using applied thematic analysis, allowing for the identification",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and exploration of recurring themes and patterns within the data.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: A total of 105 caregivers took part in this study, with a mean age of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "105",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "40.04 ± 12.96 years. 56 (53.3%) caregivers were female. Most (48.6%, n = 51)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40.04",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.96 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "56",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "53.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "48.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were spouses/partners. Ten caregivers (9.5%) had to change their occupations due",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ten",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "9.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "hypertension, asthma, and arthritis) themselves. The mean caregiver burden level",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(ZBI) was 18.55 ± 7.58. Most (59.0%) experienced mild to moderate burden, while",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ZBI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.55",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "59.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "28.6% reported a high burden. The WHOQoL BREF mean score of various domains of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "28.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "BREF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "physical health, psychological, social relationship and environmental was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "35.70 ± 12.14, 44.20 ± 13.28, 44.28 ± 15.10 and 40.07 ± 13.36 respectively. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "35.70",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "12.14",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "44.20",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "13.28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "44.28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15.10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "40.07",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "13.36",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thematic analysis revealed, difficulty in continuing education and employment,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "changing jobs, the need to travel long distances to reach dialysis facilities",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and hardship due to COVID-19 pandemic as recurring challenges among caregivers.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Caregivers of Hemodialysis patients had significant caregiver burden",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and poor QoL. Regular assessment and special attention are needed for these",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025. The Author(s).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665407 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665407",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Ethical approval and consent to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: This study was approved by the Institutional Ethical Committee with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Institutional Ethical Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "IEC Proposal No: AIIMSRPR/IEC/2021/1041 from the All India Institute of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the All India Institute of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India. All participants signed an informed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Raipur",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chhattisgarh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "written consent before participation and informed consent was obtained from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "parents and/or legal guardians of minor/illiterate study participants. The study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "was conducted under the principles of the Helsinki Declaration. Consent for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Helsinki Declaration",
        "label": "LAW"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "competing interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Utility of patient-reported outcomes for pulmonary symptoms and sleep",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disturbance and impairment in children with systemic juvenile idiopathic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "arthritis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Division of Rheumatology, TriHealth Hospital System, Cincinnati, OH, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TriHealth Hospital System",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cincinnati",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "OH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Division of Rheumatology, 3333 Burnet Ave, MLC 4010, Cincinnati, OH, 45208,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burnet Ave",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "4010",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cincinnati",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "OH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "45208",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Burnet Ave, MLC 4010, Cincinnati, OH, 45208, USA. Christopher.towe@cchmc.org.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4010",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cincinnati",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "OH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "45208",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Division of Rheumatology, 3333 Burnet Ave, MLC 4010, Cincinnati, OH, 45208,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burnet Ave",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "4010",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cincinnati",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "OH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "45208",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Patient-reported outcomes (PROs) are critical assessment tools for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical practice, observational studies, and interventional trials. While",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "families of children with systemic juvenile idiopathic arthritis (SJIA) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SJIA-associated lung disease (SJIA-LD) report significant limitations in their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "quality of life, existing PROs for juvenile idiopathic arthritis may not",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "properly measure the full impact of these disorders. Our objective was to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "utilize a newly developed lung symptom survey as well as existing, validated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "children with SJIA with and without LD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Participants were parents/guardians of SJIA patients ≤ 18 years and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "≤ 18 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Center (CCHMC) JIA Registry, and memberships in the Systemic JIA Foundation, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "JIA Registry",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Systemic JIA Foundation",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SJIA Facebook Group. Participants provided proxy-reports for their child using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA Facebook Group",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "several PRO questionnaires [CCHMC Lung Symptom Survey; PROMIS Asthma Impact,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PRO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lung Symptom Survey",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sleep Disturbance, Sleep Impairment Forms] and selected demographic and SJIA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "specific information.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: There were 139 responses, of which 40.3% (n = 57) reported some lung",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "139",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "40.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "57",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disease including 12.9% (n = 20) with interstitial lung disease (ILD), pulmonary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "20",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ILD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "alveolar proteinosis (PAP) and/or pulmonary artery hypertension (PAH). All SJIA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PAH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with any lung disease and those with ILD/PAP/PAH had significantly",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ILD/PAP/PAH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "higher total questionnaire scores than patients without lung disease on the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CCHMC Lung Symptoms Survey. Both the full survey and individual questions showed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CCHMC Lung Symptoms Survey",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "good ability to distinguish patients with ILD/PAP/PAH from those without (area",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ILD/PAP/PAH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "under the curve (AUC) > 0.7). The majority of patients reported some level of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.7",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "regardless of presence or absence of lung disease, including moderate to severe",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sleep impairment and/or disturbance in 48% of SJIA patients.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "48%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Children with SJIA and lung problems had higher scores on the CCHMC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CCHMC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Lung Symptom Survey; however, these measures did not discriminate between",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lung Symptom Survey",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SJIA-LD and other pulmonary conditions such as asthma. Based on PROMIS measures,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA-LD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PROMIS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a majority of children with SJIA had sleep disturbance and impairment,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SJIA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "regardless of steroid use or presence of lung disease.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665383 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: This study was reviewed and approved by the Cincinnati Children’s",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Cincinnati Children’s",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital Medical Center Institutional Review Board (2019 − 0888) with a waiver",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hospital Medical Center Institutional Review Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2019 −",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "0888",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of consent. Competing interests: Dr. Schulert has received consulting fees from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Schulert",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Novartis and Boehringer Ingelheim and research support from IpiNovyx. Dr. Grom",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boehringer Ingelheim",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IpiNovyx",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Grom\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "has received consulting fees from Novartis and SOBI. All author authors report",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Novartis",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SOBI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "no competing interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "6. J Med Case Rep. 2025 Jul 15;19(1):344. doi: 10.1186/s13256-025-05067-8.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "15;19(1):344",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A mixed immediate and delayed allergy to oral vitamin D supplementation: a case",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Ridge A(1)(2), Cooling N(3), Seidel B(4)(3).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ridge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)School of Pharmacy and Pharmacology, College of Health and Medicine,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)School of Pharmacy and Pharmacology, College of Health and Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Tasmania, Hobart, TAS, 7000, Australia. a.ridge@utas.edu.au.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Tasmania",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hobart",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "TAS",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "7000",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "a.ridge@utas.edu.au",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Ochre Health Research Network, c/- 85 Main Road, Huonville, TAS, 7109,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Ochre",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Health Research Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "85",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Main Road, Huonville",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "TAS",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "7109",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)School of Medicine, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hobart, TAS, 7000, Australia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hobart",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "TAS",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "7000",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Ochre Health Research Network, c/- 85 Main Road, Huonville, TAS, 7109,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Health Research Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "85",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Main Road, Huonville",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "TAS",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "7109",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Vitamin D deficiency is common worldwide and of particular concern",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vitamin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for populations at higher latitudes, including those in developed areas such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Australia. The role of vitamin D in modulating bone health and the immune system",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "is well recognized. Patients frequently have vitamin D deficiency identified and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "managed in the primary healthcare setting. Despite the high prevalence of use in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CASE PRESENTATION: The case presented here is a 53-year-old Caucasian female of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "53-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Caucasian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Northern European ancestry, with a history of asthma and irritable bowel",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Northern European ancestry",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "syndrome who was prescribed supplemental vitamin D. She experienced dyspepsia",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "D.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and stomach cramps within minutes of ingesting a vitamin D supplement. An",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "minutes",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "alternative formulation of vitamin D produced similar gastrointestinal effects,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "worsening asthma and a rash. The results of the investigations were unremarkable",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "except for mildly elevated total immunoglobulin levels. The patient was referred",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to an allergy clinic where a diagnosis of vitamin D hypersensitivity, with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "features of both immunoglobulin-E-mediated (type 1) and T-cell (type 4)-mediated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pathways, was made. A desensitization program was commenced using a modified",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Australian protocol. During the 18-week course, the patient was exposed to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Australian",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "18-week",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increasing doses of vitamin D, and after 6 months, a daily dose of 1000 IU was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1000",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "IU",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tolerated. She continues to use daily antihistamines and avoids foods rich in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: This case report highlights a rare likely allergic reaction to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "supplemental vitamin D. The patient was never known to have supratherapeutic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "D.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "levels of vitamin D, but her history of atopy may increase the likelihood of an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immune-mediated response to the supplement. While skin sensitivity testing was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "negative, a provocation test and the Naranjo scoring system indicated that a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Naranjo",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "\"probable\" allergy occurred. Vitamin D deficiency is easily detected in primary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vitamin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "healthcare, and oral supplementation is usually a safe and effective means to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "healthcare",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "restore blood levels. While reactions to vitamin D supplementation in normal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "doses are rare, an allergic cause should be considered when there are no other",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "likely precipitants. Personalized, carefully supervised, desensitization to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "vitamin D may enable the resumption of supplementation and help prevent",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unnecessary morbidity and mortality from vitamin D deficiency.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665361 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: An exemption from ethical review was granted by the University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tasmania Human Research Ethics Committee (Project ID: 30944). Consent for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tasmania Human Research Ethics Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "30944",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "publication of this case report and any accompanying images. A copy of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "written consent is available for review by the Editor-in-Chief of this journal.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Competing interests: The authors declare that there are no conflicts of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Association between neighborhood deprivation and type 2 diabetes risks among",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)School of Public Health, Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)School of Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ningxia Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yinchuan",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Key Laboratory of Environmental Factors and Chronic Disease Control, Ningxia",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Key Laboratory of Environmental Factors",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ningxia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical University, Yinchuan, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yinchuan",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Center for Primary Health Care Research, Department of Clinical Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Primary Health Care Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Clinical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)University Clinic Primary Care, Skåne University Hospital, Region Skåne,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinic Primary Care",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Skåne University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Skåne",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Departments of Family and Community Medicine and of Epidemiology, The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Family and Community Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Epidemiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Center for Community-based Healthcare Research and Education (CoHRE),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6)Center",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Community",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Healthcare Research and Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Department of Functional Pathology, School of Medicine, Matsue, Shimane",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Department of Functional Pathology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Matsue",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shimane\n",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Matsue, Japan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Matsue",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Japan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Center for Primary Health Care Research, Department of Clinical Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Primary Health Care Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Clinical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)University Clinic Primary Care, Skåne University Hospital, Region Skåne,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8)University Clinic Primary Care",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Skåne University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Skåne",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "This study aimed to investigate the potential impact of neighborhood deprivation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "on the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) among individuals with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "asthma. This nationwide, open cohort study conducted in Sweden from 1997 to 2018",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sweden",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1997",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "included asthma patients of all ages (n = 1,051,240) to assess their subsequent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1,051,240",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "risk of developing T2DM. The study compared asthma patients residing in highly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "deprived neighborhoods with those living in moderately or less deprived areas",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analyze the association between neighborhood deprivation and T2DM incidence,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with results expressed as hazard ratios (HRs) and 95% confidence intervals (95%",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CIs). Analyses were stratified by sex and adjusted for potential confounders. A",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CIs",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant association between neighborhood deprivation and T2DM risk in asthma",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients was shown. These associations remained statistically significant after",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "adjusting for confounders, with adjusted HRs of 1.44 (95% CI 1.38-1.50) for men",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.44",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.38-1.50",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and 1.51 (95% CI 1.46-1.57) for women. Furthermore, a graded relationship was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.46-1.57",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "observed, with higher levels of neighborhood deprivation associated with an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "increased incidence of T2DM among asthma patients. These findings underscore",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "critical clinical and public health concerns. The results of this study provide",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "valuable insights for policymakers, highlighting the need to consider",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neighborhood deprivation when allocating resources in primary healthcare",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "settings. They also offer guidance for optimizing clinical care strategies for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.1038/s41598-025-09150-4",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665105 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Competing interests: The authors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "declare no competing interests. Ethics approval: This study was approved by the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "regional ethical review board in Lund, Sweden on Feb. 6th, 2013 (registration No",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lund",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sweden",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Feb. 6th, 2013",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2012/795) and later amendments. Guidelines of the Helsinki Declaration were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2012/795",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Helsinki Declaration",
        "label": "LAW"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "followed. Data were obtained from the national registers collected by various",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Swedish health and social agencies. The agency Statistics Sweden linked the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Swedish",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Statistics Sweden",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(pseudonymised) unique personal identification number assigned to all Swedish",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Swedish",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "residents at birth or migration. Informed consent: Informed consent was not",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "applicable, as the study was based on secondary pseudonymized data from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "8. Nat Med. 2025 Jul 15. doi: 10.1038/s41591-025-03790-9. Online ahead of print.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nat Med",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Deep phenotyping of health-disease continuum in the Human Phenotype Project.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Human Phenotype Project",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Y(12), Stossel C(12), Raitses-Gurevich M(12), Golan T(4)(12), Dhir R(13),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Stossel C(12",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Raitses-Gurevich M(12",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golan T(4)(12",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, Weizmann Institute of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Computer Science",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Science, Rehovot, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rehovot",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Molecular Cell Biology, Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovot,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Molecular Cell Biology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Lis Maternity and Women's Hospital, Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv Sourasky Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4)Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)The Jesse Z and Sara Lea Shafer Institute for Endocrinology and Diabetes,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jesse Z",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sara Lea Shafer Institute for Endocrinology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "National Center for Childhood Diabetes, Schneider Children's Medical Center of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "National Center for Childhood Diabetes",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Internal Medicine A, Shamir Medical Center (Assaf Harofeh),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine A",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shamir Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Assaf Harofeh",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Department of Cardiology, Rabin Medical Center, Petah-Tikva, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cardiology",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rabin Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Cancer Research Center, Sheba Medical Center, Ramat-Gan, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sheba Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ramat-Gan",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(9)Institute of Breast Oncology, the Jusidman Cancer Center, Sheba Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Breast Oncology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Jusidman Cancer Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sheba Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(10)The Department of Gastroenterology and Liver Disease, Tel Aviv Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10)The Department of Gastroenterology and Liver Disease",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Center, affiliated to the Grey Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Tel Aviv",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Grey Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Tel Aviv, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(11)Department of Internal Medicine, SBS Shizuoka Health Promotion Center,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "11)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SBS Shizuoka Health Promotion Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(12)The Jusidman Cancer Center, Sheba Medical Center, Tel Hashomer, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jusidman Cancer Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sheba Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Hashomer",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(13)Swiss Institute of Allergy and Asthma Research (SIAF), University of Zurich,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13)Swiss Institute of Allergy and Asthma Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Zurich",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(18)Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "18)Carnegie",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mellon University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pittsburgh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pittsburgh",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "PA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(19)Department of Computer Science and Applied Mathematics, Weizmann Institute",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of Science, Rehovot, Israel. eran.segal@weizmann.ac.il.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Science, Rehovot",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The Human Phenotype Project (HPP) is a large-scale deep-phenotype prospective",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Human Phenotype Project",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "HPP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cohort. To date, approximately 28,000 participants have enrolled, with more than",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "approximately 28,000",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "13,000 completing their initial visit. The project is aimed at identifying novel",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13,000",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular signatures with diagnostic, prognostic and therapeutic value, and at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "developing artificial intelligence (AI)-based predictive models for disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "onset and progression. The HPP includes longitudinal profiling encompassing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HPP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "medical history, lifestyle and nutrition, anthropometrics, blood tests,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immune profiling. Analysis of these data highlights the variation of phenotypes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with age and ethnicity and unravels molecular signatures of disease by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "comparison with matched healthy controls. Leveraging extensive dietary and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lifestyle data, we identify associations between lifestyle factors and health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "lifestyle data",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes. Finally, we present a multi-modal foundation AI model, trained using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "self-supervised learning on diet and continuous-glucose-monitoring data, that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outperforms existing methods in predicting disease onset. This framework can be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "extended to integrate other modalities and act as a personalized digital twin.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "In summary, we present a deeply phenotyped cohort that serves as a platform for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "advancing biomarker discovery, enabling the development of multi-modal AI models",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and personalized medicine approaches.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature America, Inc.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Springer Nature America, Inc.",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.1038/s41591-025-03790-9",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Competing interests: Y.R., H.R. and Y.T.B are",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Y.R.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "H.R.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Y.T.B",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "employees at Pheno.AI. A.K., A.W. and E.S. are paid consultants of Pheno.AI.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pheno",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "A.K.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "A.W.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "E.S.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pheno",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "N.M. has received speaking and consulting fees from Pfizer, Abbvie, Lilly,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "N.M.",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pfizer, Abbvie, Lilly",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Takeda, Janssen, Ferring, BiomX, BMS, Nestle and Teva and grant support from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ferring",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nestle",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Teva",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the Helmsely Charitable Trust. The other authors declare no competing interests.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Helmsely Charitable Trust",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Mental health risks in children with food allergies: a population-based",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "comparison of food allergies with other chronic conditions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Flaks-Manov N(#)(1), Goldshtein I(#)(1), Yanover C(1), Lachover-Roth I(2)(3).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Flaks-Manov",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Goldshtein",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yanover",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)KI Research Institute, Kfar Malal, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)KI Research Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kfar Malal",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Allergy and Clinical Immunology Unit, Meir Medical Center, Kfar Saba, Israel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Immunology Unit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Meir Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kfar Saba",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)School of Medicine, Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences, Tel Aviv",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine, Faculty of Medical and Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Tel Aviv, Israel. idit.lachover@gmail.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tel Aviv",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Israel",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Children with chronic diseases face a higher risk of mental health disorders.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "However, the cognitive consequences of food allergies (FA), which are not",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "classified as a chronic disease, remain insufficiently researched. The objective",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of this study is to examine the association between FA and mental health in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "children and adolescents, compared to children and adolescents without FA",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(controls) and those with other chronic conditions but no history of FA. This is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a retrospective cohort study using IQVIA Medical Research Data from UK primary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IQVIA Medical Research Data",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "UK",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "care practices. Five cohorts of children aged 0-18 between 2000 and 2021 were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0-18 between 2000",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2021",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "defined: FA, control, asthma, atopic dermatitis (AD), and type 1 diabetes (T1D).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The study included 1,130,721 children without FA (control), 23,263 with FA,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1,130,721",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "23,263",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "136,453 with asthma, 207,575 with AD, and 4835 with T1D. Compared to control, FA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "136,453",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "207,575",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "4835",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "T1D.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients had higher risks of eating disorders (hazard ratio (HR) 1.85, 95% CI",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.85",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1.42-2.41), anxiety (HR 1.35, 95% CI 1.25-1.45), and depression (HR 1.24, 95% CI",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.42",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.35",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.25-1.45",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.24",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1.11-1.39). FA patients had lower depression risk than asthma and T1D patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.11-1.39",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(HR 0.77, 95% CI 0.68-0.87, 0.64, 95% CI 0.54-0.76, respectively) and lower",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.77",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.68-0.87",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.64",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.54-0.76",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "anxiety risk than asthma patients (HR 0.86, 95% CI 0.79-0.91). FA patients' risk",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.86",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.79-0.91",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of eating disorders was not significantly different from asthma and T1D patients",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(HR 1.17, 95% CI 0.88-1.55, 1.58, 95% CI 0.81-3.10, respectively) but was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.17",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.88-1.55",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.81-3.10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly higher than in the AD group (HR 1.43, 95% CI 1.07-1.90).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.43",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.07-1.90",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: This study indicates that children with FA face elevated risks of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "anxiety, depression, and eating disorders compared to children without FA, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that these risks vary when compared to children with other chronic conditions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "These findings highlight the need for integrated mental health support in FA",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "management and greater awareness of FA's psychological impact among healthcare",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "WHAT IS KNOWN: • Children with chronic illnesses such as asthma and diabetes are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "known to have an elevated risk of mental health disorders. However, research on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the mental health impact of food allergies remains limited.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "WHAT IS NEW: • This study reveals that children with FA have significantly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "increased risks of anxiety, depression, and eating disorders compared to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "children without FA and provides comparative insights into the mental health",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "risks of FA relative to other chronic conditions like asthma, atopic dermatitis,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "type 1 diabetes, and healthy controls.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Springer-Verlag GmbH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "part of Springer Nature.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Springer Nature",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40664887 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40664887",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Ethical approval: This study was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "performed in line with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Approval",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Declaration of Helsinki",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was granted by the Ethics Committee of IQVIA Scientific Review Committee (SRC",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Ethics Committee of IQVIA Scientific Review Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Reference Number: 23SRC014). Competing interest: The authors declare no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "23SRC014",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conducting the National Health and Morbidity Survey 2023 in Malaysia with focus",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the National Health and Morbidity Survey 2023",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Malaysia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "on methodology and main findings on non-communicable diseases.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Mat Rifin H(1), Mohd Yusoff MF(2), Abd Hamid HA(2).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mohd Yusoff MF(2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Abd Hamid HA(2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Institute for Public Health, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "National Institutes of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Institute for Public Health, National Institutes of Health, Ministry of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "National Institutes of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The National Health and Morbidity Survey (NHMS), which focuses on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The National Health and Morbidity Survey (NHMS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "non-communicable diseases (NCDs), their risk factors and healthcare demand, is a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cross-sectional, nationwide, population-based survey conducted every four-year",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "four-year",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cycle since 2011. NHMS 2023 was the 7th cycle of NCDs, their risk factors and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2011",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NHMS 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "7th",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "healthcare demand, which aimed to monitor trends in diseases and healthcare",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "healthcare",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "utilisation. This article outlines the methodology, sociodemographic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characteristics, and overall findings from the population surveyed in 2023",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "regarding NCDs, their risk factors, and various health-related topics. This",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "survey utilised a two-stage stratified random sampling design and encompassed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fifteen main scopes, with sample sizes calculated to meet the specific",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fifteen",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "requirements of each scope. Conducted from July to September 2023, it involved",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "July to September 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the random selection of 499 enumeration blocks(EBs) by the Department of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "499",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Department of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Statistics Malaysia (DOSM) across all states and federal territories in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DOSM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Malaysia. The step resulted in the selection of 5,988 living quarters (LQs).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malaysia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "5,988",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Data collection methods included validated questionnaires administered through",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "face-to-face interviews and self-administered questionnaires, alongside clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assessments and blood investigations using calibrated devices. To ensure the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "high quality of the collected data, we implemented stringent quality control",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "measures. Furthermore, we applied complex sampling analyses to ensure that the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "findings accurately represented the population in Malaysia. The survey received",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malaysia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "responses from 13,616 individuals out of the 5,006 LQs that were successfully",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13,616",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5,006",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "visited, resulting in an overall response rate of the survey of 83.2%, which",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "83.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "includes individuals aged 5 years and above. A substantial segment of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "population lived in urban regions, comprising 77.6% of the total. About half of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "77.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "About half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the population consisted of males (51.9%), Malay (54.6%), and individuals who",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Malay",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "54.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "had attained secondary education (54.2%). Additionally, 20.0% of the population",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "54.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "20.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were within the age range of 30 to 39 years. The weighted prevalence of diabetes",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30 to 39 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was 15.6%, hypertension 29.2%, hypercholesterolaemia 33.3%, overweight and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "29.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "33.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "obesity 54.4%. Depression among adults was 4.6%, while mental health problems",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "54.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "4.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "among children were reported at 16.5%. The current tobacco smokers prevalence",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was 19.0%, and 29.9% of adults in Malaysia were physically inactive. The known",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "19.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "29.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Malaysia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "asthma prevalence among adults was 6.2%, while the current asthma among children",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was 3.4%. Additionally, 37.7% of adults experienced sleep insufficiency. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "37.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "results indicate that the higher proportion of diabetes, hypertension, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hypercholesterolaemia, particularly among the young age group, and the high",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prevalence of overweight and obesity, as well as mental health problems, are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "making the healthcare system deal with more non-communicable diseases,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications, and problems. The methodology of this survey is robust for a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "population-based study. We took comprehensive steps to ensure the validity and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reliability of the findings. The findings indicate an urgent need for targeted",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "public health interventions to address the escalating health issues. By focusing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "on prevention and early intervention strategies, we can mitigate the impact of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "NCDs on the healthcare system and improve overall population health.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.1038/s41598-025-08311-9",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40664716 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: All respondents provided written informed consent prior to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interviews. The survey protocol was approved by the Medical Research and Ethics",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Medical Research and Ethics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Committee (MREC), Ministry of Health Malaysia (22-00545-XAC (2)). All methods",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ministry of Health Malaysia",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "22-00545-XAC",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "adhered to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and the Malaysian Good",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Declaration of Helsinki",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "Malaysian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Clinical Practice Guidelines. Competing interests: The authors declare no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Practice Guidelines",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Disinfection of medical devices with a steam machine that operates at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "atmospheric pressure and is suitable for home usage.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Medical Microbiology, University of Groningen, University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Microbiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Groningen",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Medical Microbiology, University of Groningen, University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Microbiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Groningen",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical devices that come in direct contact with human skin or the oral cavity",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "will inevitably be contaminated with microorganisms, including potential",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pathogens. Ensuring the microbiological safety of such devices is therefore",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "crucial to prevent infections. Healthcare institutions usually have the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Healthcare",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "facilities needed for effective sterilization of reusable medical devices.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "However, effective sterilization or disinfection of medical devices for usage at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "home has remained challenging both in terms of pathogen elimination and user",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "safety. Preferably, this involves easy-to-operate equipment that works at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "relatively low temperatures and atmospheric pressure. In principle this need can",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "be met by disinfection with steam. Therefore, the objective of the present study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "was to examine the efficacy of a simple electronic steam machine designed for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "home usage. Our results show that exposure to steam at 100 °C for 60 s resulted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "100",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "60",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in complete eradication (100% reduction) of bacterial contaminants, including",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "100%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA). Significant bacterial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "methicillin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Staphylococcus aureus",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reductions (ranging from ~ 90-100%) were also observed within shorter exposure",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90-100%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "times (10-30 s), depending on the strain. Importantly, the applied steam",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10-30",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disinfection approach is effective even against biofilm-embedded bacteria, or",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "bacteria applied to a medical device for home usage, as exemplified with a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "nebulizer that is used by patients with asthma or chronic obstructive pulmonary",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disease (COPD). In conclusion, our results provide quantitative proof-of-concept",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evidence that portable steam-generating devices that operate at atmospheric",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pressure can be used for effective disinfection of reusable medical devices in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.1038/s41598-025-11509-6",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40664706 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40664706",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Screening tools for work-related asthma and their diagnostic accuracy: a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "systematic review.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Applied Health Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Applied Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Birmingham",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Birmingham",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Community Medicine and Family Medicine, Thammasat University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Family Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thammasat University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Faculty of Medicine, Khlong Nueng, Pathum Thani, Thailand.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Khlong Nueng",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pathum Thani",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thailand",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Occupational and Interstitial Lung Disease Services, University Hospitals",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Interstitial Lung Disease Services",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University Hospitals",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust, Birmingham, UK.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Birmingham NHS Foundation Trust",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Birmingham",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "UK",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Khon Kaen University, Nai",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Epidemiology and Biostatistics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Applied Health Sciences, University of Birmingham, Birmingham,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Applied Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Birmingham",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Birmingham",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: One in four cases of asthma in adults is caused or worsened by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "One",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "work (work-related asthma: WRA). Early detection of WRA could prevent poor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WRA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "health and employment outcomes, but clinical diagnosis is often missed or",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "delayed. The standardisation and effectiveness of screening tools have not been",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "well established. We aimed to summarise and compare the performance of screening",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tools for identifying WRA in both clinical settings and workplaces.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WRA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We searched for studies that used structured questionnaires or",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prediction models (with/without physiological tests) to identify WRA in clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "settings or workplaces with individuals aged≥16 years in MEDLINE, Embase, other",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MEDLINE",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Embase",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "bibliographic databases and grey literature between 1975 and 2024. Two reviewers",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "between 1975 and 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "independently screened titles, abstracts and full texts for inclusion, extracted",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "data and assessed risk of bias using QUADAS-2 tool (Quality Assessment of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "QUADAS-2 tool (Quality Assessment of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
