[
  {
    "text": "polymerases and PfRad51 in genome diversification.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Vishwanatha A, Zhang X, Liu YJ, Leung A, Herring M, Chan A, Calhoun S, Deitsch",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vishwanatha A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhang X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liu YJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Leung A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chan A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Calhoun S",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Deitsch\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The haploid malaria parasite, Plasmodium falciparum, evolved a unique cohort of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DNA repair pathways enabling the parasite to survive in a vertebrate host red",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "blood cell and the mosquito vector. P. falciparum chromosomes are partitioned",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mosquito",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "into a highly conserved core genome and remarkably diverse, largely subtelomeric",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "regions that contain genes encoding important parasite virulence factors. The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular mechanisms that maintain this chromosomal structure have not been",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "identified. Here, we describe specific DNA repair pathways that differentiate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between hypervariable subtelomeric and conserved core regions of the genome.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Based on our previous work, we hypothesized that there are potentially important",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interactions between translesion (TLS) and homologous recombination (HR)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TLS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pathways for the diversification of multicopy gene families in P. falciparum.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Thus, we created knockout parasite lines of the DNA repair enzymes: PfRad51 and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the TLS polymerases PfPol ζ and PfRev1 . We identified that irradiation",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TLS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PfPol ζ and PfRev1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "hypersensitivity varied across the cell cycle for TLSΔ parasites and was uniform",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TLSΔ",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "across the erythrocytic cycle for PfRad51 Δ parasites, highlighting the variable",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PfRad51 Δ",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "roles of these pathways. However, important interactions between these pathways",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were found when we studied directed double strand break (DSB) repair, which",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DSB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed a difference in the DNA damage response according to chromosomal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "location. PfRad51 was essential for HR-mediated repair in the core genome. In",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "contrast, we identified a Rad51 independent homology-directed repair in all",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "three of our knockout lines when a DSB was made in the subtelomeric region of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "DSB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the chromosome. We propose that this differential DNA damage response maintains",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the distinction in diversification across the chromosome.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Glycosylation of Plasmodium falciparum TRAP is essential for infection of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TRAP",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mosquito salivary glands.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Vigdorovich V, Camargo N, Knutson E, Sather DN, Vaughan AM, Swearingen KE.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vigdorovich V",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Camargo N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Knutson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sather",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Swearingen KE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thrombospondin type 1 repeat (TSR) domain-bearing proteins at different stages",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "throughout its life cycle. TSRs can be modified by two types of glycosylation:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "O-fucosylation at conserved serine (S) or threonine (T) residues and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "C-mannosylation at conserved tryptophan (W) residues. Pf TRAP, which is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "expressed in mosquito-stage sporozoites, has one TSR domain that is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "O-fucosylated at Thr 256 and C-mannosylated at Trp 250 . We employed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Thr 256",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "250",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "site-directed mutagenesis by CRISPR/Cas9 gene editing to generate two Pf TRAP",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR/Cas9",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "glyco-null mutant parasites, Pf TRAP_T256A and Pf TRAP_W250F. The fitness of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pf TRAP_W250F. The",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "these mutant parasites across the life cycle was compared to the parental NF54",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "wild type as well as a Pf TRAP knockout line. The glyco-null parasites exhibited",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "major fitness defects comparable to knockout: sporozoites were unable to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "productively colonize the salivary glands and were highly impaired in gliding",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "motility and the ability to invade cultured human hepatocytes. Protein analysis",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed significantly reduced Pf TRAP abundance in the glyco-null mutants",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "despite normal transcript levels. These findings demonstrate that glycosylation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of Pf TRAP's TSR is critical for its proper expression and function, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TSR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "underscores the importance of TSR glycosylation in the mosquito stage of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TSR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "On the use of generative models for evolutionary inference of malaria vectors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Malaria in sub-Saharan Africa is transmitted by mosquitoes, in particular the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malaria",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Anopheles gambiae complex. Efforts to control the spread of malaria have often",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between populations and species in the Anopheles complex. Here, we first",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "quantify the genetic structure of mosquito populations in sub-Saharan Africa",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "using unsupervised machine learning. We then adapt and apply an innovative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "generative deep learning algorithm to infer the joint evolutionary history of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "populations sampled in Guinea and Burkina Faso, West Africa. We further develop",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Guinea",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Burkina Faso",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "West Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a novel model selection approach and discover that an evolutionary model with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "migration fits this pair of populations better than a model without post-split",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "migration. For the migration model, we find that our method outperforms earlier",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "work based on summary statistics, especially in capturing population genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "differentiation. These findings demonstrate that machine learning and generative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "models are a valuable direction for future understanding of the evolution of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malaria vectors, including the joint inference of demography and natural",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "selection. Understanding changes in population size, migration patterns, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "adaptation in hosts, vectors, and pathogens will assist malaria control",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interventions, with the ultimate goal of predicting nuanced outcomes from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "OocystMeter, a machine-learning algorithm to count and measure Plasmodium",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "OocystMeter",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "oocysts, reveals clustering patterns in the Anopheles midgut.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Anopheles",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "N, Shaw WR, Catteruccia F.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Shaw WR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Catteruccia F.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "We present OocystMeter, a machine learning-based software developed to automate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "OocystMeter",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the segmentation of malaria oocysts from images of mosquito midguts stained with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mercurochrome. Existing bioimage analysis tools, including machine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "learning-based ones, often struggle with the unique staining patterns, complex",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "midgut backgrounds, and variable morphology of oocysts, making the determination",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of oocyst size and numbers cumbersome. To overcome these challenges, we curated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a high-quality dataset comprised of 11,178 Plasmodium falciparum oocysts in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "11,178",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Anopheles gambiae midguts annotated by expert parasitologists. Using this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dataset, we fine-tuned a Mask R-CNN object detection model to achieve",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNN",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "segmentation accuracy comparable to human parasitologists (Spearman's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Spearman",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correlation of 0.998 for oocyst counts and 0.978 for size measurements).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.998",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.978",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Applying this tool in conjunction with spatial analysis, we uncovered a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "non-random, clustered spatial distribution of oocysts independent of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "midgut's anatomical regions or geometric axes, particularly in infections with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "midgut",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fewer than 75 oocysts/midgut. Our workflow significantly accelerates malaria",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fewer than 75",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "oocyst intensity and size analysis, reduces human bias, and provides spatial",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "coordinates for advanced parasitology studies. OocystMeter is freely available",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "OocystMeter",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "at https://github.com/duopeng/OocystMeter, and as a web tool at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "https://github.com/duopeng/OocystMeter",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "http://Oocystmeter.org/, offering a valuable resource for researchers",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "investigating the oocyst stage of malaria development.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Signatures of selection and mechanisms of insecticide resistance in Ugandan",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ugandan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Anopheles funestus : Insights from embedding translational genomics into the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "LLINEUP cluster randomised trial.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "JI, Kayondo J, Clarkson C, Miles A, Lawniczak MKN, Lucas ER, Donnelly MJ.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "JI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kayondo J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Clarkson C",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Miles A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lawniczak MKN",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lucas ER",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Donnelly MJ",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "In response to the emerging threat of insecticide resistance in malaria vectors,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "insecticides are being repurposed for vector control or developed de novo . Good",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stewardship of these finite new resources is essential if disease control",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "programmes are to remain effective. This is dependent on timely data to help",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "guide evidence-based decision-making for National Malaria Control programmes",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "National Malaria Control",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NMCPs). By embedding genomics into cluster randomized control trials (cRCTs),",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "we can perform surveillance and early detection of insecticide resistance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "variants to new and repurposed chemicals in natural field conditions, supporting",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effective stewardship. The LLIN Evaluation Uganda Project (LLINEUP) trial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LLIN Evaluation Uganda Project",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluated the efficacy of pyrethroid-piperonyl butoxide (PBO) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PBO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pyrethroids-only long-lasting insecticidal nets (LLINs). It was conducted in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LLINs",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Uganda between 2017-2020 and was the largest cRCT to date, covering 40% of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2017-2020",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "40%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "country in 104 health sub-districts. We embedded genomic surveillance within",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "104",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "LLINEUP to detect and track insecticide resistance variants. At baseline and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "throughout the trial, we sampled Anopheles mosquitoes with Prokopack aspirators",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Prokopack",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and performed Illumina whole-genome sequencing. We show that An. funestus",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Illumina",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "populations were relatively unaffected by the interventions, compared to An.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "gambiae s.l., which were markedly reduced six months following LLIN deployment.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "gambiae s.l.",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "six months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Standard approaches for describing genetic diversity and population structure",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Standard",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "e.g. fixation index ( F ST ), Principal Component Analysis (PCA) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "F ST",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Principal Component Analysis",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Neighbour-Joining (NJ) trees, were consistent with the density observations and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "suggestive of a single large An. funestus population in Uganda with little",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genetic differentiation. Genome-wide selection scans revealed strong signals of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "selection at the Resistance to pyrethroid-1 (RP1 ) locus and Cyp9k1 , both loci",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cyp9k1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "previously implicated in pyrethroid resistance. We report two additional loci,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eye diacylglycerol kinase ( Dgk ) (≅13.5Mb on the X chromosome) and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "O-mannosyl-transferase ( TMC-like ) (≅67.9Mb on 3RL) that showed signals of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3RL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "selection. Known DDT and permethrin resistance-associated variants at the Gste2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gste2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "locus, L119F and L119V, were also identified. Over the trial period, changes in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "haplotype frequencies were observed in regions under selection, with more",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pronounced shifts in the PBO arm. Notably, there were significant reductions in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PBO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the frequencies of swept haplotypes (measured by delta (Δ) H12) in the Dgk and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dgk",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cyp6p9a regions, while significant increases in haplotype frequency were",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "observed at Gste2 and Cyp9k1 loci. Our findings reveal the differential impact",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gste2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cyp9k1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of the trial on An. gambiae s.l. and An. funestus densities and the differing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "s.l.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "responses of An. funestus populations to pyrethroid and pyrethroid-PBO selection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pressure. These insights underscore the potential value of tailored, species-",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and region-specific vector control strategies, supported by regional genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "surveillance, to better control insecticide resistance evolution and spread. By",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "embedding genomic surveillance in cRCTs we can facilitate the discovery of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "putative resistance variants and can provide evidence of their impact on vector",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "control tool efficacy; both of crucial importance to evidence-based deployment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of vector control tools by NMCPs.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NMCPs",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Spatially-explicit genomics of An. gambiae s.l uncovers fine-scale population",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "structure and mechanisms of insecticide resistance.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Nagi SC, Essandoh J, Ato-Egyir N, Lucas ER, Miles A, Desewu K, Williams I,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nagi SC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ato-Egyir N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lucas ER",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Miles A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Desewu K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Williams",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Progress in malaria control in sub-Saharan Africa is stalling, partly due to the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "spread of insecticide resistance in Anopheles vectors. Monitoring the evolution",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Anopheles",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of insecticide resistance alleles and their spatial heterogeneity is important",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for malaria control programmes, and genomic surveillance has emerged as a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pivotal tool for this purpose. Earlier genomics research has typically employed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "convenience-based sampling, and research has yet to be performed to optimise",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sampling regimens for malaria vector genomics. In an earlier study, we developed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "malaria vector genomics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a spatially explicit sampling framework that considers the underlying ecology to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "enable sampling mosquitoes with reduced bias. We applied this framework to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sample and perform whole-genome sequencing on 485 individual specimens of An.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "485",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "gambiae s.l mosquitoes from Obuasi, central Ghana, an area with extensive gold",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Obuasi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ghana",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mining activities. In this region, An. gambiae s.l have been documented as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "highly resistant to multiple insecticides, including pyrethroids used for the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment of bed-nets. High resolution of fine-scale population structure",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "enabled the detection of isolation-by-distance in An. coluzzii in Obuasi, whilst",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Obuasi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "finding that at this scale, geographic distance, rather than the underlying",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "kinship, demonstrating that polymorphic chromosomal inversions significantly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "confound established analytical tools, while revealing how the mosquito's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mosquito",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "chromosome architecture generates high variance in genetic relatedness among",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "kin. Using genome-wide selection scans and clustering, we discover the novel",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "kin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mutations Gste2- F120L and Cyp9K1 -N224I in detoxification enzymes that are",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gste2- F120L",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cyp9K1",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "driving selective sweeps, likely in response to insecticidal pressure. We find",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that the frequencies of some resistance variants are associated with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "artisanal-gold mines, and elucidate the continued evolution of the Voltage-gated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sodium channel , the target of pyrethroid insecticides. Overall, we show that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "sodium channel",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sampling vectors strategically may enhance our ability to perform effective",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Rapid detection of G6PD deficiency SNPs using a novel amplicon-based MinION",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Sequencing Assay.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Plasmodium vivax malaria remains a significant global health challenge,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complicated by the parasite's ability to form dormant liver stages (hypnozoites)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that cause relapses. Radical cure of P. vivax malaria requires administration of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a hypnozoitocidal drug, such as primaquine or tafenoquine. However, these drugs",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "can cause severe haemolysis in individuals with glucose-6-phosphate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency. G6PD deficiency is caused by more than 230",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "more than 230",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "different variants at the gene level that confer different degrees of deficiency",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "phenotypically. Understanding the distribution of different G6PD variants in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "affected populations is essential to inform safer antimalarial treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "strategies. This study aimed to develop a cost-effective sequencing assay",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "targeting key regions of the G6PD gene, suitable for field deployment. A novel",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assay based on Nanopore technology was designed to amplify two amplicons",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nanopore",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "covering exon 3 to exon 13, focusing on known variants associated with enzyme",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "deficiency. A total of 79 samples from individuals in Cambodia, Vietnam,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "79",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cambodia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vietnam",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Afghanistan, and China were sequenced, and a bioinformatics pipeline was created",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Afghanistan",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for the targeted variant calling of 192 G6PD SNP mutations. The assay",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "192",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "SNP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "demonstrated reliable detection of known variants, with high concordance between",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "runs, within runs, and with Sanger sequencing. The Nanopore MinION long-amplicon",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sanger",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanopore",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sequencing assay offers a robust and portable solution for large-scale G6PD",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "genotyping in low-resource settings, that will improve malaria control and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "elimination strategies by enabling safer antimalarial treatment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "8. ACS Med Chem Lett. 2025 Jun 6;16(7):1383-1390. doi:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "10.1021/acsmedchemlett.5c00251. eCollection 2025 Jul 10.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1021",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Acridone Prodrugs with Enhanced Dual-Stage Antimalarial Efficacy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Acridone Prodrugs",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "J(4), Chin G(4), Kudyba K(4), McEnearney S(4), Jin X(4), Dennis WE(4), Chetree",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chin",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "McEnearney",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jin X(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dennis WE(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "R(4), Blount C(4), Pannone K(4), Dinh HT(4), Mdaki K(4), Leed S(4), Lee PJ(4),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Blount C(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dinh HT(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mdaki",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Leed",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lee PJ(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Roth A(4), Kancharla P(1), Kelly JX(1)(2).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kancharla P(1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kelly JX(1)(2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Chemistry, Portland State University, Portland, Oregon 97201,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chemistry",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Portland State University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Portland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "97201",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Portland, Oregon 97239, United",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Veterans Affairs Medical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Portland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oregon 97239",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)CAMCOR, University of Oregon, Eugene, Oregon 97403, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)CAMCOR",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Oregon",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Eugene",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oregon 97403",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Experimental Therapeutics Branch, CIDR, Walter Reed Army Institute of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Therapeutics Branch",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "CIDR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Walter Reed Army Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research, Silver Spring, Maryland 20910, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Silver Spring",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maryland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "20910",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "In this study, we present a prodrug strategy that successfully led to the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development of highly potent dual-stage antimalarial acridone analogs with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "radical cure potential. Notably, the prodrug T235, featuring a carbamate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "T235",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "promoiety on the middle ring of the acridone core, demonstrated greater oral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "efficacy than its parent compound, T226. T235 provided a complete cure in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "T226",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "T235",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Plasmodium yoelii-infected mice up to 28 days at doses of 3 and 10 mg/kg",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "up to 28 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "3 and 10 mg/kg\n",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "administered over 4 days and was also curative with a single oral dose of 20",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "20",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mg/kg. Furthermore, T235 offered full liver-stage protection and a sustained",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "T235",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "blood-stage cure in murine Plasmodium berghei infection when administered orally",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "berghei",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "at 10 mg/kg/day, exhibiting superior prophylactic efficacy compared to T226.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10 mg/kg/day",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "T226",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "This study paves the way for the development of highly effective acridone-based",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prodrugs for both malaria prevention and treatment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A Novel Plasmodium falciparum Kelch13 A675T Mutation and High Levels of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Novel Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kelch13 A675T Mutation",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Antimalarial resistance, including failure of artemisinin combination therapy,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is increasing in Africa. Molecular surveillance of markers of drug resistance is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cibitoke Province, Burundi were sequenced for ten markers of resistance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cibitoke Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Burundi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ten",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(including potential background markers conferring kelch 13-mediated artemisinin",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "partial resistance) by Illumina or Nanopore sequencing. Plasmepsin-2 and mdr1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Illumina",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanopore",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "mdr1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "copy number variations were typed by digital PCR. Among 157 isolates, no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "157",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "validated pfkelch13 mutations linked to artemisinin partial resistance (ART-R)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pfkelch13",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were detected. However, a novel pfkelch13 mutation, A675T, was identified. A",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pfkelch13",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mutation in the same position (A675V) had been found and validated in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neighboring Rwanda previously. Background mutations were frequent, including",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rwanda",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pffd D193Y (45.9%) and pfarps10 V127M (11.5%). Sulfadoxine-pyrimethamine (SP)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "D193Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "45.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "pfarps10 V127M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "11.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance was widespread, with quintuple haplotypes detected in 82.3% and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "82.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sextuple haplotypes in 12.3% of mono-infections. The pfcrt IET triple mutant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "IET",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "haplotype (94.9%) and pfmdr1 N-F-D mutant haplotype (57.9%) indicate sustained",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "94.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "pfmdr1 N-F-D",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "57.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CQ resistance and efficacy of artemether-lumefantrine (AL). No pfpm2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CQ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "duplications but rare pfmdr1 amplifications (1.8%) were identified. These",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings indicate substantial SP resistance, posing a threat to the efficacy of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SP",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "IPTp and SMC strategies in Burundi. The findings also show potential ART-R and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SMC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Burundi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "partner drug resistance in Burundi, highlighting the need for strengthened",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burundi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "surveillance and coordinated regional efforts to mitigate resistance and sustain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Artemisinin resistant kelch13 R622I and RDT negativity approaching predominance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "kelch13",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "RDT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in northern Ethiopia and emerging C580Y of African origin threaten falciparum",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Zeleke AJ, Fola AA, Tollefson GA, Niaré K, Leonetti A, Taropawala O, Marglous J,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Zeleke AJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fola AA",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tollefson GA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Niaré K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Leonetti A",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Taropawala O",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Crudale R, Brhane BG, Assefa A, Kiyuka P, Parr JB, Hailu A, Aemero M, Bailey JA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Brhane BG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kiyuka P",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Parr JB",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hailu A",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aemero M",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bailey JA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The rise of antimalarial drug-resistant Plasmodium falciparum poses a major",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "threat to malaria treatment, control, and elimination efforts. Mutations in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "kelch13 ( k13 ) gene confer artemisinin partial resistance (ART-R), compromising",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "gene confer",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the efficacy of combination therapies. In the Horn of Africa, the validated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Horn of Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mutation k13 R622I has rapidly emerged in parallel with other mutations",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "elsewhere in Eastern Africa. To monitor and inform control efforts, we conducted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Eastern Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in-depth sampling where R622I was first detected, using molecular inversion",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "probe (MIP) targeted sequencing of key resistance mutations and informative SNPs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MIP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "across the genome. Samples were collected for a year within two districts,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "a year",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gondar Zuria and Tach Armachiho, representing different ecological zones in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gondar Zuria",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tach Armachiho",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "northwest Ethiopia. Among 903 people with P. falciparum malaria, we observed a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "903",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "markedly higher prevalence of R622I (44.3%) compared to earlier reports, with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "44.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly higher prevalence in Gondar Zuria (52%) than in Tach Armachiho",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gondar Zuria",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "52%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tach Armachiho",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(40%; p<0.001). Alarmingly, the prevalence of histidine rich protein 2 (HRP2)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "based rapid diagnostic test (RDT) negativity was higher in R622I mutants",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RDT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "compared to wild types (48.3% vs 30.7%; p<0.001). Furthermore, 98.2% of R622I",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "48.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "30.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "98.2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "samples carried the multidrug resistance protein 1 NFD haplotype associated with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "NFD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced susceptibility to lumefantrine. We also detected the k13 C580Y mutation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in two patients (0.4%) from Gondar Zuria, the first report in the Horn of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gondar Zuria",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Horn of\n",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Africa. Identity-by-descent (IBD) analysis showed C580Y mutant parasites were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "likely clonal (IBD=1). Whole-genome sequencing confirmed their clonal nature and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed flanking haplotypes distinct from those seen in Southeast Asia where",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Southeast Asia",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the mutation was first observed, suggesting a local, de novo emergence. These",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings highlight increasing prevalence and types of ART-R mutations and the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "concerning association now with RDT negativity that will further challenge",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RDT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "malaria control and elimination efforts.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Investing in traditional medicine: leveraging evidence and innovative research",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to strengthen the fight against malaria in Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Youth in Research Hub, Enugu State, Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Hub",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Public Health, Federal University of Technology Owerri, Owerri,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Federal University of Technology Owerri",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Owerri",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Youth in Research Hub, Enugu State, Nigeria. Stanleyeneh234@gmail.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Youth",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Research Hub",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)IVAN Research Institute, University of Nigeria, Nsukka, Enugu State, Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4)IVAN Research Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Nigeria",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nsukka, Enugu State",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Community Health, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Obafemi Awolowo University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Departments of Public Health, College of Medical Science, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Health, College of Medical Science, University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Departments of Plant and Ecological Studies, University of Calabar, Calabar,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plant and Ecological Studies",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Calabar",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Calabar",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Faculty of Pharmacy, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun, Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmacy, Obafemi Awolowo University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(9)Department of Human Kinetics and Health Education, Faculty of Education,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Human Kinetics and Health Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(10)Department of Community Health, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Community Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Obafemi Awolowo University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(11)Department of Public Health, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, David Umahi",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "11)Department of Public Health, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "David Umahi",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Federal University of Health Sciences, Uburu, Ebonyi, Nigeria.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Federal University of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Uburu",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ebonyi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Traditional medicine (TM) has been a cornerstone of healthcare across various",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cultures, especially in Africa, where it has played an integral role in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "management of diseases such as malaria. Despite the popularity and historical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "significance of TM, scientific validation remains a key challenge, hindering its",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "widespread acceptance in modern healthcare systems. This study explores the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "potential of traditional African medicine, particularly in the context of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Nigeria, as a vital resource in the fight against malaria. Drawing on the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "success of plants like Artemisia annua in the development of modern",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Artemisia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "anti-malarial drugs, the research emphasizes the need for comprehensive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "investment in TM research. With Nigeria facing the highest malaria burden",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "globally, the research advocates for increased funding, scientific",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "investigations into the efficacy of traditional remedies, and enhanced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "regulation of herbal medicine. The paper also highlights the growing trust and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reliance on herbal remedies in rural areas of Nigeria and the importance of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ensuring their safety through pharmacological testing. This study examines these",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "issues through an analysis of existing literature, historical applications, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "documented successes of herbal treatments. By integrating traditional medicine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "into national health systems, Nigeria could unlock new strategies for combating",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigeria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "malaria and other infectious diseases, advancing toward sustainable health",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025. The Author(s).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665320 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665320",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interests: The authors declare no competing interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "12. BMC Infect Dis. 2025 Jul 15;25(1):921. doi: 10.1186/s12879-025-11266-x.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The resurgence of malaria in Northern Iran in 2023: a wake-up call.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Northern Iran",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Laboratory Sciences Research Center, Golestan University of Medical Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sciences Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golestan University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Infectious Diseases Research Center, Golestan University of Medical Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Diseases Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golestan University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Infectious Diseases Research Center, Golestan University of Medical Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Diseases Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golestan University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Control and elimination programs for malaria in Iran have",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "consistently faced significant challenges due to various factors, including the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "presence of neighboring malaria-endemic countries such as Afghanistan and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Afghanistan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pakistan. In recent years, Golestan Province in northern Iran has recorded few",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pakistan",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "recent years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golestan Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cases of imported malaria, with a sudden increase of 22 cases in 2023. This",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "article provides an overview of the malaria situation in northern Iran, along",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with a detailed report of these 22 cases.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: The study population comprises all individuals exhibiting symptoms",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "suspected of malaria (n = 445) who were referred to the Malaria Diagnosis Center",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "445",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Malaria Diagnosis Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in Golestan Province, located in northeastern Iran, for diagnosis between March",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Golestan Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "between March",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "23, 2023, and December 23, 2023. A drop of peripheral blood, collected from a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "23, 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "December 23, 2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "finger prick of each patient, was utilized for Plasmodium falciparum/P. vivax",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "antigen detection. Moreover, thin and thick smears were prepared for each",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patient to investigate morphological characteristics and parasitemia percentage",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of the parasites.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: In total, 4.94% (22/445) of individuals with malaria-suspected symptoms",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4.94%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "22/445",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were infected with Plasmodium species. All 22 infected individuals were native",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plasmodium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to Golestan Province, and none had a previous history. The mean ± standard error",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Golestan Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of mean (SEM) for the number of parasites/µL of blood sample was 16,029 ± 5,060",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16,029",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5,060",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for P. vivax and 105,460 ± 102,146 for P. falciparum. Among the patients, 77.27%",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "105,460",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "102,146",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "77.27%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(17/22) were infected with P. vivax, 18.18% (4/22) were infected with P.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "17/22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.18%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "falciparum, and 4.54% (1/22) were co-infected with both P. vivax and P.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4.54%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "1/22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "P.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "falciparum. In the case of P. falciparum, 40% (1/5) of the samples presented the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "1/5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ring form, 60% (3/5) trophozoite form, and 20% (1/5) gametocyte form. All",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "60%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "3/5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "20%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "1/5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients demonstrated a positive response to the treatment, with a decrease in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "both the number of parasites and the number of clinical symptoms over time.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: This study discussed 22 cases of malaria diagnosed in 2023 in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Golestan Province in northern Iran. Given the presence of malaria vectors in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Golestan Province",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "this area and the observation of gametocytes in specimens from some patients,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the increase in reported malaria cases could be worrisome in terms of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "establishing local transmission in this area.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665230 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665230",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: This study complied with the provisions of the Declaration of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Declaration of\n",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Helsinki and was approved by the ethics committee of Golestan University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Golestan University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical Sciences, with the following code: IR.GOUMS.REC.1402.500. Since the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "participants were patients who were referred for diagnosis and treatment of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malaria, and their personal information remained confidential and would not be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "published, with the approval of the above-mentioned ethics committee, there was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "no need to obtain an informed consent form. Consent for publication: Not",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "13. BMC Nephrol. 2025 Jul 15;26(1):390. doi: 10.1186/s12882-025-04333-7.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMC Nephrol",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jul 15;26(1):390",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Malaria associated pathogenesis of chronic kidney disease (MAP-CKD): a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malaria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prospective study of children hospitalized with severe malaria.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SL(16), Conroy AL(17)(18)(19).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Conroy AL(17)(18)(19",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Child Health and Development Centre, Makerere University College of Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Health and Development Centre",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Makerere University College of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Paediatrics and Child Health, Makerere University College of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Paediatrics and Child Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Makerere University College",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Health Sciences, Kampala, Uganda.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kampala",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Paediatrics, Mulago National Referral and Teaching Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Paediatrics, Mulago National Referral and Teaching Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Pediatric Nephrology, Indiana University School of Medicine,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pediatric Nephrology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indiana University School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Ryan White Center for Pediatric Infectious Disease and Global Health, Indiana",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7)Ryan White Center for Pediatric Infectious Disease and Global Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indiana",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indianapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(10)Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Makerere University School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Makerere University School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Public Health, Kampala, Uganda.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kampala",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(13)Department of Nephrology, Barts Health NHS Trust, London, UK.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13)Department of Nephrology",
        "label": "MONEY"
      },
      {
        "text": "Barts Health NHS Trust",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "London",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "UK",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(14)Red Cross War Memorial Children's Hospital, University of Cape Town, Cape",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Cape Town",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cape",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Town, South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Town",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "South Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(16)Division of Nephrology, Department of Pediatrics, Center for Acute Care",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16)Division of Nephrology, Department of Pediatrics",
        "label": "MONEY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(18)Ryan White Center for Pediatric Infectious Disease and Global Health,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "White Center for Pediatric Infectious Disease and Global Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, USA. conroya@iu.edu.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Indiana University School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indianapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(19), 1044 West Walnut St., Indianapolis, IN, 46404, USA. conroya@iu.edu.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "19",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1044",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "West Walnut St.",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indianapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "46404",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Severe malaria (SM) remains a leading cause of child mortality and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SM",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an important global contributor to acute kidney injury (AKI), which can progress",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to chronic kidney disease (CKD) in some survivors. Notably, 80% of AKI deaths",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "80%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanisms and recovery trajectory of SM associated AKI remain poorly",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "understood. There is a critical need to define the etiology and pathophysiology",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of SM-AKI, uncover pathways of maladaptive repair, identify risk factors for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SM-AKI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CKD, and evaluate long-term health and development.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This prospective multi-site cohort study will enroll children at three",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sites in Uganda: Mulago National Referral and Teaching Hospital, Jinja Regional",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mulago National Referral and Teaching Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "children with severe malaria and 375 community controls between 3 months of age",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "375",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "between 3 months of age\n",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and < 16 years. Participants will be followed for two years. Children with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "two years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "severe malaria will be assessed at 1-, 2-, and 4-months to evaluate short-term",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4-months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "kidney recovery and 12- and 24-months to assess kidney function and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "24-months",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "health-related quality of life. The study will investigate short-term and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "long-term kidney disease risk factors following severe malaria. We will",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characterize host pathways involved in maladaptive kidney repair, focusing on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanisms related to cell stress, angiogenesis, and tubulointerstitial injury.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Additionally, we will assess the impact of AKI and persistent kidney disease on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AKI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "morbidity, mortality, and health-related quality of life. Cognitive and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "behavioral assessments, along with brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), will",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "be used to evaluate the effects of AKI on brain injury and edema.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DISCUSSION: This study will generate key insights into the prevalence of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "persistent kidney disease following SM-AKI and identify risk factors for CKD to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SM-AKI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CKD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inform clinical follow-up. Defining specific pathways involved with maladaptive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "repair in severe malaria will provide the foundation for targeted interventions",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to promote adaptive recovery. The research has the potential to transform",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "long-term health outcomes following SM-AKI.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SM-AKI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "TRIAL REGISTRATION: ISRCTN10885288.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.1186/s12882-025-04333-7",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665227 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665227",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: The study is approved by the Makerere University School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Makerere University School of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Biomedical Sciences Research Ethics Committee (SBS-REC, protocol number:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Biomedical Sciences Research Ethics Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SBS-2022-173), Indiana University School of Medicine Institutional Review Board",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SBS-2022",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indiana University School of Medicine Institutional Review Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(IUSM- IRB, protocol number: 15144) and the Uganda National Council for Science",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15144",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Uganda National Council for Science\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Technology (UNCST, protocol number: HS2794ES). The study will be conducted",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "principles outlined in the International Ethical Guidelines for Biomedical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the International Ethical Guidelines for Biomedical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research Involving Human Participants and the Declaration of Helsinki. Consent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Involving Human Participants",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Declaration of Helsinki",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "competing interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "14. Parasitology. 2025 Jul 16:1-43. doi: 10.1017/S0031182025100310. Online ahead",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "14",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "16:1-43",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1017/S0031182025100310",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of print.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Plasmodium simium: birth and evolution of a zoonotic malaria parasite species.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Parasitology, Institute of Biomedical Sciences, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Parasitology, Institute of Biomedical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Medical Parasitology and Infection Biology, Swiss Tropical and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Parasitology and Infection Biology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Public Health Institute, Basel, Switzerland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Health Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Basel",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Switzerland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)University of Basel, Basel, Switzerland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Basel",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Basel",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Switzerland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Brazilian Center for Research in Energy and Materials, Campinas, SP, Brazil.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Brazilian",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Center for Research in Energy and Materials",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Campinas",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "SP",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brazil",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Translational Medicine, School of Medical Sciences, University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Translational Medicine, School of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Campinas, Campinas, SP, Brazil.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Campinas",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Campinas",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "SP",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brazil",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Maryland School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microbiology and Immunology, University of Maryland School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Global Health and Tropical Medicine (GHTM), Associate Laboratory in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Health and Tropical Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Associate Laboratory",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Translation and Innovation Towards Global Health (LA-REAL), Institute of Hygiene",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institute of Hygiene",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Tropical Medicine, NOVA University of Lisbon, Lisbon, Portugal.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tropical Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NOVA University of Lisbon,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lisbon",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Portugal",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "15. Nat Microbiol. 2025 Jul 15. doi: 10.1038/s41564-025-02052-1. Online ahead of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nat Microbiol",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1038",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Fighting malaria as a patient and scientist.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Malaria and NTD Division, Armauer Hansen Research Institute, Addis Ababa,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)Malaria",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NTD Division",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Armauer Hansen Research Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Addis Ababa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Infection Biology, London School of Hygiene and Tropical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Infection Biology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "London School of Hygiene and Tropical\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Medical Microbiology, Radboudumc, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Microbiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nijmegen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Netherlands",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Competing interests: The author declares no",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Automated multi-model framework for malaria detection using deep learning and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "feature fusion.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Computer Science, College of Computer and Information Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Computer Science, College of Computer and Information Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Information Systems, College of Computer and Information",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Information Systems",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "College of Computer and Information",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, Jouf University, Sakaka, Saudi Arabia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jouf University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sakaka",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Saudi Arabia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Computer Science, College of Computer and Information Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Computer Science, College of Computer and Information Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Biomedical Engineering and Systems Department, Faculty of Engineering, Cairo",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Engineering",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cairo",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Giza, Egypt.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Giza",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Egypt",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Biomedical Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering and Technology,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Biomedical Engineering Department",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Engineering and Technology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Future University in Egypt, New Cairo, Egypt. neven.saleh@fue.edu.eg.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Future University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Egypt",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "New Cairo",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Egypt",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Malaria remains a critical global health challenge, particularly in tropical and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malaria",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "subtropical regions. While traditional methods for diagnosis are effective, they",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "face some limitations related to accuracy, time consumption, and manual effort.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "This study proposes an advanced, automated diagnostic framework for malaria",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "detection using a multi-model architecture integrating deep learning and machine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "learning techniques. The framework employs a transfer learning approach that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "incorporates ResNet 50, VGG16, and DenseNet-201 for feature extraction. This is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ResNet 50",
        "label": "LAW"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "followed by feature fusion and dimensionality reduction via principal component",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis. A hybrid scheme that combines support vector machine and long",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "short-term memory networks is used for classification. A majority voting",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanism aggregates outputs from all models to enhance prediction robustness.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The approach was validated on a publicly available dataset comprising 27,558",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "27,558",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "microscopic thin blood smear images. The results demonstrated superior",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "performance, achieving an accuracy of 96.47%, sensitivity of 96.03%, specificity",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "96.47%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "96.03%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of 96.90%, precision of 96.88%, and F1-score of 96.45% using the majority voting",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "96.90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "96.88%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "F1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "96.45%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ensemble. Comparative analysis highlights the framework's advancements over",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "existing methods in diagnostic reliability and computational efficiency. This",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "work underscores the potential of AI-driven solutions in advancing malaria",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnostics and lays the foundation for applications in other blood-borne",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40664727 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Competing interests: The authors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Marked heterogeneity in malaria infection rate in a Malian longitudinal cohort.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Malian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Buckee CO(4), Crompton PD(5), Traore B(6), Tran TM(7), Neafsey DE(8)(9).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Buckee CO(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Crompton",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tran",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Neafsey",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "DE(8)(9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Immunology and Infectious Diseases, Harvard T.H. Chan School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Immunology and Infectious Diseases",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Harvard T.H. Chan School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Public Health, Boston, MA, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boston",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Infectious Disease and Microbiome Program, Broad Institute of MIT and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Disease and Microbiome Program",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Broad Institute of MIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Ragon Institute of MGH, MIT, and Harvard, Cambridge, MA, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Ragon Institute of MGH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Harvard",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cambridge",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Epidemiology, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Epidemiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Boston, MA, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boston",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Malaria Infection Biology and Immunity Section, Laboratory of Immunogenetics,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Malaria",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Infection Biology and Immunity Section, Laboratory of Immunogenetics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Health, Rockville, MD, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rockville",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MD",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Mali International Center of Excellence in Research, University of Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6)Mali International Center of Excellence in Research, University of Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Technique and Technology of Bamako, Bamako, Mali.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bamako",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mali",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Division of Infectious Diseases, Department of Medicine, Indiana University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Infectious Diseases",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indiana University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School of Medicine, Indianapolis, IN, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "School of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indianapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IN",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Department of Immunology and Infectious Diseases, Harvard T.H. Chan School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Harvard T.H. Chan School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Public Health, Boston, MA, USA. neafsey@hsph.harvard.edu.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boston",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "neafsey@hsph.harvard.edu",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(9)Infectious Disease and Microbiome Program, Broad Institute of MIT and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Broad Institute of MIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Variation in malaria infection risk, a product of disease exposure and immunity,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is poorly understood. We genotypically profiled over 13,000 blood samples from a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "over 13,000",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "six-year longitudinal cohort in Mali to characterize malaria infection dynamics",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six-year",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mali",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with detail. We generated Plasmodium falciparum amplicon sequencing data from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "464 participants (aged 3 months - 25 years) across the six-month 2011",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "464",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3 months - 25 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "six-month 2011",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transmission season and profiled a subset of 120 participants across the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "transmission season",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "120",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "subsequent five annual transmission seasons. We measured infection rate as the",
    "entities": [
      {
