[
  {
    "text": "Immunoassay for pyruvate kinase M1/2 as an Alzheimer's biomarker in CSF.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SE(1), Carlyle BC(3)(4).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SE(1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Carlyle BC(3)(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Massachusetts General Hospital & Harvard Medical School, Department of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "General Hospital & Harvard Medical School, Department",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Neurology, Boston, MA, United States of America.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boston",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States of America",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Physiology, Anatomy & Genetics, University of Oxford, Oxford,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Physiology, Anatomy & Genetics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Oxford",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "United Kingdom.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "United Kingdom",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Kavli Institute for Nanoscience Discovery, University of Oxford, Oxford,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institute for Nanoscience Discovery",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Oxford",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tangles in the brain, but these markers alone do not predict disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "progression. The intersection of these pathologies with other processes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "including metabolic changes may contribute to disease progression. Brain glucose",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolism changes are among the earliest detectable events in AD. Pyruvate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "kinase (PKM) has been implicated as a potential biomarker to track these",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic changes. We have developed an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(ELISA) to assess PKM levels in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). First, we verified",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ELISA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "First",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the relationship of CSF PKM levels with cognitive decline, revealing a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "correlation between elevated CSF PKM levels and accelerated cognitive decline in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preclinical AD patients in a tau-dependent manner. We developed the ELISA using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ELISA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "two PKM-specific antibodies and validated it through quality control steps,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "indicating robust quantification of PKM. We showed that ELISA measurements of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ELISA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PKM correlate with mass spectrometry values in matching samples. When tested on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an independent cohort, the assay confirmed elevation of PKM in AD. These",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings support the use of PKM as a potential biomarker for tracking early",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic changes in AD, offering a novel tool for investigating metabolic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "alterations and their intersection with other underlying pathologies in AD",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 the author(s), published by De Gruyter.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "De Gruyter",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Conflict of interest: B.C.C. has received",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "B.C.C.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sponsored research funding from Ono Pharmaceutical, and GSK. S.E.A. has served",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ono Pharmaceutical",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GSK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "S.E.A.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "on the Scientific Advisory Board of Allyx Therapeutics, BioVie, Bob’s Last",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Scientific Advisory Board of Allyx Therapeutics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BioVie",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bob",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Marathon, Jocasta, Sage Therapeutics, and Merck. S.E.A. has acted as Consultant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jocasta",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Merck",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "S.E.A.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for EIP Pharma and Daewoong Pharmaceuticals. S.E.A. has received sponsored",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EIP Pharma",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Daewoong Pharmaceuticals",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "S.E.A.",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "research funding from AbbVie, AC Immune, Amylyx, Athira Pharma, Chromadex,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AbbVie",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AC Immune",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amylyx",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Athira Pharma",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chromadex",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cyclerion Therapeutics, EIP Pharma, Janssen, Johnson & Johnson, Ionis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cyclerion Therapeutics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EIP Pharma",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johnson & Johnson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ionis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pharmaceuticals, Novartis, Seer Bioscience and vTv Theraputics.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Novartis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Seer Bioscience",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Theraputics",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Toxicity of glyphosate accelerates neurodegeneration in Caenorhabditis elegans",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Caenorhabditis",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "model of Alzheimer's disease.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Toxicology, School of Chemical & Life Sciences, Jamia Hamdard,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Toxicology, School of Chemical & Life Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jamia Hamdard",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, School of Pharmaceutical Education &",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Chemistry",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "School of Pharmaceutical Education &",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi, India.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jamia Hamdard",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "New Delhi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "India",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: Pesticide-related environmental contamination poses a growing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "global concern, threatening human health, wildlife, and ecosystems. Glyphosate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(N-phosphonomethyl-glycine, GLY), a widely used organophosphorus herbicide, has",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLY",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "been associated with neurotoxic effects. This study investigates the potential",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neurodegenerative impact of glyphosate using a Caenorhabditis elegans",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Caenorhabditis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease (AD) model.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Transgenic C. elegans strain CL4176, which expresses human amyloid-beta",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CL4176",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(Aβ1-42) upon temperature induction, was exposed to various concentrations of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "glyphosate (12, 15, 18.5, 20, and 25 mg/L) for 24 hours. Behavioral assays (body",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "20",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "25 mg/L",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "24 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "bends, head thrashes, body length, and pharyngeal pumping), oxidative stress",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "markers (catalase activity), and Aβ protein expression were evaluated.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Glyphosate exposure induced a concentration-dependent decline in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "locomotor and feeding behaviors. Catalase activity was significantly reduced,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "indicating elevated oxidative stress. Additionally, a marked increase in Aβ1-42",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "protein expression was observed in glyphosate-treated CL4176 worms.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CL4176",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DISCUSSION: These findings suggest that glyphosate exacerbates Aβ toxicity and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "induces AD-like phenotypes in the C. elegans model through behavioral",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "impairment, oxidative stress, and increased Aβ accumulation. Glyphosate's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Glyphosate",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "potential contribution to neurodegenerative processes warrants further",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "investigation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Rani, Alam and Parvez.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Rani",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Alam",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Parvez",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DOI: 10.3389/ftox.2025.1578230",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.3389",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Development of a method for large-scale single-molecule analysis of tau",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "proteoforms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Flaster ME, Grothe R, Guha S, Kaneshige K, McVey K, Nelson N, Perera RT, Tan SJ,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Flaster ME",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kaneshige K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "McVey K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nelson N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Perera RT",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tan SJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "S, Forton A, Sartori ER, Brereton PS, Chen K, Darcy MA, Golnabi HR, Hartley R,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sartori ER",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brereton PS",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chen K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Darcy MA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Golnabi HR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hartley R",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SK; Nautilus Biotechnology; Kapp GT, Patel S, Temple S, Bertucci T, Blanchard J,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nautilus Biotechnology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kapp GT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Patel S",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bertucci T",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Blanchard J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Proteins exist as diverse proteoforms resulting from a combination of genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "variation, alternative splicing, and post-translational modifications. Current",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "methods struggle to capture this complexity at the single-molecule level. Here",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "we introduce Iterative Ma pping of P roteoforms (IMaP), a method that enables",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Iterative Ma",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the massively-parallel interrogation of millions to billions of single-protein",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "millions to billions",
        "label": "MONEY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecules through iterative probing with fluorescently labeled antibodies. Using",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "12 site-specific antibodies, the method is capable of measuring 2 12 (4,096)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2 12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "4,096",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "potential proteoform groups. We used IMaP to measure proteoform group profiles",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IMaP",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of the tau protein, a key player in neurodegenerative diseases, using two pan",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "anti-tau antibodies (Tau-13, Tau-216), three isoform-specific antibodies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(Anti-0N, Anti-2N, Anti-4R), and seven phosphosite-specific antibodies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "seven",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Anti-pS396). The method demonstrates high sensitivity (detecting proteoforms",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "at 0.1% abundance), high reproducibility (median CV <5.5%), and broad dynamic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.1%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CV",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "5.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "range (>3 orders of magnitude), outperforming conventional techniques in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resolving closely related proteoform groups. We demonstrated that the method can",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "be used on relevant biological samples by examining various neuronal models",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(iNeuron cells, organoids, miBrains, and mouse brains) and human samples. This",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "iNeuron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "examination revealed 130 distinct tau proteoform groups with as many as six",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "130",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "as many as six",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "phosphorylation events. The non-random distribution of these phosphorylation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "events suggests ordered and site-specific modification processes rather than",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "random, stochastic accumulation. Certain combinations of phosphorylation events",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were more abundant than others; for example, pT217 preferentially co-occurred",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with pT181. In validating the applicability of the assay to human disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "samples, we noted a specific pattern of multiple phosphorylation events in an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "advanced Alzheimer's disease patient that suggests a sequential pathway of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pathological tau modification. Iterative Mapping of Proteoforms provides",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Iterative Mapping of Proteoforms",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "insights into proteoform complexity at the single-molecule level, with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "significant implications for understanding protein regulation in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neurodegenerative diseases and beyond.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Sex-Stratified Transcriptomic Meta-Analysis of Alzheimer's Disease Reveal Brain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Region and Sex Specific Dysregulation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: Alzheimer disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disorder leading to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cognitive decline. Despite growing recognition of sex differences in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "epidemiology, symptomatology, and clinical outcomes of AD, the molecular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanisms underlying these variations remain poorly defined. We performed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transcriptome association studies of AD aiming to identify sex-specific and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sex-dependent transcriptomic profiles that could provide insights into the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular mechanisms underlying sex differences in AD pathogenesis.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We conducted a meta-analysis of bulk-RNAseq data derived from human",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNAseq",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "postmortem brain studies. Specifically, we analyzed gene expression differences",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "between individuals diagnosed with AD and non-cognitively impaired (NCI)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "individuals across two key brain regions: the prefrontal cortex and the temporal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lobe. We performed stratified differential expression analyses separately in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "males and females, alongside combined analyses across sexes. Additionally, we",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assessed the data in relation to known AD genes, proteomic studies, and drug",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "repurposing opportunities.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Beyond the genes commonly dysregulated across both sexes, our",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "meta-analyses identified multiple differentially expressed genes (DEGs) between",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AD and NCI that are either altered in only one sex or show different effects",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "only one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "between sexes. Some genes are known AD genes from genetic studies, but others",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "are novel. Correlation with proteomic data suggests that these transcriptional",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "differences have functional significance, potentially contributing to the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "biological mechanisms underlying sex differences observed in AD. Finally, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "identify drug compounds that are potential candidates for treatment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "INTERPRETATION: Our findings enhance our understanding of sex-related",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "differences in disease etiology and progression, and underscore the importance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of incorporating sex as a critical variable in transcriptomic studies of AD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "These insights help pave the way for more precise, personalized medicine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "approaches that account for sex-specific molecular mechanisms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "In vivo palpation of anisotropic human brain tissue using MRI.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The mechanical stiffness of brain parenchyma varies across physiological states",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and pathophysiological conditions, such as during normal and abnormal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and traumatic brain injury (TBI), neuronal activation, and sleep via the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TBI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "glymphatic brain waste clearance mechanism. Despite its biological and clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "importance, relatively few techniques exist to measure and map mechanical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "properties of brain tissue non-invasively and in vivo . MR elastography (MRE) is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MRE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an established method that has been widely used to estimate tissue stiffness in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the liver by applying mechanical waves using an external tamper and measuring",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "their resulting deformations. However, applying MRE in the brain is more",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MRE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "challenging due to the skull and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), which impede",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanical wave propagation, and tissue mechanical anisotropy, which requires a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "4 th -order tensor description. In this study, we propose using the intrinsic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "deformation of brain tissue caused by periodic cardiac pulsation to measure the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "4 th -order stiffness tensor throughout the brain while simultaneously",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "estimating the 2 nd -order diffusion tensor in each voxel throughout the cardiac",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cycle, which we use as a priori information in the reconstruction of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stiffness tensor. While the DTI-derived mean diffusivity (MD) appears uniform",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "throughout brain parenchyma, stiffness maps obtained at about 1 Hz (i.e., at the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "about 1 Hz",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fundamental cardiac frequency) show contrast within gray matter, and within",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "white matter pathways such as along the corpus callosum, internal capsule,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "corona radiata, etc. Generally, stiffness differences at internal tissue",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "boundaries are expected to lead to local stress concentration, which may",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "predispose tissues to damage in TBI. Therefore, our novel tamperless MRE method",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TBI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MRE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "has the potential to not only identify such interfaces, but assess changes in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue stiffness there that might occur following injury.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "APOE4 drives widespread changes to the hepatic proteome and alters metabolic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "function.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Morris JK, Wilkins HM.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Morris JK",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wilkins HM",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Apolipoprotein E (APOE) is essential for lipid homeostasis and has been",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "extensively studied in the central nervous system, particularly in the context",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of Alzheimer's disease (AD). Individuals carrying an APOE4 allele have an",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increased risk of AD and exhibit deficits in energy metabolism, including",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "glucose utilization and mitochondrial dysfunction. While the role of APOE in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "liver is well characterized, the impact of APOE genetic variation on hepatic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "health and metabolism remains poorly understood. We sought to investigate this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "using young female and male APOE3 and APOE4 targeted replacement mice. We also",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE3",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "used APOE isogenic induced pluripotent stem cell (iPSC)-derived hepatocyte-like",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Proteomic and functional assays show that APOE4 causes extensive changes to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "liver mitochondrial function in a sex-specific manner in mice and alters glucose",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and lipid metabolism. APOE4 also impairs mitochondrial function in iHLCs and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "iHLCs",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "shifts metabolism towards glycolysis while modifying expression of extracellular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "matrix proteins. Additionally, APOE4 iHLCs display a greater reliance on fatty",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "acids as an energy source and show increased lipid accumulation. Taken together,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "our findings show that APOE genetic variation causes mitochondrial dysfunction",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and rewires hepatic metabolism.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Structure-specific Mini-Prion Model for Alzheimer's Disease Tau Fibrils.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mini-Prion Model for Alzheimer's",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MP, Melo AA, Tse E, Shea JE, Shell MS, Kosik KS, Southworth DR, Han S.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Melo AA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shea JE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shell MS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kosik KS",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Southworth DR",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Han S.\n",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A critical discovery of the past decade is that tau protein fibrils adopt",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the past decade",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disease-specific hallmark structures in each tauopathy. The faithful generation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of synthetic fibrils adopting hallmark structures that can serve as targets for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "developing diagnostic and/or therapeutic strategies remains a grand challenge.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "We report on a rational design of synthetic fibrils built of a short peptide",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "that adopts a critical structural motif in tauopathy fibrils found in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's Disease (AD) and Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy (CTE). They serve",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "as minimal prions with exquisite seeding competency, in vitro and in tau",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "biosensor cells, for recruiting tau constructs ten times larger its size en",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ten",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "route to AD or CTE fibril structures. We demonstrate that the generation of AD",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and CTE-like fibril structures is dramatically catalyzed in the presence of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fibril",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mini-AD prions and further influenced by salt composition in solution. Double",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Electron-Electron Resonance studies confirmed the preservation of AD-like folds",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Electron-Electron Resonance",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "across multi-generational seeding. Fibrils formed with the full AD/CTE-like core",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "show strong seeding competency, with their templating effect dominating over the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "choice of salt composition that tunes the initial selection of AD- and CTE-like",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fibril populations. The mini-AD prions serve as a potent catalyst with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "fibril",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "templating capabilities that offer a novel strategy to design pathological tau",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Sustained Lysosomal Delivery of Enhanced Cy3-Labeled Acid Nanoparticles Restores",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Lysosomal pH in Retinal Pigment Epithelial Cells and Astrocytes.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Retinal Pigment Epithelial Cells",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Astrocytes",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Lysosomal pH is frequently elevated in age-dependent neurodegenerations like",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Age-related Macular Degeneration (AMD), Alzheimer's Disease (AD), and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Macular Degeneration",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AMD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Parkinson's Disease (PD). Tools that restore lysosomal pH to an optimal acidic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "range could enhance enzymatic degradation and reduce waste accumulation. Acidic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "nanoparticles offer a promising strategy for restoring lysosomal function, but",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "accurate tracking of organelle delivery and long-term retention is needed to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "optimize dosage. To improve detection and enhance delivery, nanoparticles were",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "synthesized from Poly(D,L-lactide-co-glycolide) (PLGA) polymers covalently",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Poly(D",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "linked to the fluorescent Cyanine3 amine (Cy3) probe. Nanoparticle concentration",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and loading times were optimized to achieve >90% delivery to lysosomes in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cultured induced pluripotent stem cell-derived retinal pigment epithelial",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(iPS-RPE) cells. Uptake was heterogeneous, varying between adjacent cells. Once",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "loaded into lysosomes, the nanoparticles were stably retained, with no",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "detectable changes in concentration, distribution, or size for at least 28 days.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "at least 28 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "iPS-RPE cells internalized more nanoparticles than the ARPE-19 cell line or",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mouse optic nerve head astrocyte cultures. Functionally, PLGA nanoparticles",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mouse",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "astrocyte",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "restored an acidic pH and cathepsin D levels in compromised lysosomes. In",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "summary, Cy3-PLGA nanoparticles enabled improved tracking and long-term delivery",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to lysosomes, supporting future in vivo applications to restore lysosomal pH in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "NEW AND NOTEWORTHY: Tools that restore acidic pH in compromised lysosomes can",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "enhance autophagy and waste degradation in degenerative disorders marked by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "excessive accumulation. Here, we describe the novel synthesis of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lysosome-targeted nanoparticles composed of PLGA polymers covalently bound to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PLGA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cy3 fluorescent dye. These Cy3-PLGA nanoparticles enabled improved tracking of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lysosomal delivery and demonstrated sustained long-term retention within",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lysosomes, supporting their potential for future applications to restore",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lysosomal pH in aging and degenerating tissues.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Discovery of an Achiral Small Molecule TREM2 Agonist with Improved",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Discovery",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Achiral Small Molecule TREM2",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pharmacokinetic Profile and Validated Target Engagement.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmacokinetic Profile",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The triggering receptor expressed on myeloid cells 2 (TREM2) is a lipid-sensing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "myeloid",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immunoreceptor on microglia that has emerged as a therapeutic target for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease. Here, we report the discovery of C1 , an achiral structural",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analog of VG-3927 -the first small molecule TREM2 agonist to enter clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "VG-3927",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "development. C1 was synthesized via a modular and enantioselective-free route",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "using sequential Suzuki couplings, enabling rapid scaffold diversification.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Suzuki",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Compared to VG-3927 , the stereochemically simplified derivative ( C1 ) exhibits",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "superior microglial phagocytosis and validated target engagement. C1 induces",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "TREM2 activation in HEK293-hTREM2/DAP12 cells, and its direct binding to TREM2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "HEK293-hTREM2/DAP12",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was confirmed using both microscale thermophoresis (MST) and surface plasmon",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resonance (SPR). Importantly, C1 also demonstrates a superior pharmacokinetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SPR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "profile to VG-3927 , including enhanced metabolic stability in human and mouse",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "microsomes, favorable PAMPA permeability, and a LogD 7 . 4 compatible with CNS",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "penetration. Docking studies suggested a potential binding mode of C1 at the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "extracellular domain of TREM2, revealing key polar and hydrophobic interactions.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "These findings position C1 as a synthetically accessible and pharmacokinetically",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "favorable lead for the development of TREM2-targeted therapies.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TREM2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Population-specific brain charts reveal Chinese-Western differences in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "X, Liu Y, Shen Y, Huang X, Ji GJ; Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Liu Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shen Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Huang X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ji GJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CHIMGEN Consortium; DIDA-MDD Working Group; MCADI; Chinese Lifespan Brain",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CHIMGEN Consortium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MDD Working Group",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCADI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Human brain charts provide unprecedented opportunities for decoding",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "neurodevelopmental milestones and establishing clinical benchmarks for precision",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "brain medicine 1-7 . However, current lifespan brain charts are primarily",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "derived from European and North American cohorts, with Asian populations",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "European",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "North American",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Asian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "severely underrepresented. Here, we present the first population-specific brain",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "charts for China, developed through the Chinese Lifespan Brain Mapping",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Chinese Lifespan Brain Mapping",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Consortium (Phase I) using neuroimaging data from 43,037 participants (aged",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "43,037",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "0-100 years) across 384 sites nationwide. We establish the lifespan normative",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0-100 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "384",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "trajectories for 296 structural brain phenotypes, encompassing global,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "296",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "subcortical, and cortical measures. Cross-population comparisons with Western",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "brain charts (based on data from 56,339 participants aged 0-100 years) reveal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "56,339",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0-100 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "distinct neurodevelopmental patterns in the Chinese population, including",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prolonged cortical and subcortical maturation, accelerated cerebellar growth,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and earlier development of sensorimotor regions relative to paralimbic regions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Crucially, these Chinese-specific charts outperform Western-derived models in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "predicting healthy brain phenotypes and detecting pathological deviations in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Chinese clinical cohorts. These findings highlight the urgent need for diverse,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "population-representative brain charts to advance equitable precision",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Identification of Chlamydia pneumoniae and NLRP3 inflammasome activation in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Identification of Chlamydia",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease retina.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Gupta VK, Mirzaei M, Black KL, Meyer JG, Arditi M, Crother TR, Koronyo-Hamaoui",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gupta VK",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mirzaei M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Black KL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Meyer JG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Arditi M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Crother TR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Koronyo-Hamaoui",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chlamydia pneumoniae (Cp), an obligate intracellular bacterium, has been",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chlamydia",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "implicated in Alzheimer's disease (AD), yet its role in retinal pathology",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "remains unexplored. We analyzed postmortem tissues from 95 human donors and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "95",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "found 2.9-4.1-fold increases in Cp inclusions in AD retinas and brains, with no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.9-4.1-fold",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cp",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant elevation in mild cognitive impairment (MCI). Proteomics revealed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dysregulation of retinal and brain bacterial infection-related proteins and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "NLRP3 inflammasome pathways. NLRP3 expression was markedly elevated in MCI and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AD retinas, and its activation was evident by increased N-terminal gasdermin D",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NGSDMD) and mature interleukin-1β. Retinal Cp strongly correlated with Aβ 42",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Retinal Cp",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ 42\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and NLRP3 inflammasome components, which tightly linked to cleaved",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "caspase-3-apoptotic and NGSDMD-pyroptotic cell death. Although retinal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "microgliosis was elevated in AD, Cp-associated microglia were reduced by 62%,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "62%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suggesting impaired Cp phagocytosis. Higher retinal Cp burden correlated with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "APOEε4, Braak stage, and cognitive deficit. Machine learning identified retinal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Braak",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cp or NLRP3 combined with Aβ 42 as strong predictors of AD diagnosis, staging,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "42",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and cognitive impairment. Our findings suggest that Cp infection contributes to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AD dementia but not initiating pathology, whereas early NLRP3 activation may",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRP3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "promote disease development, warranting studies on Cp's role in AD pathogenesis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cp",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and early antibiotic or inflammasome-targeted therapies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau Clearance Reverses Neuronal Dysfunction in Both Young and Aged C. elegans.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Young",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aged C. elegans",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Carroll T, Johnson GVW, Nehrke K.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Johnson GVW",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nehrke K.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's Disease (AD) is an age-related dementia and presents a growing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "medical and economic burden as the average human lifespan continues to rise. AD",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is classically diagnosed via the accumulation and aggregation of two major",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "proteins: amyloid-β and tau. To date, potential and FDA-approved therapies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "designed to clear these aggregates at best delay rather than prevent disease,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "indicating that the root cause of AD lay upstream of aggregate formation. Tau",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "protein's phosphorylation is critical for AD progression, and phosphorylation at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Threonine 231 is thought to be an early disease-associated, \"gatekeeper\" event.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Threonine 231",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Previously, we showed that genomic, single-copy insertion of phosphomimetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "human tau (T231E) into C. elegans mechanosensory neurons induced age-dependent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "deficits in light-touch sensation. Herein, we have generated new C. elegans",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "C.",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "models which express pan-neuronal human tau to assess the idea of selective",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "vulnerability and whether specific neuronal behaviors might be impacted",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preferentially. We also tested whether tau clearance via an Auxin Inducible",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Auxin Inducible",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Degron (AID) could reverse these deficits. Despite our hypothesis that prolonged",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Degron",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "AID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stress in older animals would induce irreversible metabolic rewiring or",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "maladaptation, tau depletion rescued known behavioral deficits at all ages",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tested, including in old worms which displayed the most overt phenotypes. Taken",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "together, our data suggest that neuronal dysfunction induced by phosphorylated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tau is reversible and provides reassurance that current early-phase therapeutic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "efforts aimed at reducing soluble tau levels in AD patients may prove effective.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Redox reactivities of membrane-bound Amyloid-β-Cu complexes and their targeting",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Redox",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amyloid-β-Cu",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by metallothionein-3.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease (AD) is characterized by the accumulation of amyloid-β",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "peptide (Aβ 1-40/42 ) in the central nervous system (CNS) and its aggregation in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-40/42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "senile amyloid plaques. Copper coordination to Aβ triggers Aβ 1-40/42",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-40/42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "aggregation and, in the presence of biological reducing agents, it promotes the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "catalytic generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) via Fenton-type and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ROS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Haber-Weiss reactions. Due to its amphiphilic nature, Aβ 1-40/42 can interact",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Haber-Weiss",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-40/42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with cell membranes and compromise their integrity by thinning the lipid bilayer",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and forming channel-like structures potentially leading to cell death. In this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "work, by applying biophysical and biochemical approaches, we characterized the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "insertion of Aβ 1-42 into an artificial lipid bilayer system mimicking cell",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "membranes and demonstrate that the Aβ 1-42 -lipid interaction does not prevent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the Cu 2+ coordination to Aβ 1-42 . We performed a comparative analysis of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "redox reactivities of membrane-bound Aβ 1-42 (memAβ 1-42 -Cu 2+ ) species with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-42",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "soluble Aβ 1-42 -Cu 2+ establishing that membrane insertion leads to memAβ 1-42",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-42 -Cu 2+",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "-Cu 2+ complexes featuring an enhanced detrimental catechol oxidase activity",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "towards the neurotransmitter dopamine. Moreover, memAβ 1-42 -Cu 2+ efficiently",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1-42 -Cu",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "catalyzes Aβ di-tyrosine crosslinking and hydroxyl radical production in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ di-tyrosine",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "hydroxyl",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "presence of ascorbate. In addition, we establish that memAβ 1-42 -Cu 2+ redox",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1-42 -Cu",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reactivity catalyze lipid peroxidation in membranes containing polyunsaturated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fatty acids (PUFAs), such as arachidonic acid (AA), leading to the generation of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malondialdehyde (MDA) toxic end-products. This reactivity compromises the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "malondialdehyde",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "MDA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "structural integrity of the lipid bilayers resulting in membrane leakage,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "further substantiating how important is to control aberrant Aβ 1-40/42 -Cu 2+",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-40/42 -Cu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "interactions in AD. Metallothioneins (MTs) are key metalloproteins central to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Metallothioneins",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "neuronal and astrocytic transition metal homeostasis and buffering. These",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cysteine-rich proteins bind with high affinity d 10 metals (Cu + and Zn 2+ )",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cu +",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "forming two metal thiolate clusters in their N-terminal β-domain and C-terminal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "α-domain. The metallothionein-3 (MT-3) isoform is central to metal homeostasis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MT-3",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in the CNS, but it is downregulated in AD patients, possessing a neuroprotective",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "role in AD. MT-3 can control aberrant protein-Cu 2+ interactions and the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MT-3",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cu-centered redox reactivities of amyloidogenic protein-Cu 2+ complexes such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "α-synuclein (Parkinson's disease), PrP (prion disease), and soluble and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PrP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "aggregated Aβ 1-40 (AD). In this work, we unravel that the detrimental memAβ",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-40",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1-42 -Cu 2+ catechol oxidase and redox reactivities can be efficiently silenced",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1-42 -Cu 2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by MT-3 via metal swap reactions, effectively scavenging and reducing Cu 2+ to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MT-3",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cu + in its β-domain using thiolates as electron source, forming the redox-inert",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "species Cu + 4 Zn 2+ 4 MT-3. Consequently, MT-3 can efficiently prevent lipid",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cu + 4 Zn",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "MT-3",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "peroxidation and protect membrane structural integrity. New strategies targeting",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "membrane-bound Aβ 1-42 -Cu 2+ complexes as key players of the AD etiology could",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ 1-42 -Cu 2+",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Synergistic effects of APOE ε4 and Alzheimer's pathology on the neural",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correlates of episodic remembering in cognitively unimpaired older adults.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Amyloid-β (Aβ) and tau pathology begin accumulating decades before clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Amyloid-β",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "decades",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "symptoms and are influenced by APOE ε4, a key genetic risk factor for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease (AD). Although the presence of Aβ, tau, and APOE ε4 are",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thought to impact brain function, their effects on the neural correlates of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "episodic memory retrieval in preclinical AD remains unknown. We investigated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "this question in 159 cognitively unimpaired older adults (mean age, 68.9±5.8",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "159",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "68.9±5.8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "years; 57% female) in the Stanford Aging and Memory Study. Participants",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "57%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Stanford Aging",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "completed an associative memory task concurrent with functional MRI. Aβ was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "measured using CSF Aβ 42 /Aβ 40 or Florbetaben-PET imaging and tau was measured",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "42",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "40",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Florbetaben-PET",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "using CSF pTau 181 . Hippocampal univariate activity and cortical reinstatement",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "pTau",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "181",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "- that is, reinstatement of patterns of neocortical activity that were present",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "during memory encoding - were measured during successful memory retrieval.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Analyses revealed that APOE ε4 was independently associated with greater Aβ and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tau burden, and that associations of AD biomarkers with brain function and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "memory were moderated by APOE ε4. Among APOE ε4 non-carriers, Aβ burden was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Aβ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "linked to a pattern of hippocampal hyperactivity. Among APOE ε4 carriers, CSF",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pTau 181 was linked to weaker cortical reinstatement during memory retrieval and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pTau",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "181",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lower memory performance. Thus, abnormal AD biomarkers and genetic risk",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "synergistically impact neural and behavioral expressions of memory in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preclinical AD. These findings highlight the critical role of APOE ε4 in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "moderating effects of AD pathology on brain function and identify candidate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanisms that may contribute to increased risk of memory impairment in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "critical mechanism supporting episodic remembering that contributes to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "individual differences in memory performance in older adults. However, the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "contribution of early Alzheimer's disease (AD) pathology to variability in this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanism is unknown. We demonstrate that associations of AD biomarkers with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hippocampal activity and cortical reinstatement are moderated by APOE ε4 in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cognitively unimpaired older adults. Amyloid-β-related hyperactivity was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Amyloid-β-related",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "observed in the hippocampus among APOE ε4 non-carriers, while CSF pTau 181 was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CSF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "pTau",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "181",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "linked to weaker cortical reinstatement during memory retrieval and lower memory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "performance among APOE ε4 carriers. Our findings highlight synergistic effects",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of APOE and AD pathology on brain function and identify candidate mechanisms",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that may underlie increased risk of memory impairment in preclinical AD.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau-seed interactome analysis reveals distinct functional signatures in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer's disease across model systems.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Martinez P, Patel H, You Y, Lopes D, Amaro A, Jury-Garfe N, Min Y, Redding-Ochoa",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lopes D",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amaro A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jury-Garfe N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Redding-Ochoa",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau aggregates propagate through the brain in a prion-like manner in Alzheimer's",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disease (AD) and other tauopathies, but the molecular identity and functional",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "partners of the seeding-competent Tau species remain poorly defined. Here, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tau",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "present an unbiased proteomic profiling of a high-molecular-weight (HMW)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HMW",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau-seed isolated from AD patient brains. We contrast this interactome with that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of a biochemically similar, seeding-incompetent HMW-Tau species from age-matched",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HMW",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "healthy controls. Despite comprising less than 5% of total Tau in the brain,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "less than 5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau-seed associates with a distinct set of proteins enriched in synaptic,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mitochondrial, and vesicle-trafficking functions. Cross-species functional",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "screening in Drosophila and mouse models identifies interactors that modulate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drosophila",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Tau toxicity and seeding. Spatially resolved analysis of postmortem AD brains",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reveals heterogenous co-deposition of these proteins with Tau aggregates,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tau",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "suggesting functionally distinct Tau-seed complexes. Together, this dataset",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "provides a framework for understanding selective Tau-seed toxicity and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "identifies candidate regulators of Tau propagation with therapeutic potential.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Proteomic and metabolic profiling reveals APOE4 -dependent shifts in whole",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "brain, neuronal, and astrocytic mitochondrial function and glycolysis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Lysaker CR, Johnson CN, Csikos V, Franczak E, Benson M, Gilmore CA, Birky CJ,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lysaker CR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johnson CN",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Csikos V",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Benson M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gilmore CA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Birky CJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Davis X, McCoin CS, Smith KP, Puchalska P, Crawford P, Slawson C, Thyfault JP,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Davis X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "McCoin CS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Smith",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "KP",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Puchalska P",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Crawford P",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Slawson C",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Thyfault",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Apolipoprotein E ( APOE ) genetic variation is the strongest genetic risk factor",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for late onset Alzheimer's disease (LOAD). Studies on APOE genotype dependent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "changes have largely focused on amyloid beta (Aβ) aggregation, disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pathology, and lipid metabolism. Recently, there has been increased interest in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the relationship between metabolic function and APOE genetic variation. In this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "study, we examined how APOE genotype can alter metabolism in the brains of young",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "male and female APOE3 and APOE4 targeted replacement (TR) mice. In combination",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with this, we also examined cell type-specific differences using induced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pluripotent stem cell (iPSC) derived astrocytes and neurons. We found sex and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "genotype dependent changes to metabolism in the brains of young APOE TR mice.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Specifically, APOE4 mice show signs of metabolic stress and compensatory",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mechanisms in the brain. Using proteomics and stable isotope tracing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolomics, we found that APOE4 iAstrocytes and iNeurons exhibit signs of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4 iAstrocytes",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inflammation, mitochondrial dysfunction, altered TCA cycle and malate-aspartate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "shuttle activity, and a metabolic shift toward glycolysis. Taken together, this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "data indicates APOE4 causes early changes to metabolism within the central",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "nervous system. While this study establishes a relationship between APOE",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "APOE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genotype and alterations in bioenergetics, additional studies are needed to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "JASMINE: A powerful representation learning method for enhanced analysis of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Ballard JL, Dai Z, Shen L, Long Q; Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ballard JL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dai Z",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shen L",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Alzheimer’s Disease Metabolomics Consortium.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Disease Metabolomics Consortium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Integrative analysis of multi-omics data provides a more comprehensive and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "nuanced view of a subject's biological state. However, high-dimensionality and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Existing methods for incomplete multi-omics data are scarce, do not fully",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "leverage both modality-specific and shared information, and produce task-biased",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "representations. We propose JASMINE, a self-supervised representation learning",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "method for incomplete multi-omics data that preserves both modality-specific and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "joint information and enhances sample similarity structure. JASMINE produces",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "embeddings that achieve superior performance across multiple tasks for two",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "different incomplete multi-omics datasets while requiring only a single round of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Epigenetic genes are differentially methylated in the blood of persons with mild",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Environmental factors play a role in AD pathology and are mediated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by changes in DNA methylation levels.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS AND RESULTS: We investigated whole genome methylation sequencing (WGMS)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "data from the blood of participants with mild cognitive impairment (MCI, N =99),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "99",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "late onset dementia due to Alzheimer's disease (AD, N =109), and who are",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "N",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "109",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cognitively unimpaired (CU, N =174) to test for differential methylation in 812",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "N",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "174",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "812",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genes with roles in epigenetic regulation ( e.g. , DNA methylation and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "demethylation, chromatin remodeling, histone modification, and RNA modification)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "curated from the EpiFactors 2.1 database. 71/812 genes were differentially",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EpiFactors",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2.1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "71/812",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "methylated comprising 190 unique differentially methylated positions (DMPs) in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "190",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MCI (MCI vs . CU pairwise comparison). 60/812 genes were differentially",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "60/812",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "methylated comprising 220 DMPs in AD (AD vs . CU pairwise comparison). The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "220",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "AD",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "CU",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "majority of differentially methylated genes in both MCI (41/71) and AD (33/60)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "41/71",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "33/60",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were histone modification genes and 23 differentially methylated genes were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "23",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "shared in both pairwise comparisons. 96 genes were differentially methylated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "96",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "comprising 243 DMPs between persons with MCI and AD (AD vs . MCI pairwise",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "243",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "comparison). 10 differentially methylated genes were shared between the 3",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pairwise comparisons, including CUGBP elav-like family member 2 ( CELF2 ),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CUGBP",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "histone deacetylase 9 ( HDAC9 ), RNA binding fox-1 homolog 1 ( RBFOX1 ),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "HDAC9",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "fox-1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "TATA-box binding protein associated factor 4 ( TAF4 ), and thymine DNA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TATA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Genes that participate in the epigenetic regulation of gene",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "expression, particularly histone modifications, are differentially methylated in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "blood between persons with and without MCI and AD, warranting further",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MCI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "elucidation of their role in the molecular pathogenesis of cognitive decline.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "eCollection 2025 Jul-Sep.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and cerebral blood flow independent of physical activity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Johnson SC(1)(2), Asthana S(1)(2)(4), Christian BT(3), Cook DB(5)(6), Wieben",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Johnson",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Asthana",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Christian BT(3",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cook",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Wisconsin Alzheimer's Disease Research Center Department of Medicine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Disease Research Center Department of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Public Health Madison Wisconsin USA.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Medical Physics Department of Medicine University of Wisconsin",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Physics Department of Medicine University of Wisconsin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School of Medicine and Public Health Madison Wisconsin USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "School of Medicine and Public Health Madison Wisconsin USA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center William S. Middleton VA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Clinical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "William S. Middleton VA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hospital Madison Wisconsin USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Madison Wisconsin USA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Kinesiology University of Wisconsin School of Education 1300",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kinesiology University of Wisconsin School of Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University Avenue Madison Wisconsin USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University Avenue Madison Wisconsin USA",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)William S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital, Department of Medicine,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6)William",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "S. Middleton Memorial Veterans Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Department of Radiology E3/366 Clinical Science Center University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Radiology E3/366 Clinical Science Center University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: Central arterial stiffness and cerebral blood flow (CBF) are",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "inversely related. Poor cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF) and low physical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activity (PA) are related to both higher arterial stiffness and lower CBF. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "present study examined (i) whether CRF or PA moderate the relationship between",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "arterial stiffness and CBF, and (ii) whether the intensity or the type of PA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "needs to be considered.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Participants (N = 78, MeanAGE = 64.2±6.14, 72% female) from the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "78",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "64.2±6.14",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "72%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Wisconsin Registry for Alzheimer's Prevention and the Wisconsin Alzheimer's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Wisconsin Registry for Alzheimer's Prevention",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Disease Research Center were categorized into low, average, and high fitness",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Disease Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "groups based on maximal graded exercise treadmill test performance. PA was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assessed using the CHAMPS (Community Health Activities Model Program for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the CHAMPS (Community Health Activities Model Program",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Seniors) questionnaire. Based on hours/week, participants were classified as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Based on hours/week",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "meeting the recommended 2.5 h of moderate intensity PA per week (PA Rec Met).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PA Rec Met",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Weekly hours of moderate and low intensity PA were calculated as activities of >",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Weekly hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "PA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "3 or < 3 metabolic equivalents, respectively. Activity type was categorized as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "exercise-, sports/leisure- and work-related. Arterial stiffness was measured as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "aortic pulse wave velocity (aoPWV) by 2D phase contrast magnetic resonance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "imaging (MRI). CBF was assessed by 4D flow MRI in the internal carotid arteries",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(ICAs), cavernous ICAs, middle cerebral arteries (MCAs), and via two composite",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "measures of total and global flow.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The association between aoPWV and CBF differed by fitness levels, with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a negative relationship in the low fitness group and positive relationships in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the average and high fitness groups (all Ps<0.05). Significant moderating",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ps<0.05",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effects on the relationships between aoPWV and CBF were also observed for PA Rec",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Met (all Ps<0.05), moderate intensity (p = 0.05), and exercise-related (all",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ps<0.05",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.05",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "p's < 0.02) PA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "p's < 0.02",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DISCUSSION: Average or high fitness, meeting the PA guidelines, and more",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "specifically, moderate intensity and exercise-related PA seem to attenuate the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "negative relationship between aoPWV on CBF.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "HIGHLIGHTS: Higher cardiorespiratory fitness (CRF) reduces the negative impact",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of aortic pulse wave velocity (aoPWV) on cerebral blood flow (CBF)150 min of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "moderate physical activity (PA) also mitigates this impact, depending on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for aoPWV assessmentInnovative methods: use of free-breathing acquisition during",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cardiac MRIInnovative methods: use of cranial 4D flow MRI for CBF assessment.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "cardiac MRIInnovative",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CBF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Alzheimer's & Dementia: Translational Research & Clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Translational Research & Clinical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Interventions published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Alzheimer's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Wiley Periodicals",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Association.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Dr. Ozioma Okonkwo serves as the treasurer of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ozioma Okonkwo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the International Neuropsychological Society. He is also a guest editor of this",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the International Neuropsychological Society",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "journal but was not involved in the peer‐review process of this article nor had",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "access to any information regarding its peer‐review. Dr. Sterling Johnson serves",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sterling Johnson",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "as a consultant and on advisory boards for ALZPath and Enigma Biosciences. Dr.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ALZPath and",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Enigma Biosciences",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sanjay Asthana receives royalty as an editor of a textbook entitled, Hazzard's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sanjay Asthana",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hazzard",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Geriatrics and Gerontology, McGraw Hill, Publisher. All other authors have no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "McGraw Hill",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chronic ethanol administration exacerbates memory loss by altering",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Anesthesiology, Rutgers University, the State University of New",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Anesthesiology, Rutgers University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the State University of New\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Jersey, Newark, NJ, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jersey",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Newark",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NJ",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, School of Pharmacy, SUNY at Buffalo,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "School of Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Buffalo, NY, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NY",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Division of Gastroenterology, Rutgers University, the State University of New",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gastroenterology, Rutgers University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the State University of New\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Pathology, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pathology, Case Western Reserve University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cleveland",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OH, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "OH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Chronic alcohol use disorder (AUD) is recognized as one of the most",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AUD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "critical risk factors for the progression of Alzheimer's disease (AD).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Epigenetic and neuroimmune alterations are closely associated with the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development of memory impairment related to AUD and AD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AUD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
