[
  {
    "text": "Metagenomic Next-Generation Sequencing Unravels Talaromyces Marneffei-Induced",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Next-Generation Sequencing Unravels Talaromyces Marneffei-Induced",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Bone Destruction in an HIV-Negative Woman: A Case Report with Fatal Outcome.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-Negative Woman",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Spinal Orthopedics, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Guangxi",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Spinal Orthopedics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical University, Nanning, Guangxi, People's Republic of China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanning",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Guangxi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "People's Republic of China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: Talaromycosis is an opportunistic fungal disease caused by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Talaromyces marneffei (TM), a significant pathogen predominantly affecting",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immunocompromised individuals, especially those with HIV infection. Although",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "traditionally regarded as an HIV-associated infection, increasing cases have",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "been reported among HIV-negative patients.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CASE PRESENTATION: This report details a case of a 36-year-old HIV-negative",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "36-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "woman infected with Talaromyces marneffei. The patient presented with bone",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Talaromyces marneffei",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "destruction and was diagnosed through metagenomic next-generation sequencing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(mNGS). Despite receiving antifungal, anti-inflammatory, and symptomatic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment, the infection remained uncontrolled, ultimately progressing to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "multi-organ failure and resulting in death.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Bone damage due to Talaromyces marneffei infection is very uncommon",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Talaromyces marneffei",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in HIV-negative patients. Thus, healthcare providers should be alert for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "possible skeletal lesions linked to this infection. Early diagnosis and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "appropriate antimicrobial treatment are vital for the patient's prognosis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The authors declare that they have no competing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interests in this work.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Retention in HIV Pre-Exposure Prophylaxis Among Men Who Have Sex with Men in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Behavioural Sciences, Muhimbili University of Health and Allied",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Behavioural Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Muhimbili University of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Allied",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Community Medicine and Global Health, University of Oslo, Oslo,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community Medicine and Global Health, University of Oslo, Oslo",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Educational Psychology and Curriculum Studies, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Mbeya College of Health and Allied Sciences, University of Dar Es Salaam,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4)Mbeya College of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Allied Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Dar Es Salaam",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PURPOSE: Men who have sex with men are at high risk of Human immunodeficiency",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "virus (HIV) infection and bear the highest burden of the disease in Tanzania.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tanzania",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Although pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP) has demonstrated high efficacy in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "prevention of HIV infection in clinical trials, challenges with retention",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "threaten its effectiveness. Therefore, we assessed the extent and predictors of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "retention in PrEP care among men who have sex with men in Tanga, Tanzania.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PrEP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tanga",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tanzania",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This study included 369 men who have sex with men who were recruited",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "369",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "using respondent-driven sampling. Baseline data were collected using structured",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "questionnaires that captured socio-demographic and behavioral characteristics.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The primary outcome was one-month retention in PrEP care. A statistical analysis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one-month",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "using modified Poisson regression was conducted to identify independent factors",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Poisson",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with 1-month retention.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1-month",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: A total of 369 men (mean age, 24.7 (± 5.5 years)) participated in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "369",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "24.7",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5.5 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "study. After one month, 87 participants (23.6%) were retained in PrEP care.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one month",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "87",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "23.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Independent factors associated with retention included assuming a receptive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "position in anal sex (aPR 1.6, 95 CI: 1.0-2.6, p = 0.030), having initiated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.0-2.6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.030",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sexual activity with anal, oral, or thigh sex (aPR 2.1, 95% CI: 1.2-3.8, p =",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.2-3.8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "0.011), and having adequate social support (aPR: 1.6, 95% CI: 1.0-2.6, p =",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.011",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.6, 95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.0-2.6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Tailored interventions that improve social support and address the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "varying needs of men who have sex with men with diverse sexual behavior patterns",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "are essential for improving retention and maximizing the effectiveness of PrEP",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PrEP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in HIV prevention. Practically, this highlights the need to strengthen",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "supportive environments within communities and healthcare systems to enhance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "retention in PrEP, reduce HIV transmission, and advance progress toward ending",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PrEP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "HIV as a public health threat by 2030.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2030",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "this work.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "HIV Infection Among Pregnant Women in a Vietnamese Population: Prevalence and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vietnamese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Associated Factors.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Associated Factors",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Vinh Long Department of Health, Vinh Long City, Vietnam.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Long Department of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Long City",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vietnam",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "City, Vietnam.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "City",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vietnam",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Physiology, Faculty of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Pharmacy, Can Tho City, Vietnam.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tho City",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vietnam",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: In pregnant women, HIV infection warrants special attention due to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the high risk of complications during pregnancy and the increased likelihood of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fetal HIV exposure. Consequently, screening for HIV in pregnant women within the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "community and identifying associated risk factors are essential.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: The study aims to investigate the prevalence of HIV infection and the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "associated risk factors in pregnant women.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "MATERIALS AND METHODS: This is a cross-sectional study that utilized convenience",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sampling and was conducted between 2018 and 2020 at 107 commune health stations,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "between 2018 and 2020",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "107",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "8 district health centers, and the Obstetrics Department of Vinh Long Provincial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Obstetrics Department of Vinh Long Provincial",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: A total of 18,034 pregnant women, with a median age of 28 years.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "18,034",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "age of 28 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Fifty-one cases (0.3%) tested positive for HIV. The risk factors associated with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fifty-one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an increased likelihood of HIV infection included having multiple sexual",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "partners, drug addiction, smoking, and engaging in unprotected sex. In the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "multivariate model, only multiple sexual partners, drug addiction and alcohol",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "consumption were independent factors that significantly increased the risk of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "HIV infection among pregnant women.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: The study among pregnant women indicated that the HIV exposure rate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "within the community is below 1.0%. Unsafe sexual behaviors with multiple",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "partners were identified as the most significant risk factor for HIV exposure",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "4. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2025 Jul 2;12(7):ofaf369. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofaf369.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1093",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eCollection 2025 Jul.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eCollection",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025 Jul.",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Prevalence and Risk Factors of Liver Fibrosis Among People With HIV and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Infection and Immunity, Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Infection and Immunity",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Fudan University, Shanghai, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fudan University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanghai",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: We aimed to investigate the prevalence of liver fibrosis and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "identify the associated risk factors among people with HIV (PWH) and metabolic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Abdominal ultrasonography and transient elastography were performed to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assess liver fibrosis and steatosis. Lean MASLD was defined as MASLD occurring",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in PWH with a body mass index (BMI) < 24 kg/m2. A cutoff of liver stiffness",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "24 kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "measurement ≥ 7.1 kPa was set for significant liver fibrosis. The prevalence,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "≥",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "kPa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correlation factors, and risk factors were evaluated.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Among 361 PWH, 250 (69.25%) had a BMI < 24 kg/m2, and 141 (39.06%) were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "361",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "250",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "69.25%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "24 kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      },
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "39.06%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosed with MASLD. The 141 PWH with MASLD were classified as 2 groups based",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "on BMI: 58 (41.13%) as lean MASLD and 83 (58.87%) as overweight MASLD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "58",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "41.13%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "83",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "58.87%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Significant fibrosis was observed in 121 of the 361 PWH, including 75 of the 141",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "121",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "361",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "75",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with MASLD, 28 of the 58 with lean MASLD, and 47 of the 83 with overweight",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MASLD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "58",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "47",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "83",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MASLD. Among PWH with MASLD, independent risk factors for significant liver",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fibrosis included higher alanine aminotransferase levels and the presence of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "type 2 diabetes. Among PWH with lean MASLD, independent risk factors for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant liver fibrosis included elevated aspartate aminotransferase levels",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Significant liver fibrosis is highly prevalent among PWH and MASLD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Multiple risk factors are associated with significant liver fibrosis among PWH.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "These findings underscore the importance of early identification and management",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of liver fibrosis in PWH.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CLINICAL TRIALS REGISTRATION: NCT04215926.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford University Press",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Infectious Diseases Society of America.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Potential conflicts of interest. All authors: No",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reported conflicts. All authors have submitted the ICMJE Form for Disclosure of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Potential Conflicts of Interest.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Potential Conflicts of Interest",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Attomolar Detection of HIV-1 with Label-Free RCA-rCRISPR on Smartphone.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Smartphone",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Human Immunodeficiency Virus-1 (HIV) remains a major global public health",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "challenge, having led to over 42.3 million deaths since its discovery in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "over 42.3 million",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "early 1980s. Despite progress in prevention and treatment, around 60% of people",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "early 1980s",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "around 60%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with HIV (PWH) remain undiagnosed in resource-limited regions,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disproportionately affecting vulnerable populations and underserved communities",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "across the world. This illustrates the critical need for accessible, accurate,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and equipment-free diagnostic tools to enhance detection and thus provide",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "opportunities to curb its spread. Here, we developed a low-cost, robust, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "label-free rolling circle amplification (RCA)-rCRISPR diagnostic platform for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RCA)-rCRISPR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "detecting HIV viral load with minimal instrumentation. Our strategy, combining",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the integration of RNA-detecting RCA reaction with plasmid reporter-based",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RCA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ratiometric CRISPR (rCRISPR), enables sensitive detection of unprocessed RNA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRISPR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "rCRISPR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "targets without the need for intensive sample pre-treatment. This label-free",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RCA-rCRISPR diagnostic platform detected HIV RNA down to single-digit aM",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RCA-rCRISPR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sensitivity (~3000 copies/mL) from PWH-derived HIV samples ex vivo . Unlike",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "typical RCA, which requires sample fragmentations to break long RNA target",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RCA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sequences, our design harnesses the triple functions of the phi29 DNA polymerase",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(namely exonuclease activity, polymerization, and strand displacement), enabling",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the detection of the entire HIV genome without pre-fragmentation. For",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "point-of-care (POC) applications, we constructed an all-in-one smartphone-based",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "testing, making it accessible to resource-limited communities. Additionally, the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assay has demonstrated the ability for point mutation detection ( BRAF mutation",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BRAF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in canine urothelial carcinoma), showcasing the robustness of our strategy for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "broad disease diagnostic applications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The soluble HIV-1 Vpu protein interacts with calmodulin in a Ca (2+) -dependent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-1 Vpu protein interacts with calmodulin",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ca",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The HIV-1-encoded membrane protein Vpu plays key roles in virus lifecycle. Our",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lab recently revealed a soluble form of Vpu, and we strived to determine its",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "possible physiological function. Here, we provide solid experimental proof that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "soluble Vpu interacts with Ca 2+ -bound calmodulin (Ca 2+ -CaM). A putative",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2+ -bound",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CaM-binding motif in Vpu was predicted, but there was no experimental evidence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of the Vpu-CaM association. We applied double electron electron-resonance (DEER)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Vpu-CaM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and protein spin labeling to detect the soluble Vpu-CaM complex. We found that",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vpu-CaM",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "soluble full-length and truncated C-terminal region of Vpu directly interact",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with Ca 2+ -CaM. DEER results from the spin-labeled double cysteine mutant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "S39C/A103C of CaM showed that upon association with Vpu Ca 2+ -CaM adopts a more",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "S39C/A103C",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CaM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2+",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "closed conformation compared to those in the absence of Vpu. This restructuring",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is in agreement with previously observed Ca 2+ -CaM association with cellular",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2+ -CaM",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and other HIV-1 proteins. Our results indicate that soluble Vpu and CaM form an",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CaM",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in Vpu C-terminal region suggest that Vpu's helices 2 and 3 move away from each",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vpu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "other to facilitated CaM binding. These observations tell that under",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CaM",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "physiological conditions the soluble Vpu-CaM complex may provide Vpu with a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "trafficking pathway to membrane destination.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Rapid acquisition of HIV-1 neutralization breadth in a rhesus V2 apex germline",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "V2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "antibody mouse model after a single bolus immunization.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Amereh K, Avillion G, Bottermann M, Liang B, Chaudhary N, Callaghan S, Dye J, Li",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Amereh K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Avillion G",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bottermann M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liang B",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chaudhary N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Callaghan S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Dye J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Li",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "X, Ellis-Pugh JR, Chowdhury RR, James NE, Liu X, Maiorino L, Maldonado P,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chowdhury RR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "James NE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Liu X",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maiorino L",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maldonado P",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BH, Burton DR, Shapiro L, Kwong PD, Irvine DJ, Andrabi R, Shaw GM, Batista FD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Burton DR",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shapiro L",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kwong PD",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Irvine DJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shaw GM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Batista FD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Current vaccine strategies to elicit broadly neutralizing antibodies (bnAbs)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "against HIV-1 generally propose complex, multi-boost immunization regimens. In",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HIV-1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "rhesus macaques, SHIV infection has been observed to rapidly drive the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development of some classes of bnAbs that share structural similarities with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "those in humans. Here, we generated a knockin mouse model with B cells bearing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the unmutated common ancestor (UCA) of the V2 apex-targeted bnAb lineage,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "UCA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "V2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "V033-a. A single immunization of mice with a germline-targeting native-like",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "V033-a.",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "trimer was sufficient to recapitulate the ontogeny of the mature rhesus bnAb in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "rhesus bnAb",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "knockin mice-including rare, disfavored somatic mutations-leading to the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "knockin mice-including",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "induction of antibodies that exhibited potent neutralization against both",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "autologous and heterologous tier 2 viruses. A boost with Env escape mutant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "trimers further improved breadth and potency, and cryo-EM structure revealed the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "structural basis for heterologous neutralization breadth. Non-human primate and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mouse models can thus combine with structure to serve as a platform for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mouse",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "identifying and confirming immunogens that streamline HIV-vaccination regimens.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Dolutegravir Developmental Toxicity is Mitigated by Magnesium and Folate in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mitigated by Magnesium",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Folate",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Zebrafish Embryos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Zebrafish Embryos",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Integrase-strand-transfer inhibitors have transformed HIV therapy, yet the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "widely prescribed drug dolutegravir (DTG) has been linked to developmental",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "toxicity and its teratogenic mechanism remains uncertain. Here we use zebrafish",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to dissect DTG toxicity during early vertebrate development. DTG exposure from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2-4 h post-fertilization (hpf) to 24 hpf produced high mortality and abnormal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "24",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "morphology; co-treatment with folic acid or 5-methyltetrahydrofolate partially",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "restored normal morphology, whereas calcium had no effect. Strikingly,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "supplementation with magnesium (Mg) rescued DTG-exposed embryos almost as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effectively as folate, implicating magnesium availability in protection. In",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "competitive binding assays, Mg increased binding of folate to purified folate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mg",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "receptor (FOLR1) by 30% in the presence of DTG. Maternal-zygotic zebrafish folr1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FOLR1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "30%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "folr1\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mutant embryos contained significantly less endogenous folate than wild-type",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "embryos yet displayed marked hypersensitivity to DTG that could not be mitigated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by folate supplementation. Together, these findings reveal a dual mechanism in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "which DTG antagonizes FOLR1 while concurrently sequestering Mg. Excess Mg",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "FOLR1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mg",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Excess Mg",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "converts DTG into a Mg-bound DTG complex that can no longer antagonize FOLR1,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "FOLR1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thereby restoring normal development. Our work identifies magnesium status as a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "modifiable determinant of DTG teratogenicity and provides a proof-of-concept",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DTG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "zebrafish model that could be adapted for rapid in vivo screening of integrase",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inhibitors for developmental phenotypes.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Virus glycoprotein nanodisc platform for vaccine design.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Transmembrane glycoproteins of enveloped viruses are the targets of neutralizing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Transmembrane",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "antibodies and essential vaccine antigens. mRNA-LNP technology allows in situ",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "production of transmembrane glycoproteins upon immunization, but biophysical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characterization of transmembrane antigens and in vitro analysis of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "post-immunization antibody responses typically rely on soluble proteins. Here,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "we present a methodological platform for assembling transmembrane glycoprotein",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "transmembrane glycoprotein",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "vaccine candidates into lipid nanodiscs. We demonstrate the utility of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development by binding assays using surface plasmon resonance (SPR), ex vivo B",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SPR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cell sorting with fluorescence-activated cell sorting (FACS), and by determining",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FACS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the structure of a prototypical HIV MPER-targeting immunogen nanodisc in complex",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with three broadly neutralizing antibodies (bnAbs), including the MPER bnAb",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "MPER",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "10E8, to 3.5 Å by cryogenic electron microscopy (cryo-EM), providing a template",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10E8",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "3.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "cryogenic",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for structure-based immunogen design for MPER. Overall, the platform offers a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tool for accelerating the development of next-generation viral vaccines.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "10. Health Sci Rep. 2025 Jul 15;8(7):e71076. doi: 10.1002/hsr2.71076. eCollection",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1002",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "HIV and Maternal-Fetal Immunity: Challenges and Strategies for Reducing Vertical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Transmission-A Narrative Review.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Transmission-A Narrative Review",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Biomedical and Laboratory Science Africa University Mutare",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Biomedical and Laboratory Science Africa University Mutare",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND AND AIMS: Mother-to-child transmission (MTCT) of HIV remains a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MTCT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The virus disrupts maternal-fetal immunity through immune dysregulation,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "placental barrier impairment, and altered antibody transfer, thereby increasing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the risk of vertical transmission.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS AND RESULTS: This narrative review synthesizes current evidence on the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immunological and clinical factors influencing MTCT. It highlights how maternal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MTCT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immune exhaustion, placental inflammation, and suboptimal ART timing contribute",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to transmission. While widespread use of ART has reduced MTCT rates, persistent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MTCT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "challenges include late ART initiation, HIV drug resistance, co-infections, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transmission through breastfeeding. Emerging strategies-such as maternal immune",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "modulation, monoclonal antibody therapies, and tailored ART regimens-show",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "potential for further risk reduction.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: To effectively minimize MTCT, comprehensive prevention approaches",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MTCT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "are essential. These should combine medical interventions with maternal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "nutrition support, co-infection management, and safe breastfeeding practices",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "under ART coverage. A multifaceted strategy is key to protecting both maternal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ART",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and infant health.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Health Science Reports published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wiley Periodicals",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LLC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: The author declares no conflicts of interest.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A paradigm shift in simulating affinity maturation to elicit broadly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Biomedical Engineering Graduate Program, University of Colorado Boulder,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Engineering Graduate Program",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Colorado Boulder",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Boulder, CO, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boulder, CO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Boulder, Boulder, CO, United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Boulder",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Boulder, CO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Broadly neutralizing antibodies (bnAbs) offer a promising route to protect",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "against rapidly evolving pathogens such as HIV, influenza, and SARS-CoV-2, yet",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "eliciting them through vaccination remains a significant challenge. A key to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "this problem lies in understanding antibody affinity maturation (AM), the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evolutionary process within germinal centers (GCs) that shapes the B cell and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thus antibody response. Traditionally, AM has been viewed as favoring the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "selection of B cells with the highest-affinity B cell receptors (BCRs) through",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "competitive interplays. However, emerging evidence suggests that GCs are more",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "permissive, allowing B cells with a broad range of affinities to persist,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thereby promoting clonal diversity and enabling the rare emergence of bnAbs.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "bnAbs",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "This review reassesses affinity-based selection models and proposes a new",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "paradigm that integrates multifactorial processes, including stochastic B cell",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decisions within GC dynamics, antigen extraction efficiency influenced by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "probabilistic bond rupture, and avidity-driven BCR binding alterations and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "representations on multivalent antigens. We highlight how advanced AM",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "simulations that move beyond affinity as the sole determinant provide a more",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "realistic and predictive representation of AM, marking a major step forward in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "developing strategies to promote effective immune responses against highly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Nakarin and Sprenger.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sprenger",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "12. ACS Med Chem Lett. 2025 Jun 10;16(7):1340-1345. doi:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10;16(7):1340-1345",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "10.1021/acsmedchemlett.5c00214. eCollection 2025 Jul 10.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1021",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Effects of Oxygen Atom Position in Linear Side Chains of Ansellone Analogues on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Osaka University, 1-6 Yamadaoka",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1)Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Osaka University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Environmental and Molecular Health Sciences, Faculty of Medical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Environmental and Molecular Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Medical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Kumamoto University, 5-1 Oe-honmachi, Chuo-ku,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kumamoto University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chuo-ku",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Wakayama Medical University, 25-1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wakayama Medical University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Antiretroviral therapy can manage HIV infections, but a cure remains elusive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "owing to viral latency. The \"shock and kill\" strategy uses latency-reversing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "agents (LRAs) to reactivate viral production toward eliminating latent HIV.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "However, developing novel LRA scaffolds remains a critical challenge. This study",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LRA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "focused on a structurally simplified hydrobenzopyran analogue of ansellone A, a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "natural product with latency-reversing activity. To investigate the influence of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "incorporating ether oxygen into the alkyl chain, thought to anchor to the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "biological membrane, on the biological activity, we designed and synthesized a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "series of hydrobenzopyran analogs with varying oxygen positions in their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lipophilic side chains. Biological evaluation in J-Lat 10.6 and TZM-bl cells",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed that the oxygen atom position did not considerably influence the HIV",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "latency-reversing activity. Furthermore, none of the compounds affected cell",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viability. These findings suggest that ether-containing hydrobenzopyran",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "derivatives represent a viable and synthetically flexible scaffold for the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "development of novel LRAs.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Associations between ZIP code-level alcohol outlet density and binge drinking",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "among people who inject drugs in 22 US Metropolitan Areas.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "US",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Peddireddy SR, Beane S, Yarbrough C, Ibragimov U, Cummings JR, Haley DF, Linton",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Peddireddy SR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Beane S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yarbrough C",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ibragimov U",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cummings JR",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Haley DF",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Linton",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SL, Cooper HLF.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cooper HLF",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Although alcohol outlet density (AOD) is associated with drinking",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "behaviors in the general population, little evidence exists about this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "relationship among people who inject drugs (PWID). Establishing this connection",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "is particularly important, as alcohol use exacerbates the risk of opioid",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and binge drinking among PWID who use opioids, and 2) the potential moderating",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effect of race/ethnicity on the AOD-binge drinking relationship.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This analysis linked 2018 National HIV Behavioral Surveillance (NHBS)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "National HIV Behavioral Surveillance",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "data and 2016 ZIP code-level AOD data from the ZIP Code Business Pattern survey.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2016",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the ZIP Code Business Pattern",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hierarchical generalized linear models quantified the association between AOD",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and binge drinking, overall and by race/ethnicity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Of 9,660 PWID, 27% reported recent binge drinking. For Hispanic/Latinx",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9,660",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "27%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hispanic",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and White PWID, increases in AOD were associated with a 1% and 3% increase in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1% and",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "3%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the odds of binge drinking, respectively (p < 0.05); AOD was unrelated to binge",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "drinking among Black PWID. However, when AOD was set to the median, binge",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "drinking probability was highest among Black PWID (PP: 0.28, 95% CI: 0.24-0.33).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PP",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.24-0.33",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Reducing AOD may decrease binge drinking among White and Latinx",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Latinx",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PWID. Our results suggest, however, that this strategy alone may be not be",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effective among Black PWID. Holistic strategies targeting structural",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "determinants of alcohol and opioid co-use among Black PWID are needed to address",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inequities in drug-related harms.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ZIP code-level alcohol outlet density and nonfatal overdose among people who",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inject drugs in 22 US metropolitan statistical areas: a multilevel modeling",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "US",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Alcohol outlet density (AOD) is associated with drinking behaviors",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and related harms across several populations. As alcohol consumption compounds",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the depressive effects of opioids to increase overdose risk among people who",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inject drugs (PWID), this study investigated 1) whether off-premise AOD is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with the risk of nonfatal overdose among a large sample of PWID, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2) whether this relationship varies by individual race/ethnicity.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We linked individual-level 2018 National HIV Behavioral Surveillance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NHBS) data with ZIP code-level data on off-premise AOD in 2016 from the US",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2016",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "US",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Census Bureau's ZIP Code Business Pattern survey. NHBS surveys PWID across 22",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Census Bureau's",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ZIP Code Business Pattern",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "22",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "metropolitan statistical areas. Hierarchical generalized linear models",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "quantified the association between AOD and nonfatal overdose, overall and by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PWID race/ethnicity.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The sample comprised 9,764 PWID who used opioids, 45% of whom were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9,764",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "45%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "non-Hispanic/Latinx White, 38% non-Hispanic/Latinx Black, and 18%",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "non-Hispanic",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "38%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "non-Hispanic",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "18%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hispanic/Latinx. Over a quarter (28%) experienced an overdose in the past year.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hispanic/Latinx",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "28%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "the past year",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The median outlet density was 4.0 outlets per square mile. The adjusted model",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4.0",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "did not show a significant relationship between AOD and odds of overdose (OR:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "1.01, 95% CI: 1.00-1.02), and the relationship remained null in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1.01",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.00-1.02",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "race/ethnicity interaction model.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Regulating AOD alone may not effectively mitigate overdose risk",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "among PWID. Future research should explore why overdoses among PWID are not",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sensitive to changes in AOD. Possible explanations to consider are whether (1)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AOD is unassociated with alcohol consumption among PWID, or (2) PWID stagger the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWID",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "timing of their alcohol consumption so it does not coincide with opioid",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "15. Oxf Med Case Reports. 2025 Jul 14;2025(7):omaf104. doi: 10.1093/omcr/omaf104.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1093",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A case of classic epidermodysplasia verruciformis associated with elephantiasis:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "an atypical presentation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Dermatology-Venereology, Mohamed VI University Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dermatology-Venereology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mohamed VI University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Faculty of Medicine and Pharmacy, M3MF+GCG, 90100, La Nouvelle Ville Ibn",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine and Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "90100",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Epidermodysplasia verruciformis (EV) is a rare genetic skin disorder",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Epidermodysplasia",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "characterized by increased susceptibility to human papillomavirus infections",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(HPV) and a high risk of cutaneous carcinomas. We report the case of a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "30-year-old female patient presenting with diffuse verrucous lesions,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30-year-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "predominantly affecting the extremities, associated with unilateral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "elephantiasis. The diagnosis was histologically confirmed, revealing vulgar",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "warts consistent with EV. HIV serology was negative, and systemic retinoid",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "therapy was initiated. EV is linked to mutations in the EVER1 and EVER2 genes,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EVER1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "EVER2",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "predisposing patients to chronic infections with specific HPV types. Close",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HPV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "monitoring is crucial to prevent malignant transformation. This case highlights",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the diagnostic and therapeutic challenges of EV, emphasizing the importance of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "an appropriate management strategy to control lesions and prevent complications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford University Press",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "interests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "10.1177/08850666251359546. Online ahead of print.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.1177/08850666251359546",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Severe Community-Acquired Pneumonia: Impact of HIV on Clinical Presentation,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Microbiological and Laboratory Findings, and Outcome.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Venturas JP(1), Titus A(2), Richards GA(3), Feldman C(4).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Venturas JP(1",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Titus A(2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Richards",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Feldman C(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the Witwatersrand Medical School, Johannesburg, South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Witwatersrand Medical School",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johannesburg",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "South Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Independent Statistician, Johannesburg, South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Independent",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Statistician",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johannesburg",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "South Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Dept of Surgery, Division of Critical Care, Faculty of Health Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Surgery, Division of Critical Care, Faculty of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of the Witwatersrand",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johannesburg",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "South Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Witwatersrand",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johannesburg",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "South Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Severe community-acquired pneumonia (SCAP) is associated with significant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "morbidity and mortality, but there is a paucity of data regarding these",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infections in sub-Saharan Africa, especially among people living with HIV",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(PLWH). This study investigated the impact of HIV on clinical presentation,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "microbial aetiology, laboratory findings, and outcome of SCAP. This was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "microbial aetiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SCAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "additional analysis of data from a large, single-centre, retrospective,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "observational study conducted among consecutive adult patients (≥18 years)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "admitted to the multidisciplinary ICU at the Charlotte Maxeke Johannesburg",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ICU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Charlotte Maxeke Johannesburg\n",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Academic Hospital, between 1 July 2007 and 31 May 2019, with SCAP. The current",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Academic Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "between 1 July 2007",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "31 May 2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "SCAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "study describes 718 PLWH and 131 HIV-negative cases extracted from the initial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "718",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "131",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cohort. The median age was 37 [IQR 30-46] years with PLWH significantly younger",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "37",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IQR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "than their HIV-negative counterparts (36 years [IQR 29-44] years vs 52 years",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "36 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IQR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "52 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "[IQR 34-65] years; P < .001). PLWH were more commonly female (P = .053), while",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "P < .001",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": ".053",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "more of the HIV-negative patients were male. The median CD4 count of the PLWH",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was 42 [IQR 14-108] cells/mm3 and only 15.5% were on anti-retroviral therapy",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "42",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IQR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "only 15.5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(ART) prior to hospitalisation. Differences were noted in clinical, laboratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and radiological features between the groups. Overall, Mycobacterium",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tuberculosis was the most common microbial aetiology in both groups, followed by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mortality, whereas mortality with Pneumocystis jirovecii infection, which",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pneumocystis",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "occurred only in PLWH, was high. Overall ICU mortality was high (48.9%), and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ICU",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "48.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "while HIV was an independent risk factor for mortality (OR 0.58, 95% CI",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.58",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "0.37-0.92; p = .02) on univariate analysis, this finding was not true when HIV",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.37",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "considered within the multivariable analysis. This study describes one of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "largest cohorts of PLWH with SCAP and compares their findings with HIV-negative",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PLWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SCAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cases. HIV was not a significant predictor of mortality when considered in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "context of other covariables on multivariable analysis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "17. J Int Assoc Provid AIDS Care. 2025 Jan-Dec;24:23259582251358929. doi:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "17",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Int Assoc",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Epidemiology of Antiretroviral Therapy Related Adverse Drug Reactions and its",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Predictors Among Patients with Human Immunodeficiency Virus/AIDS in Ethiopia: A",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Systematic Review",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Pharmacy Education and Clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmacology and Toxicology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pharmacy Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Services Directorate, College of Health Sciences, Debre Tabor University, Debre",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "College of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Debre Tabor University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Clinical Pharmacy, Pharmacy Education and Clinical Services",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pharmacy Education",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Clinical Services",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Directorate, College of Health Sciences, Debre Tabor University, Debre Tabor,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Directorate, College of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Debre Tabor University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ObjectiveAdverse drug reactions (ADRs) induce iatrogenic harm in antiretroviral",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ObjectiveAdverse",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "therapy (ART) care continuum. However, there is a dearth of concrete evidence in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "a resource-limited setting. Thus, this study was designed to consolidate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "existing knowledge, thereby informing policy and clinical care to improve",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patient safety.DesignSystematic review and meta-analysis.Data sourcesPubMed,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CINAHL, Web of Science, and EMBASE databases were searched.Eligibility",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EMBASE",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "criteriaEmploying the condition, context, and population framework,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "observational primary studies were included.Data extraction and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "synthesisIndependent reviewers undertook data extraction and synthesis. This",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "synthesisIndependent",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "meta-analysis employed the random-effects restricted maximum likelihood (REML)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "method, with its protocol preregistered on the International Register of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the International Register of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Systematic Reviews (CRD42024546390).ResultsThe pooled prevalence of ADRs was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "36.7% [95% CI: 26.6-46.9, I2 = 99.64%].ConclusionAltogether, this study revealed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "36.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "26.6-46.9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that ART-related ADRs in Ethiopia was 36.7%, underscoring rigorous monitoring.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "36.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Giving special emphasis to patients with female gender, advanced disease,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "comorbidities, malnutrition, TB treatment, and poor adherence is a prudent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Plain Language Summary: Epidemiology of ART-related Adverse Drug Reactions among",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Adverse Drug Reactions",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Patients with HIV/AIDS in Ethiopia: A Systematic Review and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Meta-analysisMedicines are crucial in the arena of the healthcare system.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Despite the undeniable relevance of medicines, a substantial challenge is the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "potential for harmful drug reactions when used. Antiretroviral therapy (ART) is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the application of antiretroviral medicines to combat human immunodeficiency",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "virus (HIV). While it is pivotal in treating diseases, it is plugged with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "adverse drug reactions (ADRs). ADRs are harmful effects that can occur when",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "people take medications. These undesirable drug effects are quite common and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "especially costly in the treatment of HIV. In countries with limited healthcare",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resources, there is limited information about how common these harmful effects",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "are. This study aimed to bring together the available evidence about the rate of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ADRs related to ART among people living with HIV in Ethiopia. In this study, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ethiopia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reviewed the results of 29 studies involving 19,003 people living with HIV. We",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "29",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "19,003",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "found that about 4 in every 10 patients (36.7%) experienced ADRs from their",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "about 4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "36.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "treatment. Our analysis also showed that certain groups, including women, those",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with lower education levels, advanced HIV disease, other chronic health",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "problems, weaker immune systems (low CD4 counts), opportunistic infections,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malnutrition, and those taking medications containing zidovudine or nevirapine,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were more likely to face these ADRs. Patients receiving tuberculosis treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "at the same time or struggling with medication adherence were also at higher",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "risk. Based on these findings, special attention should be given to monitoring",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "these vulnerable groups to catch and manage ADRs early.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665675 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665675",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe authors",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "authorship, and/or publication of this article. Data Availability StatementWe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Availability StatementWe",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "have provided all crude data that was utilized in this investigation as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "individuals living with HIV/AIDS and mental disorders.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Studies focusing on individuals living with HIV and mental disorders are crucial",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to inform and enhance care for this inherently vulnerable population group,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "especially considering that people living with HIV/AIDS (PLHIV) are more likely",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to develop mental disorders compared to the general population, contributing to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lower adherence to antiretroviral therapy (ART). This study cross-sectional",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Sul, Brazil. Patient-reported data from PLHIV who received care in at least one",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Brazil",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLHIV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "at least one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of the Psychosocial Care Network facilities of the Brazilian Unified Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Psychosocial Care Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Brazilian Unified Health\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "System from 2014 to 2018 were collected to assess the adherence to ART. Among",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2014",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2018",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the 76 participants eligible, 35 were included in the study. Substance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "76",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "35",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "use-related mental disorders were the most prevalent (45.7%), followed by mood",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "45.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "disorders (25.7%) and anxiety (11.4%). Most of the participants had a low ART",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "11.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "adherence (62.9%), followed by insufficient adherence (22.9%) and good adherence",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "62.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "22.9%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the study variables. Our findings suggest the importance of assessing adherence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "based on both direct and indirect measures, as biological markers and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "self-report.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025. The Author(s).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PMID: 40665443 [Indexed for MEDLINE]",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40665443",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate: This study was approved by the Human Subject Research Ethics",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Human Subject Research Ethics",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Committee of the Federal University of Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil (protocol",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Federal University of Mato Grosso",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sul",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Brazil",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "number: 3,416,555; CAAE: 15431819.3.0000.0021). All procedures were performed in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3,416,555",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. Informed consent was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "obtained from all participants. The interviewers took care to explain the study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clearly, using accessible language appropriate to the intellectual and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "educational level of each individual. Competing interests: We have read the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "journal’s policy and the authors of this manuscript have the following competing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "journal",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "interests: EFO serves as an Editorial Board Member of BMC Public Health.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Editorial Board",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMC Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "19. Br J Dermatol. 2025 Jul 16:ljaf213. doi: 10.1093/bjd/ljaf213. Online ahead of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "19",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Br J Dermatol",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "16",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1093",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Prurigo nodularis: disease burden, clinical features and approach to management.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Maryland, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Maryland",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Institute of Allergology, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, corporate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Fraunhofer Institute for Translational Medicine and Pharmacology ITMP,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institute for Translational Medicine and Pharmacology ITMP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Immunology and Allergology Berlin, Berlin, Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Allergology Berlin",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Berlin",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Dermatology, French Expert Itch Center, University Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "French",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Itch Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Dermatology, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dermatology, University of Pennsylvania Perelman School",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Regeneron Pharmaceuticals Inc., Tarrytown, New York, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "7)Regeneron Pharmaceuticals Inc.",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tarrytown",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "New York",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Sanofi, Reading, UK.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Reading",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "UK",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Prurigo nodularis (PN) is a distinct, chronic inflammatory skin disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characterised by intensely pruritic, fibrotic nodular lesions. Despite continued",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "progress in the field, lack of clarity regarding the definition of PN as a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disease, clinical presentation and therapeutic options results in delayed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosis and management. PN can arise following other diseases, but once",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "established, it is an independent disease. Here, we summarise the current",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "knowledge of epidemiology, clinical characteristics, disease burden and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "management approaches that may help healthcare providers recognise PN as a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "primary diagnosis independent of triggers or associated comorbidities. PN is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "more common among patients aged 50-60 years, and some evidence suggests it is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "50-60 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "more frequent among Black populations than White and Asian populations. A subset",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Asian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of PN patients have an atopic background and can present with comorbid atopic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dermatitis; however, PN can also exist without atopic comorbidities. Other",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "comorbidities typically include diabetes, obesity, thyroid disease, kidney",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disease, chronic liver disease, hypertension, HIV infection, skin infections,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "malignancies and mental health disorders. Multiple intensely pruritic lesions",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "induce chronic scratching, which leads to inflammation, hyperkeratotic nodules",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and perpetuation of a vicious itch-scratch cycle. PN is associated with a high",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disease burden and negative effect on quality of life; patients often report",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "intense and relentless itching, poor sleep, absence from work, anxiety and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "depression. Early diagnosis of PN and identification of comorbidities are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "important to facilitate better disease management. By increasing their awareness",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of PN epidemiology, disease burden, clinical presentation and management,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "physicians may begin to identify the disease as a distinct condition independent",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of its triggers or associated comorbidities and provide patients with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "appropriate care earlier in their treatment journeys.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of British",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford University Press",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "British",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Association of Dermatologists. All rights reserved. For commercial re-use,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Association of Dermatologists",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "via the Permissions link on the article page on our site—for further information",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Permissions",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "journals.permissions@oup.com",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "20. BMC Womens Health. 2025 Jul 16;25(1):349. doi: 10.1186/s12905-025-03876-z.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "20",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMC Womens Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "16;25(1):349",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1186",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Incidence and predictors of pregnancy among reproductive-age women in an ART",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clinic of public health facilities in Arsi zone, southeastern ethiopia: a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Arsi zone",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "five-year retrospective cohort study.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "five-year",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SM(3), Aseffa M(4), Tadesse BL(5).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Aseffa",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tadesse",
