[
  {
    "text": "1. Recent Adv Inflamm Allergy Drug Discov. 2025;19(2):259-268. doi:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025;19(2):259-268",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A Comparative Study of Dexamethasone and Methylprednisolone in COVID-19",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Patients: Clinical Outcomes and Inflammatory Markers.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Student Research Committee, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mashhad",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)School of Pharmacy, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmacy, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mashhad",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Lung Diseases Research Center, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Diseases Research Center, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Pharmaceutical Nanotechnology, School of Pharmacy, Mashhad",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutical Nanotechnology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "School of Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mashhad",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Clinical Research Development Unit, Ghaem Hospital, Mashhad University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Development Unit",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ghaem Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mashhad University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: The Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, prompted by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Coronavirus",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2, has created complicated health crises. An excessive inflammatory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "response and cytokine storm characterize severe COVID-19. Corticosteroids like",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dexamethasone and methylprednisolone are used for their anti-inflammatory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effects, but comparisons of their efficacy are lacking.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: This study seeks to rigorously assess and contrast the effectiveness",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of dexamethasone and methylprednisolone in combating COVID-19 infections.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: This retrospective clinical study evaluates the effects of these two",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "corticosteroids by reviewing the files of 500 hospitalized COVID-19 patients.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "500",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The baseline characteristics of the patients, chest CT severity score, type of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "steroid prescription, duration of hospitalization and steroid prescription,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dosage of corticosteroid therapy, their recovery status, hospital mortality, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "specific disease severity-associated markers, such as lactate dehydrogenase",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(LDH), complete blood count (CBC), C-reactive protein (CRP), and Erythrocyte",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CRP",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Erythrocyte",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sedimentation rate (ESR) were collected and compared.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ESR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The study found no significant difference in most disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "severity-associated markers between the two corticosteroid groups. However,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lower mortality rates and shortened hospital stays were significantly associated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with dexamethasone, especially in critical patient groups. A detailed analysis",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of inflammatory markers suggested minimal differences based on the type of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: The study indicates that dexamethasone may have some advantages in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "specific clinical outcomes. Further research needs to explore the mechanisms",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright© Bentham Science Publishers; For any queries, please email at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bentham Science Publishers",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A data-mining analysis of host solute carrier family proteins in SARS-CoV-2",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infection with reference to brain endothelial cells and the blood-brain barrier",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in COVID-19.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Schmidt College of Medicine, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "College of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Florida Atlantic University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Boca Raton",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "FL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "United States.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: The brain vasculature is a key player in neurological manifestations",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of COVID-19. Infection of brain endothelial cells with SARS-CoV-2 along with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "circulating cytokines may cause dysfunction of the blood-brain barrier (BBB).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Solute carrier transporters (SLCs) in brain endothelial cells regulate substrate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transport across the BBB. Here, it was hypothesized that transport functions of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SLCs will be impaired by interactions with viral proteins, and subsequently,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Virus-host protein-protein interaction data for SARS-CoV-2 infection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were retrieved from the BioGRID database, filtered for SLCs, and then annotated",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for relevant expression in brain endothelial cells using a mouse brain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transcriptomics database. Host SLCs expressed in brain endothelial cells were",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "further explored using publicly available databases and information in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "literature. Functional Annotation Clustering was performed using DAVID, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Functional Annotation Clustering",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "DAVID",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Enrichr served for pathway analysis. Substrates were retrieved from NCBI Gene.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Enrichr",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Links to monogenic disorders were retrieved from Online Mendelian Inheritance in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Online Mendelian Inheritance",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Man™ and screened for disorders of the nervous system. Interactome data for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viral proteins of SARS-CoV-2 were retrieved from BioGRID. Reports for host SLCs",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in viral receptor functions, viral entry mechanisms, and other major roles in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the viral cycle were explored in databases (VThunter) and literature.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ATP-binding cassette transporters (ABCs) were studied in parallel.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: N = 80 host SLCs showed relevant expression in brain endothelial cells",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "80",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "whereby amino acid transporter stood out. N = 24/80 host SLCs were linked to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "24/80",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "monogenic disorders of the nervous system. N = 9/29 SARS-CoV-2 viral proteins",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9/29",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "had strong links to SLCs and key functions in viral infection (e.g., interferon",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "interferon\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "response). SLCs serving as viral receptors and with closely associated functions",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were significantly enriched among all known listed viral receptors (chi-square",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "test, p = 0.001). Literature searches for host SLCs revealed involvement of a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.001",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "subset of SLCs in infection mechanisms for SARS-CoV-2 and more broadly for other",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viruses. N = 17 host ABCs were found in brain endothelial cells where they may",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "17",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DISCUSSION: This hypothesis-generating work proposes a set of N = 80 host SLCs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "80",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expressed in endothelial cells as contributors to BBB impairment after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2 infection. Theoretically, persistent dysfunction of SLCs at the BBB,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BBB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in particular insufficient transport of amino acids, could be one of many",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reasons for cognitive changes in long-COVID. Functions of SLCs in viral entry",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and associated roles deserve close attention.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "School-informed risk calculator tool for reducing the spread of respiratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viral infection among school-aged children.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Wilson AM(1), Lowe AA(2)(3), Amoh-Asante NAA(1), Zhan Y(1), Ashraf A(1), Gerald",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Wilson",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lowe AA(2)(3",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Amoh-Asante NAA(1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zhan",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gerald\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Community, Environment & Policy, Mel and Enid Zuckerman College",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community, Environment & Policy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Enid Zuckerman College",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Public Health, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Public Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Arizona",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tucson",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AZ",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Nursing & Health Sciences Division, College of Nursing, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Nursing & Health Sciences Division",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Asthma & Airway Disease Research Center, Tucson, AZ, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Asthma & Airway Disease Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tucson",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "AZ",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Office of Population Health Sciences, Office of the Vice Chancellor for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Population Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "School health staff need decision support for responding to respiratory viral",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "outbreaks. Quantitative microbial risk assessment (QMRA) tools are an",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inexpensive and fast resource. Our objectives were to engage school districts to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "inform the development of a risk-based calculator tool, test the tool across",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hypothetical cases, and elicit feedback among school health staff. We",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "administered an online survey for Kindergarten (K) - Grade 5 teachers, school",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kindergarten",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "health professionals, and other school staff to gather data about respiratory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viral disease interventions and model parameters. A risk calculator tool was",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "developed in which users choose hypothetical scenarios to estimate infection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "risk per individual and compare interventions. Three case studies (CS) were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "explored: CS1 - Rhinovirus transmission in a general education classroom with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "\"poor\" vs. \"great\" air quality, CS2 - Influenza A virus transmission in a music",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "classroom with vs. without a portable air purifier, CS3 - SARS-CoV-2",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transmission in a special education classroom with vs. without open",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "doors/windows. The prototype tool was presented at a national school nursing",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "meeting, and attendees were surveyed on (dis)likes and anticipated tool uses.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "dis)likes",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "For the initial survey of Arizona school personnel (n = 132), the top",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Arizona",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "132",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory viral outbreak strategies reported by teachers were hand (94 %) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "94 %",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "surface hygiene (85.1 %). For all case studies, infection risks were above",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "85.1 %",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "thresholds used in other contexts but were comparable to published student",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory illness incidence data. At the national meeting, school nurses (n =",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "12) identified potential uses including advocating for interventions to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "administrators. This work reflects a unique application of community partnership",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and QMRA to address school health decision support.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Identifying Key Hub Genes that Attribute Varying Host Responses: A Longitudinal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RNA-seq Analysis of SARS-CoV-2 Delta and Omicron Infections.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Omicron Infections",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Bajracharya D, Jansen RJ, Yan C, Ramamoorthy S.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bajracharya D",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jansen RJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ramamoorthy S.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by SARS-CoV-2, has severely impacted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Coronavirus",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "global health, with different Variants of Concern (VOCs) resulting in varied",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Variants of Concern",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical outcomes. Among these, the Delta and Omicron variants have drawn",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Delta",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Omicron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant attention due to their distinct characteristics-Delta is associated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Delta",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with higher virulence and Omicron has greater transmissibility but reduced",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Omicron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "severity. This study compares host immune responses to the Delta and Omicron",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Delta",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Omicron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "variants using RNA-seq data from infected primary human airway epithelial cells.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Both variants triggered a robust antiviral innate immune response by 2 days",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2 days",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "post-infection (dpi). However, Omicron was found to elicit a more rapid immune",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Omicron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "response, showing pathway enrichment at 1 dpi. In contrast, Delta displayed no",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Delta",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immune-related pathway activation within the first 24 hours, suggesting it may",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the first 24 hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "evade early immune detection, promoting increased viral replication. By 3 dpi,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Delta induced a more aggressive immune response, particularly in pathways",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Delta",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "related to cell death and pro-inflammatory signaling, such as \"programmed cell",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "death\" and \"regulation of cell death.\" Weighted gene co-expression network",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis revealed distinct immune-related genes: Delta infections were",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characterized by hub genes like MYD88 and IL1R1 involved in pro-inflammatory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "responses, HLA-A & B, NLRC5 and PSMB9 involved in antigen presentation and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HLA-A & B",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NLRC5",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "PSMB9",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "TNSF10 and IFR1 involved in pro-apoptotic processes. Conversely, Omicron",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IFR1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Omicron",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infections were marked by hub genes such as CXCL1 and CXCL8 involved in immune",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCL1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CXCL8",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cells recruitment, MET and LYN involved in reducing hyperinflammatory responses",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MET",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "LYN",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and maintaining immune balance, and IFI44, EIF2AK2 and IFIT5 responsible for the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IFI44",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IFIT5",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sensing of viral RNA among others.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Open-science discovery of DNDI-6510, a compound that addresses genotoxic and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic liabilities of the COVID Moonshot SARS-CoV-2 Mpro lead inhibitor.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Robinson RP, Lefker BA, Duberstein S, Lahav N; COVID Moonshot Consortium;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Lefker BA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Duberstein S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lahav N",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID Moonshot Consortium",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Braillard S, Vangeel L, Laporte M, Charvillon FB, MacLeod AK, Wells A, Garner P,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Braillard S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vangeel L",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Laporte M",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Charvillon FB",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "MacLeod AK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wells A",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Garner P",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Knight R, Rees P, Simon A, Jochmans D, Neyts J, Read KD, Barr H, Robinson M, Lee",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Knight R",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Simon A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jochmans",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Neyts",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Read KD",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Barr H",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lee\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The 2020 SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus pandemic highlighted the urgent need for novel",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2020",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "small molecule antiviral drugs. (S)- x38 DNDI-6510 is a non-covalent SARS-CoV-2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "x38",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "main protease inhibitor developed by the open science collaboration COVID",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Moonshot. Here, we report on the metabolic and toxicologic optimization of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lead series previously disclosed by the COVID Moonshot Initiative, leading up to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the COVID Moonshot Initiative",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the selection of (S)- x38 DNDI-6510 as the preclinical candidate. We describe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "x38",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the thorough profiling of the series, identifying key risks such as formation of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "genotoxic metabolites and high clearance, which were successfully addressed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "genotoxic metabolites",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "during lead optimization. In addition, we disclose the in vitro and in vivo",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluation of (S)- x38 DNDI-6510 in pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic models,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "x38",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "exploring multiple approaches to ameliorate rodent-specific metabolic clearance,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and show that both co-dosing of (S)- x38 DNDI-6510 with an ABT inhibitor and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "x38",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "ABT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "utilizing a metabolically humanized mouse model (8HUM) achieve significant",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "improvements in exposure. Through comparisons of ABT co-dosing and humanized",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ABT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mouse models in efficacy experiments, we demonstrate that continuous exposure",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "mouse",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "over cellular EC 90 is required for SARS-CoV-2 antiviral efficacy in vivo in an",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "EC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "antiviral model using a mouse-adapted SARS-CoV-2 strain. Finally, (S)- x38",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "x38",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "DNDI-6510 was assessed in maximum tolerated dose experiments in two species,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "demonstrating significant in vivo PXR-linked auto-induction of metabolism,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PXR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "leading to the discontinuation of this compound. In summary, we report the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "successful effort to overcome series-specific AMES liabilities in a lead",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AMES",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "development program. Downstream optimization of existing series will require",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in-depth optimization of rodent-specific liabilities and metabolic induction",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2 NSP13 interacts with TEAD to suppress Hippo-YAP signaling.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hippo-YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The Hippo pathway controls organ development, homeostasis, and regeneration",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hippo",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "primarily by modulating YAP/TEAD-mediated gene expression. Although emerging",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studies report Hippo-YAP dysfunction after viral infection, it is largely",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hippo-YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(SARS-CoV-2). Here, we analyzed RNA sequencing data from induced pluripotent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stem cell-derived cardiomyocytes (iPSC-CMs) and SARS-CoV-2-infected human lung",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "samples, and observed a decrease in YAP target gene expression. In screening",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2 nonstructural proteins, we found that nonstructural protein 13",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "13",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NSP13), a conserved coronavirus helicase, inhibits YAP transcriptional activity",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "independent of the upstream Hippo kinases LATS1/2. Consistently, introducing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hippo",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NSP13 into cardiomyocytes suppresses an active form of YAP (YAP5SA) in vivo .",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NSP13",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Subsequent investigations on NSP13 mutants revealed that NSP13 helicase",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NSP13",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "NSP13",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "activity, including DNA binding and unwinding, is crucial for suppressing YAP",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transactivation. Mechanistically, TEAD4 serves as a platform to recruit NSP13",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TEAD4",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NSP13\n",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and YAP. NSP13 likely inactivates the YAP/TEAD4 transcription complex by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "NSP13",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "the YAP/TEAD4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "remodeling chromatin to recruit proteins, such as transcription termination",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "factor 2 (TTF2), to bind the YAP/TEAD/NSP13 complex. These findings reveal a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "novel YAP/TEAD regulatory mechanism and uncover molecular insights into",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "YAP",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hippo-YAP regulation after SARS-CoV-2 infection.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hippo-YAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Comprehensive investigation of SARS-CoV-2 intestinal pathogenesis in Drosophila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drosophila",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "El Kamali L, Nagy P, Girard J, Buchon N, Mavingui P, El-Kalamouni C, Osman D.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "El Kamali L",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nagy P",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Girard J",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Buchon N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mavingui",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "El-Kalamouni C",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Osman D.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gastrointestinal (GI) manifestations have been increasingly reported in COVID-19",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients. Here, we use the Drosophila melanogaster midgut model to investigate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drosophila",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2-induced GI pathogenesis. The fly midgut exhibits susceptibility to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "orally administered virus, resulting in disrupted epithelial architecture,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced organ size, and altered visceral muscle dynamics. These effects are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "accompanied by sustained proliferation of intestinal stem cells alongside",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decreased replenishment and viability of differentiated cells. Transcriptomic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "profiling reveals biphasic perturbations in midgut gene expression, particularly",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "midgut",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "in pathways related to lipid metabolism. Intriguingly, SARS-CoV-2 elicits a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dichotomous effect on lipid homeostasis, with lipid droplet accumulation in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "posterior midgut and depletion in anterior segments. Treatment with Plitidepsin,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plitidepsin",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "a COVID-19 drug candidate, mitigates most SARS-CoV-2 pathogenic features in both",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the Drosophila midgut and human pulmonary cells, while modulating basal lipid",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drosophila",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "droplet homeostasis in uninfected conditions. These findings establish the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Drosophila midgut as a potent model for studying SARS-CoV-2 GI pathogenesis and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Drosophila",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GI",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "evaluating antiviral compounds.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Susceptible host dynamics explain pathogen resilience to perturbations.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A major priority for epidemiological research in a time of anthropogenic change",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is understanding how infectious disease dynamics respond to perturbations.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Interventions to slow the spread of SARS-CoV-2 significantly disrupted the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transmission of other human pathogens. As interventions lifted, whether and when",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory pathogens would eventually return to their pre-pandemic dynamics",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "remains to be answered. Here, we present a framework for estimating pathogen",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resilience based on how fast epidemic patterns approach their pre-pandemic,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "endemic dynamics and analyze relevant time series data from Hong Kong, Canada,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hong Kong",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Canada",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Korea, and the US. By quantifying the resilience of common respiratory",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Korea",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "US",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pathogens, we are able to predict when each pathogen will eventually return to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "its pre-pandemic dynamics. Our predictions closely match the observed deviations",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(or lack thereof) from the pre-COVID dynamics of respiratory pathogens.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Discrepancies between predicted and observed dynamics indicate the long-term",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "impacts of pandemic perturbations, suggesting that some pathogens may be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "converging to a different endemic cycle. Finally, we show that the replenishment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "rate of the susceptible population is a key determinant of pathogen resilience,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "which in turn determines the sensitivity of a system to stochastic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "perturbations. Overall, our analysis highlights the persistent nature of common",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "respiratory pathogens compared to vaccine-preventable infections, such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A combination TLR7/8 and RIG-I agonist adjuvant reverts asthmatic allergic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sensitization and prevents aggravated influenza infection in OVA-sensitized",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Allergen-specific immunotherapy (AIT) is the only disease-modifying treatment",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Allergen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "AIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "currently available to treat allergy. However, it has limitations, as most",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "allergens are poorly immunogenic, resulting in an AIT process that can take",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "years. Therefore, adjuvant selection becomes critical to achieve a more",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "efficacious therapy. Our group has developed and tested an amphiphilic TLR7/8",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TLR7/8",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "agonist (IMDQ) and a RIG-I agonist (SDI) that used alone, or in combination,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IMDQ",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "have demonstrated strong adjuvant activity for influenza and SARS-CoV-2 vaccines",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in preclinical models. Here we describe the effect of these adjuvants in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sensitization of preclinical models with the ovalbumin (OVA) asthmatic allergic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "model via an in-depth humoral and cellular immune profiling. We assess their",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immune skewing and tolerance inducing capacities in previously sensitized",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "preclinical models with different genetic backgrounds (C57BL/6 vs. BALB/c mice).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Moreover, we evaluate their effect in an unrelated antigenic challenge with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "influenza. Finally, we investigate the role of IgG subclasses and T-cell",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IgG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "subpopulations in the protection against OVA challenge conferred by the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "OVA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "combination of IMDQ and SDI. We demonstrate that OVA-immunization in combination",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IMDQ",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with IMDQ+SDI prevents allergic sensitization via the induction of a balanced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Type 1/Type 2 response. Furthermore, it can revert the allergic phenotype in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mice previously sensitized with OVA-Alum, through reducing lung eosinophilia, as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "well as IL-4 and IL-5 production. However, this was dependent on genetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IL-5",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "background. IMDQ+SDI sensitization also led to reduced morbidity of a secondary",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "influenza challenge in OVA-sensitized mice. Finally, we demonstrated that IgG2c,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "influenza",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "IgG2c",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by itself, cannot protect from allergic sensitization and that both CD4 + and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CD8 + T-cells are needed for IMDQ+SDI prevention of eosinophil recruitment and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activation upon intranasal OVA-challenge.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PUM2 binds SARS-CoV-2 RNA and PUM1 mildly reduces viral RNA levels, but neither",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PUM1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "protein affects progeny virus production.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Phan N, Zaytseva Y, Lin CC, Mishra M, Sun W, Pawlica P.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Phan N",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Zaytseva Y",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lin CC",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mishra M",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pawlica P.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of gene expression found across plants, animals, and yeast. They bind Pumilio",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pumilio\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Response Elements (PREs) on messenger RNAs (mRNAs) to modulate mRNA stability",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Response Elements",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and translation. PUMs have been implicated in diverse cellular processes,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "including stem cell maintenance, neurogenesis, and cell cycle regulation. They",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "have also been reported to negatively regulate innate immunity genes and to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "participate in viral RNA sensing. Previous high-throughput interactome studies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "revealed that PUMs bind SARS-CoV-2 RNA. We found that SARS-CoV-2 transcripts",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SARS-CoV-2 RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "contain multiple conserved PREs, some of which are preferentially bound by PUM2.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Surprisingly, altering PUM levels does not affect the production of progeny",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PUM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "virions. However, depletion of PUM1 slightly increases intracellular viral RNA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "levels, suggesting that PUM1 either plays a mild antiviral role against",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SARS-CoV-2 or regulates a host factor that promotes viral replication. Notably,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PUM1 also negatively regulates innate immunity gene expression both at steady",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "state and during SARS-CoV-2 infection. Our findings support a complex",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immunomodulatory role for PUM1, acting both as a negative regulator of innate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PUM1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immunity genes and a mild inhibitor of SARS-CoV-2 RNA accumulation. However, in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SARS-CoV-2 RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cell culture, these roles appear negligible based on viral progeny output.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Whether the multiple PREs found in the SARS-CoV-2 genome contribute to evasion",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of PUM1 activity remains an open question.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The Renin-Angiotensin System Modulates SARS-CoV-2 Entry via ACE2 Receptor.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Renin-Angiotensin System Modulates",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ACE2 Receptor",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The RAS plays a central role in cardiovascular regulation and has gained",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RAS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prominence in the pathogenesis of COVID-19 due to the critical function of ACE2",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ACE2\n",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "as the entry receptor for SARS-CoV-2. Angiotensin IV, but not angiotensin II,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Angiotensin IV",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "II",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "has recently been reported to enhance the binding between the viral spike",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "protein and ACE2. To investigate the virological significance of this effect, we",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ACE2",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "developed a single-round infection assay using SARS-CoV-2 viral-like particles",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "expressing the spike protein. Our results demonstrate that while angiotensin II",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "II",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "does not affect viral infectivity across concentrations ranging from 40 nM to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "40 nM",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "400 nM, angiotensin IV enhances viral entry at a low concentration but exhibits",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dose-dependent inhibition at higher concentrations. These findings highlight the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "unique dual role of angiotensin IV in modulating SARS-CoV-2 entry. In silico",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular docking simulations indicate that angiotensin IV was predicted to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associate with the S1 domain near the receptor-binding domain in the open spike",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "S1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "conformation. Given that reported plasma concentrations of angiotensin IV range",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "widely from 17 pM to 81 nM, these levels may be sufficient to promote, rather",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "17 pM",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "81 nM",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "than inhibit, SARS-CoV-2 infection. This study identifies a novel link between",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RAS-derived peptides and SARS-CoV-2 infectivity, offering new insights into",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RAS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19 pathophysiology and informing potential therapeutic strategies.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Uncovering the Pathophysiological Pattern of Expression from Integrated Analysis",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Pathophysiological Pattern of Expression",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Integrated Analysis",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "across Uniformly Processed RNA Sequencing COVID-19 Datasets.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Uniformly",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Post-acute sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC) affects millions",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "millions",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "globally, yet the molecular mechanisms underlying acute COVID-19 and its chronic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "sequelae remain poorly understood.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "sequelae",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: We performed an integrative transcriptomic analysis of three",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "independent RNA-seq datasets, capturing the complete COVID-19 pathophysiology",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "from health through acute severe infection to post-acute sequelae and mortality",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(n=142 total samples). We implemented a containerized analytical pipeline from",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "these three RNA-seq datasets.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Our analysis reveals striking molecular dichotomies contrasting disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "phases with profound clinical implications. Acute severe/critical COVID-19",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reveals predominant enrichment of TNF-α signaling via NF-κB pathways (normalized",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TNF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NF-κB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "enrichment score >2.5, FDR <0.001), reflecting a cytokine storm pathophysiology",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2.5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "FDR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "characterized by rapid inflammatory developments involving IL-6, TNF-α, and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IL-6",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "TNF",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Myc Targets V1 and Oxidative Phosphorylation pathways (NES >2.2, FDR <0.005),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Myc Targets V1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxidative Phosphorylation",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "NES",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2.2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "FDR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "indicating important shifts toward cellular adaptation. Pathway signature",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis identifies core differentially expressed genes that reliably",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distinguish disease phases, thereby offering objective biomarkers for precision",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "distinguish",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: These findings establish a comprehensive molecular framework",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distinguishing acute inflammatory from chronic metabolic COVID-19 phases, with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "potential clinical applicability. TNF-α/NF-κB pathway signatures identify",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients at risk for severe disease progression, while Myc/OXPHOS signatures",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "allow objective PASC diagnosis, addressing current reliance on subjective and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "eliminative diagnosis. This integrative analytical framework has utility beyond",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19, offering an applicable approach for precision medicine implementation",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "across other diseases processes.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CLINICAL SIGNIFICANCE: This study transforms COVID-19 from a symptom-based to a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecularly-defined disease spectrum, enabling precision diagnosis, prognostic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "monitoring, classification, and targeted therapeutic possibilities based on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pathway-specific biomarkers rather than subjective clinical assessments.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Do Work Schedule and Work Position have an Impact on Fatigue among Geothermal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Geothermal",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Workers during the COVID-19 Pandemic? An Analysis Using Structural Equation",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Postgraduate Program of Occupational Medicine, Faculty of Medicine,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Program of Occupational Medicine, Faculty of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Community Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Community Medicine, Faculty of Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indonesia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, Krida Wacana Christian University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine and Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Krida Wacana Christian University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVES: This study aimed to examine the impact of work schedule and work",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "position on fatigue levels among employees at a private geothermal firm in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Indonesia during the COVID-19 pandemic. The company has modified its work",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Indonesia",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "schedule considering the COVID-19 epidemic to ensure a continuous supply of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "energy and meet the needs of the public.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: In this cross-sectional study, the dependent variable is fatigue, which",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is classified as a latent variable. Fatigue is assessed using the Indonesian",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fatigue",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Indonesian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "version of the Swedish Occupational Fatigue Inventory (SOFI). Fatigue is a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Swedish Occupational Fatigue Inventory",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fatigue",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "condition that has five dimensions: lack of energy, physical exertion, physical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "discomfort, sleepiness, and lack of motivation. The observed variables in this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "study include work schedule and work position, which serve as independent",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "variables. Using structural equation modeling (SEM), we assessed the impact of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the independent variables on each dimension of fatigue. This approach allowed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for the analysis of both the measurement and structural models.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The investigation employed total sampling, involving 132 workers from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "132",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the company who willingly participated in the study. According to the findings,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "workers' main fatigue dimension was lack of energy. However, the statistical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis did not establish a significant influence of work schedule and work",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Based on the findings of the SEM analysis, it is evident that there",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "positions with various dimensions of fatigue assessed using the SOFI",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SOFI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "questionnaire. These dimensions include lack of energy, physical exertion,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "physical discomfort, sleepiness, and lack of motivation. While this outcome",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "suggests that work schedules and job positions may not directly influence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "fatigue levels as measured in this study, it underscores the importance of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "promoting good work practices such as offering flexible working hours may help",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "hours",
        "label": "TIME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "address potential fatigue concerns among employees. However, further research is",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "necessary to explore additional variables that could potentially impact fatigue",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "levels in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic and beyond.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Cross-sectional Cranial CT Imaging Findings and Patterns in Clinically Diagnosed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cranial CT Imaging Findings",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19 Cases in a Tertiary Referral Center.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19 Cases",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Vascular and Interventional Radiology Section, Department of Radiology,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Interventional Radiology Section,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Radiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Philippine General Hospital, University of the Philippines Manila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Philippine General Hospital, University of the Philippines",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Manila",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by the SARS-CoV-2 virus,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2019",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "presents not only as a respiratory ailment but also poses risks of neurological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "complications whose underlying mechanisms remain unclear. These complications",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "range from mild to severe and may involve direct invasion of the central nervous",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "system (CNS), disruption of the blood-brain barrier, or systemic cytokine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effects. Diagnostic challenges persist due to the suboptimal sensitivity of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RT-PCR assays.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RT-PCR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: The present study aimed to review the contrast and non-contrast",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "enhanced cranial CT images of all diagnosed COVID-19 patients in a tertiary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "referral center with the clinical impression of non-traumatic and nonoperative",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CNS pathologies.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with neurological symptoms. Among 51 included patients, plain CT scans",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "were predominantly used, revealing no acute infarcts or hemorrhages in the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "majority, while frontal lobe involvement was notable in cases with pathology.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Chronic infarcts or ischemic changes were observed in over half of the cases,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "over half",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "primarily affecting the anterior circulation. Only one case of meningitis was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Only one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "meningitis",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: In the final analysis, 51 patients met the inclusion criteria out of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "51",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the initial 64 enrolled. The study population, predominantly male with a mean",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "64",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "age of 58.02 ± 20.87 years, mainly comprised patients solely diagnosed with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "58.02",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "20.87 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "COVID-19. Plain CT scans were favored over contrast-enhanced scans (76.50%, n =",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "76.50%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "39). While most patients had no acute infarcts or hemorrhages, the frontal lobe",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "39",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was commonly affected among stroke patients (9.8%, n = 5). Additionally, a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9.8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "5",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant portion of patients without acute stroke findings exhibited chronic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infarcts or ischemic changes (57.69%, n = 15).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "57.69%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: This study sheds light on the radiological patterns of CNS",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "involvement in COVID-19 patients, highlighting frequent frontal lobe involvement",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "possibly attributed to hypercoagulability and endotheliitis. Further research",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with larger sample sizes and MRI utilization is recommended to enhance our",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding of CNS manifestations in COVID-19. This study contributes to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CNS",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding COVID-19 neurological sequelae, particularly in terms of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "findings highlight the need for comprehensive evaluation and management of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Utilization of Oxford Nanopore Technology for human infectious disease detection",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and surveillance in Africa: a scoping review.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Minnesota",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Minneapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MN,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Medical Microbiology and Parasitology, Faculty of Clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Microbiology and Parasitology, Faculty of Clinical",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, College of Health Sciences, University of Jos, Jos, Plateau State,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sciences, College of Health Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Jos,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Plateau State",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Health Sciences Libraries, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3)Health Sciences Libraries",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Minnesota",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Minneapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MN,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Pediatrics and Division of Critical Care, University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pediatrics and Division of Critical Care, University of\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Pediatrics and Division of Critical Care, Hennepin County",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pediatrics and Division of Critical Care",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Hennepin County",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical Center, Minneapolis, MN, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Minneapolis",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MN,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Department of Animal Science, College of Food, Agricultural and Natural",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Animal Science, College of Food, Agricultural and Natural",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Resources Science, University of Minnesota, Saint Paul, MN, USA.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Resources Science, University of Minnesota",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Saint Paul",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "MN,",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "USA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(7)Department of Medical Microbiology, University of Jos and Jos University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Microbiology",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Jos and",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jos University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Teaching Hospital, Faculty of Basic Clinical Sciences, College of Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Teaching Hospital, Faculty of Basic Clinical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "College of Health\n",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(8)Department of Paediatrics, Faculty of Clinical Sciences, College of Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Paediatrics, Faculty of Clinical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "College of Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Sciences, University of Jos and Jos University Teaching Hospital, Jos, Plateau",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Jos and Jos University Teaching Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jos",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(#)Contributed equally",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Background. Nanopore-based sequencing by Oxford Nanopore Technologies (ONT)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Oxford Nanopore Technologies",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "offers rapid, cost-effective and portable sequencing. As an emerging technology,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ONT must be evaluated for efficacy and practical application in both high- and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "low-resource settings. This scoping review (SR) aimed to (1) describe how",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "nanopore technology is used in Africa for surveillance and diagnosis of human",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infectious diseases, (2) describe how nanopore technology aids in the real-time",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "detection of infectious pathogens in Africa and (3) identify challenges and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      },
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "opportunities for utilizing nanopore technology in Africa to study infectious",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diseases. Methods. This SR followed the Joanna Briggs Institute Reviewer's",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Joanna Briggs Institute Reviewer's",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Manual framework for SRs. English language studies published from 1 January 2008",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "English",
        "label": "LANGUAGE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1 January 2008",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to 30 April 2024 that used ONT on human specimens collected in Africa and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30 April 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "targeted ≥1 microbial agent were included. Searches were performed in Embase,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "≥1",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Embase",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medline, PubMed, CINAHL and the Cochrane Library. The protocol was publicly",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medline",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PubMed",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Cochrane Library",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "available on the Open Science Framework Bastug et al. (Nanopore Sequencing for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Open Science Framework Bastug",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanopore Sequencing",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Infectious Diseases Surveillance and Diagnostics in Africa: a Scoping Review",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Africa",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2024) prior to data collection. Two independent reviewers screened studies using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Covidence, and data was extracted using a custom REDCap instrument. Descriptive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "statistics and data visualization were performed in Microsoft Excel. Results.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microsoft Excel",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "One thousand one hundred sixty-two studies were identified and 93 (8%) underwent",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "One thousand one hundred sixty-two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "93",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "8%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "full-text review. The portable MinION Mk1B was the most common ONT device (65%",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "65%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of studies). Eighty-eight studies analysed specimens from a single African",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Eighty-eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "country. Of these, 45% were sequenced in the same country, 7% in a different",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "45%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "African country and 11% in a non-African country, while 32% did not specify the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "11%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "non-African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "32%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "location. Specimen types included direct patient specimens (62%) and cultured",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "62%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "isolates (35%), or a combination of both. Blood, serum or plasma was most common",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "35%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(35%), followed by naso- or oropharyngeal specimens (27%). Forty-four studies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "35%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "27%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Forty-four",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "used ONT during an active infectious disease outbreak, 25 of which studied",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studies used ONT for genomic surveillance of infectious pathogens or antibiotic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance genes, and one study used ONT for a direct clinical application.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "African-affiliated authors were included as first, middle and last authors in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "46% of studies, and 15% were published by entirely African-affiliated teams. Ten",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "46%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "15%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ten",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studies published information on workflow timeline, and five studies published",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "five",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the per-specimen cost. Conclusions. ONT can enable timely and affordable",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "sequencing in African countries as demonstrated through a small number of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studies that accomplished these goals individually. Most studies used ONT for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genomic surveillance of pathogens or antimicrobial resistance genes, while only",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "one study used ONT directly for a real-time clinical application. A small number",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of studies described a short interval between specimen collection and sequence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "result, supporting that clinical applications are possible. There is a need for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "improved reporting of ONT methodology including pipeline timelines, cost, use of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "barcoding, flow cell models and the use of negative controls. Publications that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "provide these details will enhance reproducibility and support the development",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of new studies using ONT for the diagnosis and surveillance of infectious",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ONT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diseases in low-resource settings.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "this work. Thirty-one studies included multiple co-first authors, and 21 studies",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Thirty-one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "21",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "included multiple co-last authors. Fourteen studies (15%) were composed of only",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fourteen",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "authors who were affiliated with African institutions, while two studies (2%)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "did not include an African-affiliated author. The most common authorship team",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "structure included having an author affiliated with an African institution",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(termed ‘African-affiliated’) in all three positions of the paper, i.e. as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "African",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "first, middle and last authors (N=52, 56%, Fig. 4). Fig. 4.African-affiliated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "56%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fig",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fig",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "authors present in different authorship positions amongst studies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The Essential Network (TEN): consulting stakeholders and experts to better",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Essential Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "TEN",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "understand implementation of a blended care mental health support services for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Australian health professionals.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Australian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Coleshill M(1)(2), Fransisca K(3), Du X(3), Black M(1)(4), Newby JM(1)(4),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Coleshill",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fransisca K(3",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Du X(3",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Newby JM(1)(4",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Black Dog Institute, Sydney, Australia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sydney",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)UNSW Medicine & Health, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)UNSW Medicine & Health",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of New South Wales",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sydney",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)School of Psychological Sciences, Macquarie University, Sydney, Australia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Psychological Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Macquarie University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sydney",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)School of Psychology, University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Psychology, University of New South Wales",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sydney",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Australia",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: The Essential Network (TEN) is a blended care mental health support",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Essential Network",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "service for Australian health professionals. We conducted a series of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Australian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "semi-structured interviews with key stakeholders and researchers to understand",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "health professionals' needs, canvas suggested changes to TEN, and examine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TEN",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "methods of improving service uptake.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHOD: Nine semi-structured individual or group interviews were conducted with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "METHOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nine",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "10 TEN stakeholders (external stakeholders) and eight interviews were conducted",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "TEN",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "eight",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with 18 researchers or related roles with experience implementing or evaluating",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "18",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mental health services for health professionals (internal experts).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "De-identified transcripts were thematically analysed using an inductive and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "deductive approach.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Participants highlighted the need for confidentiality, with mandatory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reporting concerns being a key barrier to health professionals engaging with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "mental health services. External stakeholders viewed digital services as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "advantageous due to accessibility and anonymity, although both groups noted that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "concerns around effectiveness were a barrier to engagement with digital",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "services. Both groups agreed that peer endorsement was key to implementation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Digital services were viewed as promising, but best employed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "alongside person-to-person options in a blended care format. Services that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "address the unique workplace culture of healthcare, including stigma and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "systemic barriers to help-seeking, can create effective and scalable support for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "health professionals.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Plain Language Summary: What is already known about this topic: (1) Health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "professionals are at a greater risk of poor mental health compared to the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "general public. (2) The COVID-19 pandemic has placed further strain upon health",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "COVID-19",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "professionals, highlighting the need for more tailored mental health services.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(3) Cultural and systemic issues exist within healthcare that act as barriers to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "help-seeking. What this topic adds: (1) Digital services were viewed as best",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "employed alongside person-to-person services in a blended care format. (2) In",
    "entities": [
      {
