[
  {
    "text": "Cup as a Cap on the Diabetic Wound: A Hope for Treatment of Diabetic Ulcers.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cap",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "the Diabetic Wound: A Hope for Treatment of Diabetic Ulcers",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Author information:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Biomedical Engineering, Meybod University, Meybod, Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Biomedical Engineering",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Meybod University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Meybod",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Iran",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Diabetes is known as one of the most important widespread diseases in the world.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Diabetic ulcer is one of the main complications associated with this disease.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The use of the capabilities of modern science such as nanotechnology can be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effective in developing new strategies for treating diabetic ulcers. Regulating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "homeostasis, controlling infections, and the ability to regenerate/ heal are",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "some of the proposed mechanisms of nanomaterials in wound healing. In this",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "regard, cuprorivaite bioceramic, as a bioceramic containing copper nanoparticles",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with effects on angiogenic factors and infection control, can effectively be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "used in the healing of diabetic ulcers. In this prospective article, we have",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "presented the potential of this bioceramic in the design of new dressings for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetic wound healing.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright© Bentham Science Publishers; For any queries, please email at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bentham Science Publishers",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A Comprehensive Review of Acanthosis Nigricans: Pathogenesis, Clinical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "manifestation and Management.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Pharmaceutics, Laureate Institute of Pharmacy, Kathog",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutics, Laureate Institute of Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kathog\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "INTRODUCTION: Acanthosis Nigricans is a dermatological condition characterized",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nigricans",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "by hyperpigmented velvet plaques that can be observed in flexural areas such as",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the neck, axilla, and groin. AN is frequently associated with insulin resistance",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and obesity, however, it can also appear in non-obese people and as a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "non-obese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "paraneoplastic disease. Its prevalence varies across different populations, with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "higher rates observed in individuals with obesity, diabetes, and certain genetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "syndromes. Classification of AN can be based on underlying etiology,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "distinguishing primary and secondary forms. Pathogenesis is the complex",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interplay of genetic, hormonal, and environmental factors, with insulin",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resistance playing a central role. Diagnosis relies on clinical evaluation of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "characteristics of skin changes, often requiring further investigation for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "underlying systemic disease. Topical therapies involve keratolytic agents,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "retinoids, and alpha hydroxyl acids to improve the cosmesis and reduce the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "plaque's thickness. Treatment strategies address underlying conditions by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "emphasizing lifestyle modifications and in some cases, pharmacological",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interventions.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "OBJECTIVE: This review aims to comprehensively examine the pathogenesis,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "clinical manifestation, and management of acanthosis nigricans.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "DISCUSSION: AN is closely linked to insulin resistance, characterized by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "impaired cellular response to insulin, leading to compensatory hyperinsulinemia.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Recognizing AN's clinical presentation is paramount for early diagnosis and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thickened patches of skin, typically occurring in skin folds and creases. It can",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "be a sign of an underlying health issue such as insulin resistance, obesity,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hormonal disorders, or certain medications. Proper diagnosis and management of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "the underlying conditions are crucial. Treatment may involve addressing the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "underlying causes, lifestyle changes, and topical medications to improve the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "appearance of the skin. Regular monitoring and follow-up with a health care",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "professional are essential for optimal management and to prevent complications.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Intraosseous versus intravenous fluid resuscitation in gastrointestinal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tumor-related acute hemorrhage: impact on 30-day mortality and lactate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "clearance.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Emergency Medicine, The People's Hospital of Rugao Rugao",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Emergency Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The People's Hospital of Rugao Rugao",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Gastroenterology, The People's Hospital of Rugao Rugao 226500,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The People's Hospital of Rugao Rugao",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "226500",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Emergency Medicine, PLA Eastern Theater General Hospital",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Emergency Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLA Eastern Theater General Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Department of Emergency Medicine, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital Group Suqian",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Emergency Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nanjing",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "This retrospective study evaluated the impact of intraosseous infusion (IO)",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "versus traditional intravenous infusion (IV) on 30-day mortality and clinical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "30-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "outcomes in 518 patients with acute gastrointestinal bleeding (AGIB) secondary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "518",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "to gastrointestinal tumors from January 2022 to July 2024. Patients were divided",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "January 2022 to July 2024",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "into IO (n=217) and IV (n=301) groups based on initial resuscitation strategy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IO",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Compared to IV group, the IO group demonstrated higher first-attempt",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "IO",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "first",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "catheterization success rate, shorter vascular access time, and faster blood",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "pressure recovery (all P<0.001), alongside higher 6-hour lactate (LA) clearance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6-hour",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(34% vs. 22%, P<0.001) and lower 30-day mortality (11.98% vs. 18.6%, P=0.016).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "34%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "22%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "30-day",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "11.98%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Multivariate analysis identified IO infusion as protective factor for lactate",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolism (HR=0.289, 95% CI: 0.092-0.864), while advanced age (HR=1.125),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HR=0.289",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.092-0.864",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes (HR=3.23), and low LA clearance (HR=0.016) were independent risk factor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HR=3.23",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for mortality. Causal mediation analysis revealed that 6-hour LA clearance",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6-hour",
        "label": "TIME"
      },
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mediated 68% of the IO-associated mortality reduction (P<0.001), whereas",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "68%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes history was not a significant mediator (P=0.156). Complication rates",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "were comparable between groups (P>0.05). These findings indicate that IO",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "P>0.05",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IO",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infusion improves survival in AGIB due to gastrointestinal tumors by rapidly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "restoring hemodynamics and enhancing lactate metabolism. The mortality benefit",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "is primarily driven by accelerated LA clearance rather than comorbidities like",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "LA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes. Given its safety profile comparable to IV, IO infusion should be",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "AJCR Copyright © 2025.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: None.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "4. Front Pharmacol. 2025 Jul 1;16:1646006. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2025.1646006.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "4",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.3389",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Correction: Mechanism underlying the involvement of CXCR4/CXCL12 in diabetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCR4/CXCL12",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "wound healing and prospects for responsive hydrogel-loaded CXCR4 formulations.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CXCR4",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Clinical Nutrition, The Affiliated Hospital of Yangzhou",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Nutrition",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yangzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Yangzhou University, Jiangsu, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Yangzhou University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jiangsu",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Institute of Translational Medicine, Medical College, Yangzhou University,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Institute",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Translational Medicine, Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yangzhou University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of General Surgery, The Affiliated Hospital of Yangzhou",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Surgery",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Affiliated Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yangzhou",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Front Pharmacol. 2025 Apr 16;16:1561112. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2025.1561112.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Front Pharmacol",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.3389",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "[This corrects the article DOI: 10.3389/fphar.2025.1561112.].",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.3389",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Wang, Nie, Lu and Chong.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wang",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nie",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lu",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chong",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Inverse association between dietary fiber intake and gallstone disease in U.S.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "U.S.",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "adults: a cross-sectional study from the NHANES database.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NHANES",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Research Center for Translational Medicine, Hubei Key Laboratory of Wudang",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Center for Translational Medicine",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Local Chinese Medicine Research, Hubei Provincial Clinical Research Center for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Local Chinese Medicine Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Provincial Clinical Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Parkinson's Disease at Xiangyang No.1 People's Hospital, Hubei University of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)College of Biomedicine and Health, Huazhong Agricultural University, Wuhan,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)College",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Huazhong Agricultural University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wuhan",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Clinical Medical Research, Binhai County People's Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Medical Research",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Clinical Medical College of Yangzhou University, Yancheng, Jiangsu, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Clinical Medical College",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yangzhou University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yancheng",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jiangsu",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: The cross-sectional association of dietary fiber intake with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "gallstone disease in United States adults remains to be comprehensively",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "data from 2017-2023. The assessment of dietary fiber intake was derived from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2017-2023",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "24-h dietary recalls. Stratified analyses were then used to demonstrate dietary",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "24",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fiber intake corresponding to different groups of gallstone and non-gallstone",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "conditions. The use of weighted logistic regression was employed to explore the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "correlation between dietary fiber intake and gallstone disease. Subgroup and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interaction analyses were used to identify potential interacting factors.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Additionally, restricted cubic spline was used to assess the dose-response",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The study population comprised 9,273 patients, with a gallstone",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9,273",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prevalence of 10.47% (971 cases). In the context of various subgroups, patients",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.47%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "971",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosed with gallstones exhibited a reduced dietary fiber intake in comparison",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with individuals not bearing gallstones. In the fully adjusted model, an inverse",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "association was observed between dietary fiber intake and gallstone disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "value = 0.039). The highest quartile of dietary fiber intake exhibited a lower",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "0.039",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "risk of gallstone disease in comparison with the lowest quartile (quartile 4 vs.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "quartile 1: 0.65 (0.45, 0.94), p value = 0.022). The inverse correlation between",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.65",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.45",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.94",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.022",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dietary fiber intake and the prevalence of gallstones was found to be",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "statistically significant in several subgroups, including males, Hispanic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hispanic",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "individuals, those with less than a high school education, alcohol consumers,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and individuals diagnosed with diabetes. Furthermore, the analysis of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dose-response curves indicated a nearly linear correlation between dietary fiber",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "intake and the risk of gallstone development.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Dietary fiber intake is inversely associated with gallstone disease",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in United States adults. Adequate dietary fiber intake may be beneficial in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "United States",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright © 2025 Zuo, Sang, Sun, Chen and Ji.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ji",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "6. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2025 Jul 2;12(7):ofaf369. doi: 10.1093/ofid/ofaf369.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1093",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "eCollection 2025 Jul.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "eCollection",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025 Jul.",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Prevalence and Risk Factors of Liver Fibrosis Among People With HIV and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Metabolic Dysfunction-Associated Steatotic Liver Disease",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Infection and Immunity, Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Infection and Immunity",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanghai Public Health Clinical Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Fudan University, Shanghai, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fudan University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shanghai",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: We aimed to investigate the prevalence of liver fibrosis and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "identify the associated risk factors among people with HIV (PWH) and metabolic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Abdominal ultrasonography and transient elastography were performed to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "assess liver fibrosis and steatosis. Lean MASLD was defined as MASLD occurring",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "in PWH with a body mass index (BMI) < 24 kg/m2. A cutoff of liver stiffness",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "24 kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "measurement ≥ 7.1 kPa was set for significant liver fibrosis. The prevalence,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "≥",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "kPa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "correlation factors, and risk factors were evaluated.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Among 361 PWH, 250 (69.25%) had a BMI < 24 kg/m2, and 141 (39.06%) were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "361",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "250",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "69.25%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "24 kg",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      },
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "39.06%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diagnosed with MASLD. The 141 PWH with MASLD were classified as 2 groups based",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "on BMI: 58 (41.13%) as lean MASLD and 83 (58.87%) as overweight MASLD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "58",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "41.13%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "83",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "58.87%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Significant fibrosis was observed in 121 of the 361 PWH, including 75 of the 141",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "121",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "361",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "75",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "141",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with MASLD, 28 of the 58 with lean MASLD, and 47 of the 83 with overweight",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MASLD",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "28",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "58",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "47",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "83",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MASLD. Among PWH with MASLD, independent risk factors for significant liver",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "fibrosis included higher alanine aminotransferase levels and the presence of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "type 2 diabetes. Among PWH with lean MASLD, independent risk factors for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significant liver fibrosis included elevated aspartate aminotransferase levels",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSIONS: Significant liver fibrosis is highly prevalent among PWH and MASLD.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Multiple risk factors are associated with significant liver fibrosis among PWH.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "These findings underscore the importance of early identification and management",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of liver fibrosis in PWH.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PWH",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CLINICAL TRIALS REGISTRATION: NCT04215926.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oxford University Press",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Infectious Diseases Society of America.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: Potential conflicts of interest. All authors: No",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reported conflicts. All authors have submitted the ICMJE Form for Disclosure of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Potential Conflicts of Interest.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Potential Conflicts of Interest",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Differences in immune cell profiles around the time of islet autoimmunity",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "seroconversion in children with and without type 1 diabetes.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "M, Norris JM, Johnson RK.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Norris",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Johnson",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Seroconversion (SV) marks the initiation of islet autoimmunity (IA) and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Seroconversion (SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "IA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pre-clinical phase of type 1 diabetes, yet the contributions of immune cells",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "beyond cytotoxic T cells remain unclear. We applied high-resolution immune",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "cell-type deconvolution using peripheral blood DNA methylation data from nested",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "case-control samples of the Diabetes Autoimmunity Study in the Young (DAISY;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Diabetes Autoimmunity Study",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "n=151) and The Environmental Determinants of Diabetes in the Young (TEDDY;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "The Environmental Determinants of Diabetes",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Young",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "TEDDY",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "n=166) to estimate immune cell proportions across pre-SV and SV timepoints and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "construct functional ratios, such as the neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio (NLR).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Using linear models, we evaluated differences between type 1 diabetes cases and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "linear",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "controls at pre-SV, SV, and the change across timepoints. Pre-SV, cases had",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pre-SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pre-SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "higher NLR and lower CD4T/CD8T cell ratios. At SV, the combined B-CD4T-CD8T",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CD4T",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "B-CD4T-CD8",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "memory/naïve ratio was reduced in cases. From pre-SV to SV, cases showed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pre-SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "attenuations in NLR, B-memory/naïve, and B-CD4T-CD8T memory/naïve ratios. These",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NLR",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "B-CD4T-CD8",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "patterns may reflect delayed or disrupted immune maturation with the persistence",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "or expansion of naïve cells or impaired transition to memory subsets following",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "antigen exposure. Our findings highlight early shifts in innate and adaptive",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "immune cell dynamics during type 1 diabetes pathogenesis and support immune cell",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ratios as potential biomarkers for risk stratification and mechanistic insight.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ARTICLE HIGHLIGHTS: We sought to examine immune cells around the time of IA",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "seroconversion in children at higher risk for type 1 diabetes.We wanted to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "answer whether immune cell ratio differences exist between type 1 diabetes cases",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and controls around IA at pre-SV, SV, and the change pre-SV to SV.We found",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "pre-SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "immune cell ratio differences between type 1 diabetes cases and controls before,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "during, and across SV timepoints, suggesting potential etiological and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pathophysiological roles.Our findings highlight the complexity of immunodynamics",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "around IA seroconversion and potential role for immune cell ratios in type 1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IA",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes risk stratification and intervention.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Spatial transcriptomic profiling of human paravertebral sympathetic chain",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ganglia reveals diabetes-induced neuroplasticity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Moreno MM, Patel PJ, Goss K, Mian SM, Nakisli S, Inturi N, Shiers SI, Horton P,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Moreno MM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Patel PJ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Goss K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mian SM",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Nakisli S",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Inturi N",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Shiers SI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Horton P",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Price TJ, Yousuf MS.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Yousuf MS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The paravertebral sympathetic chain ganglia (SCG) are autonomic ganglia critical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "for regulating the \"fight-or-flight\" response. Symptoms of sympathetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "dysfunction are prevalent in diabetes, affecting up to 90% of patients. The",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "up to 90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular and cellular composition of the human SCG and its alteration in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes remains poorly defined. To address this gap, we performed spatial",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "transcriptomic profiling of lumbar SCGs from diabetic and non-diabetic organ",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "donors. We identified 3 three distinct neuronal populations, two noradrenergic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "three",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NA1 and NA2) and one cholinergic (CHO), based on tyrosine hydroxylase ( TH )",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NA1",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CHO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and SLC18A3 expression, respectively. We also characterized 9 non-neuronal",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "populations consisting of Schwann cells, immune cells, fibroblasts, adipocytes,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Schwann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and endothelial cells. In diabetic SCGs, we observed a significant loss of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "myelinating Schwann cells and a phenotypic shift of cholinergic neurons toward a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Schwann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "noradrenergic identity. Additionally, diabetes was associated with a significant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "noradrenergic",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reduction in the transcripts of vasodilatory neuropeptides, such as VIP and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CALCA , suggesting a mechanism for impaired vascular control. Upstream regulator",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CALCA",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "analysis highlighted altered neurotrophic signaling in diabetes, with enhanced",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "NGF/TRKA and diminished BDNF/TRKB activity, potentially driven by target-derived",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NGF",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "TRKA",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cues. Comparison between SCG and dorsal root ganglia (DRG) neurons revealed",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ganglia-specific genes, like SCN3A and NPY (SCG) versus SCN10A and GPX1 (DRG),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCN10A",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "offering specific therapeutic targets for autonomic dysfunction or pain. Our",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "findings provide a transcriptomic characterization of human SCG, revealing",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular signatures that underlie diabetic autonomic dysfunction. This work",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "lays a foundation for the development of therapies to restore sympathetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "function and avoid unintended autonomic effects in the development of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "SIGNIFICANCE STATEMENT: Autonomic dysfunction affects up to 90% of people with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SIGNIFICANCE STATEMENT",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "up to 90%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetes, yet the human sympathetic nervous system remains poorly molecularly",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "defined. To address this gap, we present a spatial transcriptomic profile of the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "human sympathetic chain ganglia (SCG), revealing how diabetes affects the human",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SCG",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "autonomic nervous system. We show that diabetes shifts the cholinergic neuronal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "population to a noradrenergic phenotype and reduces vasodilation neuropeptide",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "expression, potentially explaining impaired vascular control and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "thermoregulation. Comparative analysis of sympathetic and sensory ganglia",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "reveals distinct gene profiles that may inform novel therapeutic strategies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "These findings offer critical insight into the molecular drivers of diabetic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "autonomic neuropathy and lay the groundwork for safer, more precise treatments",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "autonomic neuropathy",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that selectively modulate autonomic or sensory function in chronic disease.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Stressed β-cells contribute to loss of peri-islet extracellular matrix in type 1",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Johansen CG, Lam K, Farnsworth NL.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Johansen CG",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lam K",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Farnsworth NL",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Type 1 diabetes (T1D) is characterized by the immune-mediated destruction of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "1",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "insulin-producing β-cells in pancreatic islets. The peri-islet extracellular",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "matrix (ECM) is a complex protein barrier that is lost in T1D, in part due to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ECM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infiltrating immune cells. The contribution of stressed β-cells to ECM",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ECM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "degradation during T1D remains unclear. To bridge this gap, we used",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "12-15-week-old NOD mice and pancreas sections from healthy, ≥2 autoantibody",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15-week-old",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "positive (Aab+), and recent onset T1D donors. We focused on MMP-3 due to its",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MMP-3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "role in degrading type IV collagen (COL IV) in the peri-islet ECM. Treatment",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "IV",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "COL IV",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ECM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with proinflammatory cytokines or hyperglycemia increased MMP-3 gene expression",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MMP-3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "and protein levels in mouse and human islets. In NOD pancreas sections,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NOD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increased MMP-3 expression in β-cells correlates with loss of COL IV during",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MMP-3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "COL IV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "insulitis and hyperglycemia; however, this was independent of insulitis score.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "We observed similar increases in MMP-3 and loss of COL IV in islets and exocrine",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MMP-3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "COL IV",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue from Aab+ and recent onset T1D donors. These results suggest that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "stressed β-cells degrade the ECM during preclinical T1D, further weakening the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ECM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "peri-islet ECM barrier and facilitating islet infiltration and death. Inhibiting",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ECM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expression of MMP-3 may represent a novel treatment to prevent islet death in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MMP-3",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "T1D.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "T1D.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The Chromatin Remodeler Protein CHD4 Cooperates With NKX2.2 to Regulate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Regulate",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Pancreatic Beta Cell Integrity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "identity and function; however, cofactor proteins that modulate the functional",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activity of NKX2.2 in β cells are relatively unexplored. An unbiased proteomics",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NKX2.2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NKX2.2 interacting partner. CHD4 is a nucleosome remodeler that directs the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NKX2.2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "appropriate differentiation, maturation and function of many cell types by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "activating or repressing genes. To characterize the NKX2.2-dependent and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "NKX2.2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "independent roles of CHD4 in β cells, we generated Chd4 βKO mice. Deletion of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CHD4",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Chd4",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Chd4 substantially impaired the maturation and function of β cells. The Chd4 βKO",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chd4",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mice were diabetic as early as 3 weeks of age due to the disruption of islet",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "early as 3 weeks of age",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "integrity, impaired glucose-stimulated insulin secretion and calcium signaling,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and downregulation of essential β cell regulatory genes. These studies",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "demonstrate that CHD4 is an essential transcriptional cofactor of NKX2.2 that is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CHD4",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "NKX2.2",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "required for the proper maturation and function of pancreatic β cells.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Improved conditioning for hematopoietic chimerism induces islet tolerance to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Mixed hematopoietic chimerism after hematopoietic cell transplantation (HCT) can",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "modulate the immune system and induce tolerance to allogeneic tissues. However,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "bone marrow conditioning-related toxicities preclude wider adoption of HCT for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "HCT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transplant allotolerance. We sought agents that reduced conditioning intensity,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "while promoting durable mixed chimerism after HCT across complete major",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "histocompatibility complex (MHC) mismatch in diabetic mice, permitting islet",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MHC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "allotransplantation and diabetes reversal. We systematically tested baricitinib",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(JAK1/2 inhibitor), venetoclax (Bcl2 inhibitor), and αCD47 antibody, agents in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "current clinical use, and quantified hematopoietic chimerism after HCT. Combined",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "with αCD117 antibody, transient T cell depletion, and just 10 centigray (cGy)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "just 10",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "total body irradiation (TBI), these agents enabled durable mixed chimerism and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "TBI",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "matching allo-islet tolerance, to cure diabetes without evidence of GVHD. Thus,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "we have developed a conditioning regimen to promote allogeneic mixed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "hematopoietic chimerism and transplanted islet allotolerance that minimizes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "conditioning radiation and cures diabetes, a significant achievement.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Med14 phosphorylation shapes genomic response to GLP-1 Agonist.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLP-1 Agonist",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Under feeding conditions, release of glucagon-like peptide (GLP-1) from",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLP-1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "intestinal L cells promotes insulin secretion and pancreatic beta cell",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viability. Binding of GLP-1 to its cognate receptor on the beta cell surface",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLP-1",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "results in induction of the cAMP signaling pathway, leading to the protein",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "kinase A (PKA) mediated phosphorylation of CREB and induction of CREB target",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CREB",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CREB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "genes. By contrast with the acute effects of this pathway on immediate early",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CREB target genes, which attenuate the cAMP-CREB response, sustained exposure of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CREB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "beta cells to the stable GLP-1 receptor agonist Exendin-4 stimulates the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLP-1",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "expression of beta cell specific CREB target genes with delayed kinetics. In a",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CREB",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "proteomic screen for transcriptional co-regulators that mediate the long-term",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "effects of GLP-1 analogs, we identified Med14, a backbone subunit of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GLP-1",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Mediator complex. Exposure to Exendin-4 stimulates Med14 phosphorylation at",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Ser983, corresponding to a conserved PKA recognition site (RRXS) that is located",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "within an intrinsically disordered region of Med14. Phosphorylation of Med14 by",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "PKA is essential for maintenance of enhancers that drive induction of beta",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PKA",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "cell-specific and diabetes-linked genes. Mutation of Med14 at Ser983 to alanine",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "decreased beta cell numbers and repressed Exendin-4 induced gene regulation in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "primary mouse beta cells. Our work reveals how phosphorylation of a general",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "primary mouse",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "transcription factor in response to GLP-1 analogs triggers a broad genomic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "transcription",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "GLP-1",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "response with salutary effects on beta cell function.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Long-read transcriptome assembly reveals vast isoform diversity in the placenta",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the placenta\n",
        "label": "FAC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "associated with metabolic and endocrine function.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Bresnahan ST, Yong H, Wu WH, Lopez S, Yen Chan JK, White F, Jacques PÉ, Hivert",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bresnahan ST",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yong H",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wu WH",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Lopez S",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Yen Chan JK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "White F",
        "label": "FAC"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jacques PÉ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MF, Chan SY, Love MI, Huang JY, Bhattacharya A.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chan",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Love MI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Huang JY",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bhattacharya A.\n",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The placenta plays a critical role in fetal development and mediates maternal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "metabolic effects on offspring health outcomes. Despite its importance, the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "placenta remains understudied in large-scale genomic initiatives, with most",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "analyses focusing on gene-level expression based on annotations from adult",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "tissue references that obscure isoform diversity particularly vital to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "understanding function in developmental tissues. Here, we employed",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "largest-in-class long-read RNA sequencing (N = 72) to generate a comprehensive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RNA",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "72",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "placental transcript reference, yielding 37,661 high-confidence isoforms across",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "37,661",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "12,302 genes. Our assembly revealed 14,985 novel isoforms of known genes and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12,302",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "14,985",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "2,759 transcripts representing previously unannotated genes, with extensive",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2,759",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "diversity in genes involved in obesity, placental lactogen production, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "growth control. We demonstrate this approach has two immediate practical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "advantages: First, the improved reference reduced inferential uncertainty in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "First",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "isoform quantification by approximately 37%, reduced the frequency of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "approximately 37%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "low-confidence annotations and increased the yield (read depth) of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "high-confidence annotations. Second, in analyses of gestational diabetes",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "mellitus (GDM) with short-read RNA-seq datasets from two independent,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GDM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "multi-ancestry birth cohorts (N = 344) as an exemplar, we were able to identify",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "344",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "novel isoforms of chorionic somatomammotropin hormone 1 ( CSH1 ) mediating the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CSH1",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "effect of maternal hyperglycemia on birth weight that was not apparent in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "conventional gene-level analyses. These findings demonstrate that isoform-level",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "annotation of placental transcriptomics provides greater sensitivity and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "specificity than gene-level approaches. This enhanced precision may be essential",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "for understanding placental function in developmental programming of metabolism",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and reveal ancestry- and context-specific variation in placental function and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Exploring the Chemical Profile, Antioxidants, and Anti-Diabetic Properties of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Chemical Profile",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Anti-Diabetic Properties",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Coffee Beans From Selected East African Countries: A Comparative In Vitro and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Selected East African Countries",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vitro",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Computational Study.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Biochemistry, School of Life Sciences University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Biochemistry, School of Life Sciences University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "KwaZulu-Natal Durban South Africa.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "KwaZulu-Natal Durban South Africa",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Microbiology, School of Life Sciences University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Microbiology, School of Life Sciences University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "East Africa, the origin of coffee beans, is renowned for its coffee's cultural",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "East Africa",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significance and potential health benefits, particularly in mitigating metabolic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "disorders and their related complications. Despite this, studies that",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "comprehensively evaluate their pharmacological potential remain limited. This",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "study investigated the antioxidant and antidiabetic properties of coffee beans",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "from Uganda, Burundi, and Tanzania using in vitro and computational methods.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Uganda",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Burundi",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tanzania",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Antioxidant activities were evaluated via DPPH, FRAP, and nitric oxide",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "FRAP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(NO) assays, while antidiabetic potential was assessed using α-glucosidase and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "was employed to screen and identify the phytochemical compounds in the coffee",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "beans. Additionally, computational studies such as molecular docking and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "molecular dynamics (MD) simulation were performed to investigate the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MD",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "interactions and stability between the phytochemicals and target enzymes. The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "results revealed that coffee beans from Burundi exhibited the highest DPPH and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burundi",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "FRAP scavenging activities, while Ugandan cofee beans demonstrated the strongest",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ugandan",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "NO scavenging activity. Tanzanian beans showed the most potent inhibition of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Tanzanian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "α-glucosidase and α-amylase enzymes. Additionally, Burundian coffee extracts",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burundian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "stimulated glucose uptake in yeast cells more effectively than other samples.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "The LC-MS analysis highlighted that Burundian and Tanzanian beans were rich in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Burundian",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tanzanian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "phenolic acids, whereas Ugandan beans had the highest caffeine content.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ugandan",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Molecular docking and dynamics simulations confirmed strong inhibitory",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interactions between the identified phytochemicals and target enzymes,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "supporting their role in antioxidant and antidiabetic activities. The study",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "underscores East African coffee beans' potent antioxidant and antidiabetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "East African",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "properties, attributed to their unique phytochemical profiles. These findings",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "emphasize their potential as functional foods for managing metabolic disorders,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "providing a scientific basis for their health benefits.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "© 2025 The Author(s). Food Science & Nutrition published by Wiley Periodicals",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Food Science & Nutrition",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Wiley Periodicals",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "15. Food Sci Nutr. 2025 Jul 15;13(7):e70404. doi: 10.1002/fsn3.70404. eCollection",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "15",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sci Nutr",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.1002",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of the Impact of Cornus mas L. on",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Meta-Analysis",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Anthropometric Indices and Body Composition.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Medicinal Plants Research Center, Department of Nutrition Maragheh University",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Plants Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Nutrition Maragheh University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of Medical Sciences (MRGUMS) Maragheh Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maragheh Iran",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Student Research Committee, Faculty of Nutrition and Food Sciences Tabriz",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Nutrition and Food Sciences Tabriz",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University of Medical Sciences Tabriz Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "University of Medical Sciences Tabriz Iran",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Student Research Committee, Department of Nutrition Maragheh University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Research Committee",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Department of Nutrition Maragheh University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Medical Sciences (MRGUMS) Maragheh Iran.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Maragheh Iran",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Obesity and its related metabolic disorders have been a global concern in health",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "care over the past few decades. Lifestyle modification and evidence-based",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the past few decades",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "dietary interventions, including the usage of nutraceuticals with minimal",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "adverse effects, have gained widespread recognition as effective strategies for",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "obesity management. Cornelian cherry, scientifically identified as Cornus mas L.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cornelian",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "Cornus",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(CM) is rich in anthocyanins, flavonoids, tannins, and polyphenols, with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "anti-inflammatory, anti-oxidant, anti-diabetic, anti-obesity, and hypolipidemic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "properties. Cornelian cherry inhibits hepatic lipogenesis, increases hepatic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cornelian",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lipid oxidation and clearance, and regulates the expression of peroxisome",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "proliferator-activated receptors. Additionally, CM activates the AMP-activated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "AMP",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "protein kinase and adiponectin signaling pathways in the white adipose tissue,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "resulting in adipocytokine level decline. We aimed to perform a systematic",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "review and meta-analysis of the impact of CM on anthropometric indices and body",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "composition. A comprehensive search was conducted on the Web of Sciences,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Web of Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PubMed, and Scopus databases up to April 2025 for published papers. The quality",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PubMed",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "April 2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "of methodology and risk of bias of selected studies were assessed by the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Cochrane Risk of Bias tool. Overall, six randomized controlled trials (RCT) were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bias",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "six",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "included. Pooled analyses indicated no significant differences observed in cases",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "of body weight (BW), body fat percentage (BF%), fat mass (FM), weight",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "circumference (WC) and hip circumference (HC). However, a modest but significant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "increase in body mass index (BMI) was observed after supplementing CM.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Furthermore, according to sub-group analyses, BW, BMI, BF%, FM, WC, and HC were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "BW",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BMI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "BF%",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "WC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly increased when administration was accomplished on MAPLD patients,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "MAPLD",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the sample size was > 50, the lyophilized dried and CM fruit extract forms were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "50",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "used, intervention duration was < 12 weeks, and doses were ≥ 30 g. Future",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12 weeks",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "≥",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "30 g. Future",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "research should prioritize well-designed, long-term follow-up RCTs investigating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CM as an adjunct therapy to multimodal lifestyle interventions, focusing on both",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "CM",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "anthropometric indices and biochemical markers.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Skin microbiota and diabetic foot ulcers.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Burn Department, Ningbo No.2 Hospital, Ningbo, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ningbo No.2 Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ningbo",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Institute of Pathology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Bonn, Bonn,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2)Institute",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Faculty of Medicine, University of Bonn",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bonn",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Germany",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Health Science Center, Ningbo University, Ningbo, China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Science Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ningbo University",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ningbo",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Skin microbiota is the microbial population on the skin surface, which has a",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "symbiotic relationship with the host skin and plays an important role in",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "maintaining skin health and regulating immune responses. In patients with",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs), the skin microbiota is unbalanced. The abundance of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "increases, forming biofilms, destroying the skin barrier function, aggravating",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "infection, and leading to poor wound healing. Studies have shown that the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "diversity of skin microbiota is positively correlated with the severity of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "ulcers, and regulating its composition and function may be an important strategy",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "to improve DFUs healing. In recent years, with the development of molecular",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "recent years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "biology technology, progress has been made in the study of skin microbiota, such",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "as 16S rRNA gene sequencing technology to understand its composition changes and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "16S",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "explore the interaction mechanism with the host immune system. Based on this,",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "some new therapeutic approaches are being explored, such as the use of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "probiotics or antibacterial drugs to modulate the composition of the microbiota",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "and the development of microbiota-based personalized treatment regimens.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "However, there are still challenges in current research. For example, the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "composition and function of skin microbiota are affected by many factors, and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "there are relatively few studies on other microorganisms such as fungi and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "viruses. In the future, it is necessary to further explore its diversity and the",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "interaction mechanism with the host, and develop more effective treatment",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "methods to improve the prognosis of patients with DFUs.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "eCollection 2025 May-Aug.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "May-Aug.",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Effect of Ginkgo biloba extracts in the prevention of posterior capsule",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "opacification after cataract surgery: A randomized clinical trial.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Sports Medicine Research Center, Neuroscience Institute, Tehran University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Medicine Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Neuroscience Institute",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tehran University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Ophthalmology, Bu Ali Sina Hospital, Mazandaran University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Bu Ali Sina Hospital",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mazandaran University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(3)Department of Pharmaceutics, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mazandaran University of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Pharmaceutics, Faculty of Pharmacy",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Mazandaran University",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(4)Behavioral Diseases Counseling Center, Mazandaran University of Medical",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "(5)Department of Biostatistics, Health Sciences Research Center, Addiction",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "5)Department",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Biostatistics, Health Sciences Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Institute, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences, ON, Canada.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Institute, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "ON",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Canada",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(6)Diabetes Research Center, Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6)Diabetes Research Center",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "University of Medical Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "PURPOSE: This study aims to explore the effect of Ginkgo biloba extracts (GbE)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PURPOSE",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ginkgo",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "on the prevention of posterior capsule opacification (PCO).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "STUDY DESIGN: This study was a double-blinded, placebo-controlled, single-center",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Patients with senile cataracts randomly received GbE supplement",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "capsules at a dose of 200 mg (n = 74) or an identical placebo (n = 70) daily for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "200",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "74",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "70",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "daily",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "6 months after cataract surgery. Patients' follow-ups were scheduled for up to 3",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "6 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "up to 3",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "years after cataract surgery. PCO formation (Pearl/Fibrotic) was graded using",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "years",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Pearl/Fibrotic",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "slit-lamp examinations. The necessity of a Neodymium-doped yttrium aluminum",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "garnet (Nd: YAG) laser capsulotomy was evaluated by patients' complaints of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "garnet",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "reduced visual acuity imputable to PCO.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCO",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: A total of 144 patients with a mean age of 64.92 ± 7.77 years were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "144",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "64.92",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "7.77 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "studied. The mean Log MAR visual acuity in the placebo group started to decrease",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Log MAR",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "at 12 months (P = 0.003) and remained significantly lower than the GbE group",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "12 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.003",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "throughout 36 months (P = 0.005). At 1-year postsurgery, a significant",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "36 months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.005",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "1-year",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "difference between the two groups of GbE and Placebo was observed regarding",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "two",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Placebo",
        "label": "LOC"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "pearl PCO score, but obvious fibrotic PCO score differences occurred 3 years",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "3 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "after surgery. The Nd: YAG capsulotomy was performed in six eyes (6.1%) for the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "six",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "6.1%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "GbE group and 18 eyes (20.4%) for the placebo group (P = 0.004) 3 years after",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "18",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "20.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.004",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "3 years",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the cataract surgery.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: Six months of supplementation with GbE was well tolerated and may",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Six months",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "provide some marginal prevention in the PCO formation. Besides the effect of the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "PCO",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "GbE in the inhibition of PCO, we also observed a noticeable reduction in the",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GbE",
        "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
      },
      {
        "text": "PCO",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "need for Nd: YAG laser capsulotomy.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Copyright: © 2025 Oman Ophthalmic Society.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "2025",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "Oman Ophthalmic Society",
        "label": "EVENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Conflict of interest statement: There are no conflicts of interest.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "A comparative study of retinal vein occlusion and serum 25 hydroxy Vitamin D at",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "Vitamin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Ophthalmology, Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ophthalmology, Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(2)Department of Biochemistry, Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Biochemistry, Calcutta National Medical College and Hospital",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Prevalence of retinal vascular occlusion is second to diabetic",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "second",
        "label": "ORDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "retinopathy and age-related macular degeneration. Various age-related local and",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "systemic factors have been associated with retinal vein occlusion (RVO).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Hemodynamic changes (venous stasis), degenerative changes of the vessel wall and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hemodynamic",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "blood hypercoagulability underlies the pathogenesis. The role of Vitamin D in",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vitamin D",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "modulating the inflammatory responses within the arterial wall, the capacity to",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "attenuate the oxidative stress and direct effect of hypovitaminosis D on",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "increased vascular resistance hints at a potential association of Vitamin D",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vitamin D",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "levels with disorders of retinal vasculature.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "AIM: To estimate serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25 OH Vit D) level in patients of",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AIM",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "RVO and compare it with matched controls.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "MATERIALS AND METHODS: Fifty patients of RVO as cases and 50 without RVO as",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fifty",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "50",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "controls underwent systemic and ocular examination including the estimation of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "serum 25 OH Vit D and other biochemical parameters.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the Social Sciences",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "SPSS",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "software version 25 was used for the analysis. An alpha level of 5% was taken,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "5%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "that is P < 0.05 was considered statistically significant.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: Mean serum 25 OH Vit D level in cases of RVO was 21.82",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "21.82",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "nanogram/deciliters (ng/dL) compared to 30.71 ng/dL in the control group which",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "30.71 ng/dL",
        "label": "QUANTITY"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "was significantly lower in cases compared to control (P < 0.001). The odds ratio",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "calculated for RVO cases versus controls was 1.137; 95% confidence interval",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "1.137",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: A positive association of low serum 25 OH Vit D levels and RVO was",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "found highlighting the importance of evaluating serum Vitamin D levels in all",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vitamin",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "the cases of RVO. This correlation may have possible implications for",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "prophylaxis and treatment of RVO, even though this part of our country gets",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "RVO",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "abundant sunlight throughout the year.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "the year",
        "label": "DATE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "19. Int J Gen Med. 2025 Jul 11;18:3837-3849. doi: 10.2147/IJGM.S526363.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "19",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "10.2147",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "25-(OH)D Deficiency and the Risk of Minor Amputation in Patients with Diabetes",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Foot Ulcers: A Chinese Cohort Study.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(1)Department of Orthopedics, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Soochow",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Orthopedics",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "The Second Affiliated Hospital of Soochow",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "University, Soochow, 215004, People's Republic of China.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "215004",
        "label": "DATE"
      },
      {
        "text": "People's Republic of China",
        "label": "GPE"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "BACKGROUND: Diabetic foot amputation represents the severe complication of",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "patients with diabetic foot ulcers (DFU), with worsened clinical outcomes",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "concomitant with 25-hydroxyvitamin D [25-(OH)D] deficiency. This study aimed to",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "investigate the value of 25-(OH)D deficiency and its association with minor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "lower limb amputation in Chinese patients with DFU in type 2 diabetes mellitus",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Chinese",
        "label": "NORP"
      },
      {
        "text": "2",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(T2DM).",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "METHODS: Ninety-one T2DM patients with DFU undergoing minor amputation (surgical",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ninety-one",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "group), 94 T2DM patients without DFU (diabetic control group), and 40 healthy",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "94",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "40",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "controls were enrolled in the study finally. Serum 25-(OH)D levels were measured",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "spectrometry. Patients in the surgical group underwent pathogen detection.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "RESULTS: The overall incidence of 25-(OH)D deficiency was 73.0%. Amputation",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "73.0%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "group exhibited significantly higher prevalence versus control group (85.7% vs",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "85.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "60.6%, P<0.001). The levels of serum 25-(OH)D in the minor amputation group were",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "60.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "significantly lower than the T2DM group [10.71 (8.2,16.7) vs 18.8 (15.0, 23.9)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "10.71",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "18.8",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "15.0",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "23.9",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "ng/mL, P<0.001]. Compared with the control group, amputation group showed lower",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ng/mL",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "25-(OH)D, calcium, albumin and higher WBC, platelet, inflammatory markers (all",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "WBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "P<0.001). Minor amputation subgroups showed that 25-(OH)D deficiency associated",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "with elevated WBC (P=0.002), PLT (P=0.011), D-dimer (P=0.041), HbA1c (P=0.033),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "WBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "PLT",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "SII (P=0.023). While low expression of 25-(OH)D group had higher WBC (P=0.016),",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SII",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "P=0.023",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "WBC",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "D-dimer (P=0.004), SIRI (P=0.042), lower albumin (P=0.009) vs high expression",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "SIRI",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "group. ROC analysis confirmed 25-(OH)D as superior amputation predictor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "ROC",
        "label": "GPE"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "(AUC=0.798, 95% CI 0.734-0.861) compared to inflammatory markers. Multivariate",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "AUC=0.798",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "95%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "CI",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "0.734-0.861",
        "label": "PRODUCT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "regression identified deficiency as independent amputation risk factor.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "Polymicrobial infections (26.4%) correlated with lower 25-(OH)D (P=0.003), with",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "26.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Gram-negative (52.4%) and Gram-positive bacteria (47.6%) among bacterial",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Gram-negative",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "52.4%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      },
      {
        "text": "Gram",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "47.6%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "infections.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "text": "CONCLUSION: 25-(OH)D deficiency occurs in 85.7% of patients with minor",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "85.7%",
        "label": "PERCENT"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "amputation in DFU, and the levels of 25-(OH)D decreased. 25-(OH)D deficiency is",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
        "label": "CARDINAL"
      },
      {
        "text": "25-(OH)D",
